<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halopiger_xanaduensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>SH-6T (=CECT 7173T=CGMCC 1.6379T=JCM 14033T)</strain>
  <reference>Halopiger xanaduensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from saline Lake Shangmatala in Inner Mongolia, China IJSEM 57:1402-1407</reference>
  <file>Halopiger.xanaduensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.  Cells are 0.5–1.0 mm wide and 3.0–13.0 µm long.  Colonies are circular, 1–2 mm in diameter after incubation for 10 days at 37 ˚C.  Extremely halophilic.  Cells lyse in water.  Magnesium is not required.  Growth does not occur above 45 ˚C.  Amino acids are not required for growth.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Anaerobic growth with arginine does not occur.  Production of indole and methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons’ citrate tests are negative.  H2S is not produced from cysteine.  Acid is produced from D-arabinose, D-glucose and D-xylose, but not from D-fructose, D-galactose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, sucrose or D-trehalose.  Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.  Urea, Tween 80, gelatin and aesculin are hydrolysed, whereas starch, casein, DNA and phosphatase are not.  Nitrate and nitrite are reduced with gas production.  The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: D-galactose, D-glucose, D-xylose, L-asparagine, L-serine, acetate and L-glutamate.  No growth on D-arabinose, D-fructose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-raffinose, D-ribose, starch, D-trehalose, glycerol, D-sorbitol, D-mannitol, glycine, isoleucine, L-lysine, L-threonine, fumarate, malate, propionate or succinate.  Susceptible to bacitracin (10 U), novobiocin (30 µg) and sulfamethoxazole (25 µg).  Resistant to ampicillin (10 µg), cephalothin (30 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), neomycin (10 µg), penicillin G (10 U), rifampicin (30 µg), polymyxin (300 U), streptomycin (10 µg), tetracycline (30 µg) and vancomycin (30 µg).  The G+C content of the DNA is 63.1 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, SH-6T (=CECT 7173T=CGMCC 1.6379T=JCM 14033T), was isolated from Shangmatala salt lake, Inner Mongolia, China.  Contained phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglyceromethylphosphate derived from both C20C20 and C20C25 glycerol diethers as shown from the two spots.  The glycolipid S2-DGD-1 was also detected.</description>
</treatment>
