<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Gail Gasparich">
  <taxon_name>Acholeplasma_laidlawii</taxon_name>
  <file>Aclaidlawii Sabin 1941</file>
  <description>laid.law'i.i N.L. gen. masc. n. laidlawii of Laidlaw, Named after Patrick P. Laidlaw, one of the microbiologists who first isolated this species.  This is the type species of the genus Acholeplasma.  Filaments, unsually relatively short, although much longer branched filaments may develop in media with certain ratios of saturated to unsaturated fatty acids.  Coccoid forms may predominate in certain cultures including co-culture with eukaryotic cells.   Agar colonies are large for a mollicute and exhibit well-develped central zones and peripheral growth on horse serum agar.  On serum-free agar, colonies are smaller and may show only the central zone of growth in the agar.  Relatively strong turbidity is produced during growth in broth containing serum.  Temperature range for growth is 20-41°C with optimum at 37°C, even for strains recovered from plant or non-animal sources.  Usually produces large amounts of carotenoids when cultivated in the presence of PPLO serum fraction (Difco).   Serologically distinct from most established species in the genus, but partial cross-reactions may occur with Acholeplasma granularum strains.  DNA-DNA hybridization between strains of this species range from 40 to 80%. Acholeplasma granularum strain BTS-39 showed 20% hybridization with Acholeplasma laidlawii PG8.  Pathogenicity has not been established. Source:  Isolated from sewage, manure, humus, soil and many animal hosts and their tissues including some isolates from human oral cavity, vagina and wounds.  Has been recovered from the surfaces of some plants, although few isolations have been reported from insect hosts.  Frequent contaminant of eukaryotic cell cultures.  DNA G + C content (mol%): 31.7-35.7 (Bd, Tm).  Type strain:  ATCC 23206, Pg8, NCTC 10116, CIP 75.27, NBRC 14400.  Sequence accession no. (16S rRNA gene): U14905.</description>
</treatment>
