<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Acidianus_infernus</taxon_name>
  <strain>So4aT (= DSM 3191)</strain>
  <reference>Acidianus infernus gen. nov., sp. nov., and Acidianus brierleyi comb. nov.: Facultatively Aerobic, Extremely Acidophilic Thermophilic Sulfur-Metabolizing Archaebacteria IJSB 36:559-564</reference>
  <file>Acidianus.brierleyi.infernus.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram negative.  Non-motile.  Exponentially growing cells are about 0.5 to 1.5 µm wide in an aerobic cultures and 0.8 to 2 µm wide in aerobic cultures, becoming smaller in the stationary growth phase.  Packed cells from aerobic cultures are ochre colored, and packed cells from extremely anaerobic cultures are greenish black.  Growth is obligately chemolithotrophic at temperatures ranging from 65 to 96˚C, with optimum growth at around 90˚C, as shown for strain So4aT.  No growth is detected at 60 and 98°C.  The pH suitable for growth ranges from 5.5 to 1.0, with the optimum pH around 2 (isolate So4aT).  No growth is obtained at pH 0.5 or 6.0.  Exhibits a broad salt tolerance, with an optimum around 0.2% NaCl (data not shown); this tolerance is independent of the salinity of their place of origin.  Anaerobically grown cultures of isolate so4aT at pH 2 can be used for at least 2 years as inocula, when they are stored at 4°C.  However, we were unable to obtain growth from aerobically grown cultures after storage at pH 2 and 4°C for 2 months.  Viability of aerobic cultures can be increased to about 4 months by raising the pH to 5.5 by adding CaCO3.  Cells lyse at pH values greater than 8.5.  Isolates were obtained from hot water, mud, and marine sediments at geothermal springs in Italy, the Azores, Iceland, and the United States.  The type strain is strain So4a (= DSM 3191). The new isolates described here are extreme thermoacidophiles which were obtained from distant acidic geo- and hydrothermally heated areas; therefore, these organisms may be distributed worldwide in similar biotopes.  Although these organisms grow in laboratories only at temperatures ranging from 65 to 96°C at pH 1 to 5.5, they were also isolated from places with much lower temperatures (e.g., 40°C) and higher pH values (e.g., pH 6.5).  These bacteria may thrive at such places only within distinct temperatures and pH gradients formed by small hot fumaroles which heat the surface water or sediments.  Because of their broad salt tolerance, the new isolates are found within solfatara fields with low ionic strength, as well as in hydrothermal seawater in high-ionic-strength environments.  Because of their unique ability to employ two contrary modes of chemolithotrophy, in which S˚ is oxidized or reduced depending on the oxygen supply, these organisms are capable of growing in the oxygen-rich surfaces of solfataric biotopes and at reduced depths that are well supplied with H2 and CO2 by escaping volcanic gasses.   The new organisms, represented by strain so4aT, belong to the archaebacteria on the basis of their lack of murein, their resistance to the antibiotics vancomycin, ampicillin, and kanamycin, the occurrence of isopranyl ether lipids in their cells, and the presence of elongation factor 2 which is sensitive to diphtheria toxin.  Isolate so4aT, which is described above, resembles the type species of Thermoproteus, T. tenax, in its anaerobic H2-S˚ lithotrophy, but strongly differs in its shape, its ability to grow aerobically, its extremely acidophilic mode of life, and its much lower G+C content.  On the other hand, it shows a distinct similarity to the type species of Sulfolobus, S. acidocaldarius, in its morphology, its extreme thermoacidophily, its lithotrophy based on So oxidation, the presence of calditol and caldariellaquinone, the same strongly acidic biotope, and the low, although different, G+C content of its DNA.  However, isolate so4aT diverges from the Sulfolobus type species and from S. solfataricus by its lower G+C content and its ability to grow anaerobically by means of S˚ reduction.  A. brierleyi has the same G+C content as isolate so4aT and is also able to grow anaerobically by means of So reduction; the latter feature was not recognized in its earlier description.  It differs from so4aT by its ability to grow organotrophically without S˚ in the presence of O2, by its much lower growth temperature, and by the lack of significant DNA homology, indicating that it is a separate species.  Marine isolates Vcll and Vc16 exhibit a high degree of DNA homology with so4aT and each other, indicating that they belong to the same species.  There is also no significant DNA homology between A. brierleyi DSM 1651T and S. acidocaldarius DSM 639T and S. solfataricus DSM 1616T.  As determined by 16s ribosomal ribonucleic acid cataloging, S. acidocaldarius DSM 639T and S. solfataricus DSM 1616T show a similarity coefficient of only 0.41, indicating a large phylogenetic difference between these two species of the same genus.  However, no further distinguishing taxonomic markers are present now to justify their placement in different genera.  Aerobic hydrogen oxidation.</description>
</treatment>
