<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Acidiplasma_aeolicum</taxon_name>
  <strain>VT (=DSM 18409T = JCM 14615T)</strain>
  <reference>Acidiplasma aeolicum gen. nov., sp. nov., a euryarchaeon of the family Ferroplasmaceae isolated from a hydrothermal pool, and transfer of Ferroplasma cupricumulans to Acidiplasma cupricumulans comb. nov. IJSEM 59:2815-2823</reference>
  <file>Acidiplasma.aeolicum.cupricumulans.pdf</file>
  <description>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.  Exhibits filamentous protrusions extending from the cell surface.  Temperature and pH ranges for growth are 15–65 ˚C (optimum 42–45 ˚C) and pH 0–4 (optimum pH 1.4–1.6).  Oxidizes reduced sulfur species.  Able to grow organoheterotrophically with yeast extract and glucose.  The G+C content of DNA of the type strain is 36 mol%.  Principal membrane lipids are dibiphytanyl- based tetraether lipids.  The polar lipids are dominated by a single phosphoglycolipid derivative based on a galactosyl dibiphytanyl phosphoglycerol tetraether, together with smaller amounts of mono- and diglycosyl dibiphytanyl ether lipids and the corresponding phosphoglycerol derivatives.  The major respiratory quinones present are naphthoquinone derivatives.  The type strain is strain VT (=DSM 18409T = JCM 14615T), which was isolated from a hydrothermal pool on Vulcano Island, Italy.  No growth on elemental sulfur, tetrathionate, and thiosulfate.  Not capable of growth on L-arabinose, fructose, sucrose, L-sorbitol, glucose-1-phosphate, glucose-6-phosphate, maltose, D-xylose, D-mannitol, lactose, cellobiose, D-galactose, mannose, L-fucose, gentiobiose, myoinositol, D-lactulose, melibiose, methyl b-D-glucoside, D-psicose, rhamnose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, trehalose, turanose, xylitol, cyclodextrin, dextrin, inosine, uridine, thymidine and glycogen; organic acids and their salts: aminobutyric acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, cis-acetic acid, citric acid, formic acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, D-glucuronic acid, a-hydroxybutyric acid, b-hydroxybutyric acid, c-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, a-ketobutyric acid, a-ketoglutaric acid, a-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, urocanic acid and L-pyroglutamic acid; amino acids: glucuronamide, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanyl glycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl L-aspartic acid, glycyl L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, hydroxy- L-proline, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, D-serine, D-serine, L-threonine, DL-carnitine, putrescine and phenylethylamine; alcohols: 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, L-a-glycerol phosphate, adonitol, D-arabitol and i-erythritol; and others: Tweens 40 and 80, N-acetyl D-galactosamine and N-acetyl D-glucosamine.  Sensitive to rifampicin, chloramphenicol, and tetracycline.  Resistant to streptomycin, kanamycin, vancomycin, gentamicin, and ampicillin.</description>
</treatment>
