<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Aeropyrum_pernix</taxon_name>
  <strain>K1 = JCM 9820</strain>
  <reference>Aeropyrum pernix gen. nov., sp. nov., a Novel Hyperthermophilic Archaeon Growing Temperatures up to 100°C IJSB 46:1070-1077</reference>
  <file>Aeropyrum.pernix.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are gram negative and irregular coccoid.  Cells are usually about 0.8 to 1.0 µm in diameter.  Vigorous motility is evident by light microscopy either at room temperature or at 90°C.  Cells frequently have pili-like appendages.  The envelope surrounding the cells is about 25 nm wide.  Packed cells are brown.  Strictly aerobic, heterotrophic, hyperthermoneutrophiles.  Growth occurs between 70 and 100°C (optimum, 90 to 95˚C), at pH 5 to 9 (optimum, pH 7.0), and at 1.8 to 7.0% salinity (optimum, 3.5% salinity).  No growth is detected at 68 or 102°C.  Cells lyse by low osmotic shock (below 1.5% salinity).  Thiosulfate stimulates growth, but was not required for growth.  Oxygen serves as a possible electron acceptor.  Grows on proteinaceous complex substrates such as yeast extracts, trypticase peptone, tryptone, or nutrient broth but not on Casamino Acids.  Any single carbohydrate (ribose, arabinose, xylose, glucose, galactose, fructose, fucose, rhamnose, mannose, maltose, lactose, sucrose, cellobiose, melibiose, raffinose, cellulose, starch, sorbitol, mannitol, glycerol), organic acid (acetate), or amino acids tested did not suffice as a sole carbon and energy source.  During growth, H2S is not produced in either the presence or absence of thiosulfate.  The growth yield was not stimulated by sulfate, sulfite, S˚, sulfide, cysteine, or methionine.  The core lipids consist solely of disesterterpanyl (C25, C25) glycerol ether lipids.  The polar lipids consist of five components, but only phosphoglycolipid (AGI; 91 %) (containing inositol and glucose) and phospholipid (AI; 9%) are predominant.  Genomic DNA has a G+C content of 67 mol%.  Isolate was obtained from hot sedimentary materials and venting waters at a coastal solfataric vent in Kodakara-Jima Island, Japan.  The type strain is Aeropyrum pernix K1, JCM 9820, Japan Collection of Microorganisms, The Institute of Physical and Chemical Research (RIKEN), Wako-shi, Saitama, Japan.  Insensitive to ampicillin, vancomycin, and cycloserine.  Sensitive to chloramphenicol.</description>
</treatment>
