<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Gail Gasparich">
  <taxon_name>Anaeroplasma_abactoclasticum</taxon_name>
  <file>Anabactoclasticum Robinson et al 1975</file>
  <description>Obligately anaerobic, filterable microorganisms have been isolated from the rumen of cattle and sheep. On the basis of typical colonial appearance, lack of cell wall, filterability through a 450-nm membrane filter, absence of reversion to a bacterial form, and inhibition of growth by homologous antiserum, these organisms fit the Text for organisms in the order Mycoplasmatales. They exhibit unique cultural, biochemical, and serological properties, and we have thus placed them in a new genus, Anaeroplasma. A. abactoclasticum is the type species of the new genus. Strain 6-1, a sterol-requiring strain, has been designated as the type strain of A. abactoclasticum and has been deposited in the American Type Culture Collection as ATCC 27879; a non-sterol-requiring strain, number 161, has been deposited as ATCC 27880. The relationship of Anaeroplasma abactoclasticum to Acholesplasma bactoclasticum, an anaerobic mycoplasma possessing extracellular proteolytic and bactoclastic enzymes, is discussed.  Strain ATCC 27112 ferments starch to produce mainly acetic, formic, and lactic acids, C02, Ha, and ethanol. The G+C content of the deoxyribonucleic acid is 33.7 mol%. It does not grow in sterol-free media, but it grows in rumen fluid medium and also in culture medium when rumen fluid is replaced by volatile acids, Trypticase, a vitamin mixture, cholesterol, and the LPS fractionffrom E. coli cells. The growth of this strain is inhibited by thallous acetate (0.02%) and digitonin (200 pg/ml). Properties of Anaeroplasma bactoclasticum. Anaeroplasma bactoclasticum is a strictly anaerobic organism found in the rumen. Cells of young (12- to 18-h-old) cultures are coccoid, about 500 nm in diameter, gram negative, and nonmotile. A variety of pleomorphic forms are exhibited by older cells. Phase microscopy reveals single cells and dumbbell forms. Clusters of 2 to 10 coccoid forms joined by short filaments are common. The cells are filterable through a 450-nm pore size filter.  Electron micrographs of thin sections of cells show cells bounded by a unit membrane with no distinguishable cell wall. This organism does not revert to bacteria with cell walls in the absence of penicillin. Surface colonies average about 1 mm in diameter, have a dense center and translucent peripheries, and present the so called “fried-egg” appearance commonly associated with mycoplasma colonies. Subsurface colonies are golden, irregular, and often multilobed. This organism is insensitive to penicillin but is sensitive to thallous acetate and digitonin. It produces extracellular proteolytic and bacterioclastic enzymes. Starch is fermented, but there is some variation within the species regarding fermentation of other carbohydrates. Fermentation products include: acetic, formic, lactic, and propionic acids, and trace amounts of other volatile fatty acids; CO and H; and ethanol. Cholesterol and a factor in LPS Boivin are required for growth. The optimum temperature is between 30 and 47C. Arginine is not fermented. Chicken embryos are not killed when inoculated with cells of the organism, and no hemolysis of bovine, ovine, or guinea pig blood can be detected in an anaerobic medium. Serologically unrelated to other known mycoplasmas. The G+C content of the deoxyribonucleic acid of the type strain is 33.7 mol% and that of a similar strain (7LA) is 32.5 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
