<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Caldivirga_maquilingensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>IC-167T = JCM 10307T = MCC-UPLB 1200T= ANMR 017gT</strain>
  <reference>Caldivirga maquilingensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a new genus of rod-shaped crenarchaeote isolated from a hot spring in the Philippines IJSB 49:1157-1163</reference>
  <file>Caldivirga.maquilingensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Grows anaerobically or microaerobically.  Heterotrophic.  Growth is stimulated significantly by archaeal cell extracts or a vitamin mixture.  Growth occurs from 60 to 92 ˚C, and between pH 2.3 and 5.9 when buffered with 10 mM trisodium citrate.  Alternatively, grows up to pH 6.4 by using 10 mM MES as buffer agent.  Strain IC-167T grows optimally around 85 ˚C, pH 3.74.2, with a doubling time of 8 h.  Grows at low salinity (0-0.75 % NaCl).  Utilizes glycogen, gelatin, beef extract, peptone, tryptone and yeast extract as carbon sources.  Requires sulfur, thiosulfate or sulfate as possible electron acceptors.  Produces sulfide during growth.  The G+C content of genomic DNA is 43 mol%.  The 16s rDNA may contain introns.  The type strain is strain IC-167, which was isolated from a hot spring at Mt Maquiling, Laguna, the Philippines.  The two strains IC-166 and IC-167T have been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, The Institute of Physical and Chemical Research, Saitama, Japan, as JCM 10306 and JCM 10307T, respectively.  Also, the isolates have been deposited in the Microbial Culture Collection of the Museum of Natural History, University of the Philippines, Los Bafios, the Philippines, as MCC-UPLB 1199 and MCC-UPLB 1200T, respectively.  In addition, both strains are registered as ANMR 0177 and ANMR 017gT, respectively, as the strains belong to the 'Asian Network on Microbial Researches ' project.  No or negligible growth was obtained on D-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-ribose, sucrose, D-xylose, soluble starch, acetate, butyrate, citrate, formate, fumarate, lactate, L-malate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-cysteine, L-glutamic acid, L-glutamine, glycine, L-histidine, L-isoleucine, L-leucine, L-lysine, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, L-tryptophan, L-tyrosine, L-valine, methanol, ethanol, formamide, monomethylamine, trimethylamine, Casamino acids or malt extract.  No growth was obtained in the medium supplemented with sulfite, cystine, oxidized glutathione, malate or fumarate.  Resistant to chloramphenicol, kanamycin, oleandomycin, streptomycin, ampicillin, erythromycin, and vancomycin.  Sensitive to novobiocin and rifampicin.  Large amounts of tetraether core lipids, trace amounts of diether core lipids.  The core lipid fractions contained at least 5 cyclized glycerol-bisphytanyl-glycerol tetraethers.</description>
</treatment>
