<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Lisa Moore">
  <taxon_name>Cyanothece.sp.PCC7425</taxon_name>
  <strain>PCC 7425</strain>
  <reference>Variations in the Rhythms of Respiration and Nitrogen Fixation in Members of the Unicellular Diazotrophic Cyanobacterial Genus Cyanothece (Bandyopadhyay, A., et al., 2013)</reference>
  <DOI>NA</DOI>
  <file>Bandyopadhyay, A., et al. Cyanothece.sp.PCC7425.pdf</file>
  <description>unicellular nitrogen-fixing cyanobacteria, unicellular diazotrophic cyanobacteria, Cyanothece sp. ATCC 51142, a member of this genus, has been shown to perform efficient aerobic nitrogen fixation and hydrogen production., Systems-level studies in the unicellular genus Cyanothece  have revealed a temporal separation of the two processes, photosynthesis occurring during the day and nitrogen fixation occurring at night., Cellular respiration plays a critical role during the transition from one phase to the next, rapidly freeing the intracellular environment of the photosynthetically generated oxygen and rendering it conducive for the induction of nitrogenase activity. In addition, respiration also sustains the process of nitrogen fixation, not only by maintaining a low oxygen environment required for the functioning of the nitrogenase enzyme but also by mobilizing the stored solar energy to fuel this energy-intensive process., In contrast, some Synechococcus  spp. strains can fix nitrogen only when incubated under anoxic conditions., Members of the unicellular cyanobacterial genus Cyanothece  are diazotrophs that thrive in marine as well as terrestrial environments., Some of the features that define the largely heterogeneous genus Cyanothece  are oval to cylindrical cells, larger than 3 μm in size (they can be as large as 24 μm in diameter), radially arranged thylakoids, and a mucilaginous layer surrounding the cells, all but Cyanothece  sp. PCC 7425 have regions of radially arranged thylakoid membranes, consistent with the definitions of the genus Cyanothece, Cyanothece sp. PCC 7425 cells are the smallest in size (3–4 μm) and are more coccoid in shape compared with the oval shape of the other Cyanothece spp. cells., isolated from rice fields, Cyanothece sp. PCC 7425 cells are not as efficient in fixing atmospheric nitrogen, as is evident from the cultures turning yellow within a few days of growth in nitrogen-deficient medium, anaerobic nitrogen-fixing strain. In Cyanothece sp. PCC 7425 cells incubated under aerobic conditions, no nitrogenase activity or hydrogen production could be detected., In Cyanothece sp. PCC 7425 incubated under anoxic conditions, the rate of ethylene and hydrogen production was about 40 μmol mg-1 chlorophyll h-1 . did not exhibit any significant difference in growth rate when grown in the presence of glycerol, In Cyanothece  sp. PCC 7425, glycerol enhanced the rates of nitrogen fixation (approximately 60 μmol ethylene mg-1 chlorophyll h-1) and hydrogen production (approximately 80 μmol mg-1 chlorophyll h-1) by about 1.5- to 2-fold. Unicellular diazotrophic cyanobacteria maintain a dynamic metabolic profile throughout the diurnal cycle.</description>
</treatment>
