<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Lisa Moore">
  <taxon_name>Cyanothece.sp.PCC8802</taxon_name>
  <strain>PCC 8802</strain>
  <reference>Variations in the Rhythms of Respiration and Nitrogen Fixation in Members of the Unicellular Diazotrophic Cyanobacterial Genus Cyanothece (Bandyopadhyay, A., et al., 2013)</reference>
  <DOI>NA</DOI>
  <file>Bandyopadhyay, A., Cyanothece.sp.PCC8802.pdf</file>
  <description>unicellular nitrogen-fixing cyanobacteria, unicellular diazotrophic cyanobacteria, Cyanothece sp. ATCC 51142, a member of this genus, has been shown to perform efficient aerobic nitrogen fixation and hydrogen production., Systems-level studies in the unicellular genus Cyanothece  have revealed a temporal separation of the two processes, photosynthesis occurring during the day and nitrogen fixation occurring at night., Cellular respiration plays a critical role during the transition from one phase to the next, rapidly freeing the intracellular environment of the photosynthetically generated oxygen and rendering it conducive for the induction of nitrogenase activity. In addition, respiration also sustains the process of nitrogen fixation, not only by maintaining a low oxygen environment required for the functioning of the nitrogenase enzyme but also by mobilizing the stored solar energy to fuel this energy-intensive process., In contrast, some Synechococcus  spp. strains can fix nitrogen only when incubated under anoxic conditions., Members of the unicellular cyanobacterial genus Cyanothece  are diazotrophs that thrive in marine as well as terrestrial environments., Some of the features that define the largely heterogeneous genus Cyanothece  are oval to cylindrical cells, larger than 3 μm in size (they can be as large as 24 μm in diameter), radially arranged thylakoids, and a mucilaginous layer surrounding the cells, growing rapidly under nitrogen-fixing conditions, Cyanothece sp. PCC 8802 fixed nitrogen at approximately 100 μmol ethylene mg-1 chlorophyll h-1 and produced hydrogen at approximately 50 μmol mg-1 chlorophyll h-1. did not exhibit any significant difference in growth rate when grown in the presence of glycerol, In contrast, glycerol had an adverse effect on nitrogen fixation in Cyanothece  sp. PCC 8801 and PCC 8802, although hydrogen production remained unchanged., Unicellular diazotrophic cyanobacteria maintain a dynamic metabolic profile throughout the diurnal cycle.</description>
</treatment>
