<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Lisa Moore">
  <taxon_name>Cyanothece_sp._ATCC_51142</taxon_name>
  <strain>ATCC 51142</strain>
  <reference>Variations in the Rhythms of Respiration and Nitrogen Fixation in Members of the Unicellular Diazotrophic Cyanobacterial Genus Cyanothece (Bandyopadhyay, A., et al., 2013)</reference>
  <DOI>NA</DOI>
  <file>Bandyopadhyay, A., et al. Cyanothece sp. ATCC 51142.pdf</file>
  <description>unicellular nitrogen-fixing cyanobacteria, unicellular diazotrophic cyanobacteria, Cyanothece sp. ATCC 51142, a member of this genus, has been shown to perform efficient aerobic nitrogen fixation and hydrogen production., Systems-level studies in the unicellular genus Cyanothece  have revealed a temporal separation of the two processes, photosynthesis occurring during the day and nitrogen fixation occurring at night., Cellular respiration plays a critical role during the transition from one phase to the next, rapidly freeing the intracellular environment of the photosynthetically generated oxygen and rendering it conducive for the induction of nitrogenase activity. In addition, respiration also sustains the process of nitrogen fixation, not only by maintaining a low oxygen environment required for the functioning of the nitrogenase enzyme but also by mobilizing the stored solar energy to fuel this energy-intensive process., In contrast, some Synechococcus  spp. strains can fix nitrogen only when incubated under anoxic conditions., Members of the unicellular cyanobacterial genus Cyanothece  are diazotrophs that thrive in marine as well as terrestrial environments., Some of the features that define the largely heterogeneous genus Cyanothece  are oval to cylindrical cells, larger than 3 μm in size (they can be as large as 24 μm in diameter), radially arranged thylakoids, and a mucilaginous layer surrounding the cells, It was recently demonstrated that Cyanothece  sp. ATCC 51142, a member of the genus Cyanothece , has the unique ability to produce molecular hydrogen at exceptionally high rates under aerobic conditions. This striking observation was attributed to the nitrogenase enzyme system of Cyanothece  sp. ATCC 51142., is a marine strain, efficient in fixing atmospheric nitrogen, Cyanothece sp. ATCC 51142 exhibited the highest rates of nitrogenase activity and hydrogen production., Under anaerobic incubation, the rate of nitrogenase activity in Cyanothece sp. ATCC 51142 cells was more than 230 μmol mg-1  chlorophyll h-1 , and compared with this, the rate of hydrogen production was significantly higher (approximately 350 μmol mg-1  chlorophyll h-1 ). Photomixotrophic growth in the presence of glycerol was shown to significantly enhance the rate of hydrogen production in Cyanothece  sp. ATCC 51142, In Cyanothece  sp. ATCC 51142, the cells supplemented with glycerol fixed nitrogen at more than 200 μmol ethylene mg-1 chlorophyll h-1 and produced hydrogen at more than 250 μmol mg-1 chlorophyll h-1 when incubated under aerobic conditions. Under anaerobic incubation conditions, these rates were approximately 300 and 450 μmol mg-1 chlorophyll h-1, respectively., utilizes glycerol for biomass production as well as nitrogenase-mediated hydrogen production, Unicellular diazotrophic cyanobacteria maintain a dynamic metabolic profile throughout the diurnal cycle. Cyanothece sp. ATCC 51142 was shown to be highly active during the dark phase of a day and night period, with the abundance of transcripts being highest at the early dark period.</description>
</treatment>
