<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Lisa Moore">
  <taxon_name>Cyanothece.sp.PCC7822</taxon_name>
  <strain>PCC 7822</strain>
  <reference>Variations in the Rhythms of Respiration and Nitrogen Fixation in Members of the Unicellular Diazotrophic Cyanobacterial Genus Cyanothece (Bandyopadhyay, A., et al., 2013)</reference>
  <DOI>NA</DOI>
  <file>Bandyopadhyay, A., Cyanothece.sp.PCC7822.pdf</file>
  <description>unicellular nitrogen-fixing cyanobacteria, unicellular diazotrophic cyanobacteria, Cyanothece sp. ATCC 51142, a member of this genus, has been shown to perform efficient aerobic nitrogen fixation and hydrogen production., Systems-level studies in the unicellular genus Cyanothece  have revealed a temporal separation of the two processes, photosynthesis occurring during the day and nitrogen fixation occurring at night., Cellular respiration plays a critical role during the transition from one phase to the next, rapidly freeing the intracellular environment of the photosynthetically generated oxygen and rendering it conducive for the induction of nitrogenase activity. In addition, respiration also sustains the process of nitrogen fixation, not only by maintaining a low oxygen environment required for the functioning of the nitrogenase enzyme but also by mobilizing the stored solar energy to fuel this energy-intensive process., In contrast, some Synechococcus  spp. strains can fix nitrogen only when incubated under anoxic conditions., Members of the unicellular cyanobacterial genus Cyanothece  are diazotrophs that thrive in marine as well as terrestrial environments., Some of the features that define the largely heterogeneous genus Cyanothece  are oval to cylindrical cells, larger than 3 μm in size (they can be as large as 24 μm in diameter), radially arranged thylakoids, and a mucilaginous layer surrounding the cells, Cyanothece sp. PCC x7822 has the largest cells (8–10 μm), possess the pigment phycoerythrin, which imparts a brownish green color to the cells, isolated from rice fields, Cyanothece sp. PCC 7424 and PCC 7822 cells have a propensity to form clumps, and these two strains grow slower compared with the other strains both in the presence and absence of combined sources of nitrogen in the medium (Fig. 3A). The strains exhibit a longer lag phase under nitrogen-fixing conditions, and the length of the lag phase varies among the strains. Cyanothece sp. PCC 7424, PCC 7822, and PCC 8801 also grow in medium lacking sources of fixed nitrogen, but they exhibit much reduced doubling time., The lowest nitrogenase activity (approximately 50 μmol mg21 chlorophyll h-1)was observed in Cyanothece  sp. PCC 7424 and PCC 7822, and the hydrogen production rate in these two strains was also about 50 μmol mg-1 chlorophyll h-1. did not exhibit any significant difference in growth rate when grown in the presence of glycerol, In Cyanothece  sp. PCC 7424 and PCC 7822, glycerol also contributed toward higher nitrogen fi xation and hydrogen production rates, Unicellular diazotrophic cyanobacteria maintain a dynamic metabolic profile throughout the diurnal cycle.</description>
</treatment>
