<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Ferroplasma_acidiphilum</taxon_name>
  <strain>YT = DSM 12658T</strain>
  <reference>Ferroplasma acidiphilum gen. nov., sp. nov., an acidophilic, autotrophic, ferrous-iron-oxidizing, cell-wall-lacking, mesophilic member of the Ferroplasmaceae fam. nov., comprising a distinct lineage of the Archaea IJSEM 50:997-1006</reference>
  <file>Ferroplasma.acidiphilum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are irregular cocci, varying from spherical to filamentous, forming duplex and triplex forms.  Gram negative.  Strict aerobes.  Cell wall and S-layer are absent.  Acidophilic.  Strictly chemolithoautotrophic; no organic compounds have been found that are used as carbon sources.  Oxidizes Fe2+ from FeSO4 and pyrite (Fe2S); oxidizes Mn2+ from MnSO4.  Mesophilic.  Principal lipids are archaetidic acid and archaetidyl glycerol.  The type and only species of the genus is Ferroplasma acidiphilum.  G+C content of DNA is 36.5 mol%.  Growth occurs between temperatures of 20 and 45 °C with an optimum at 35 °C and at pH 1.3-2.2 with an optimum at pH 1.7.  Strain YT is the only and type strain of Ferroplasma acidiphilum.  Ferroplasma acidiphilum strain YT has been deposited in the DSMZ as strain DSM 12658T. Addition on yeast extract was observed to be essential for growth.  A vitamin solution could be substituted for yeast extract.  No growth on: L-arabinose, fructose, sucrose, L-sorbitol, L- and D-glucose, glucose-1-phosphate, glucose-6-phosphate, L-maltose, d-xylose, d-mannitol, lactose, cellobiose, d-galactose, mannose, l-fucose, gentiobiose, m-inositol, lactulose, d-melibiose, b-methyl d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, cyclodextrin, dextrin, inosine, uridine, thymidine and glycogen.  No growth on: aminobutyric acid, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, acetic acid, cis-acetic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, a-hydroxybutyric acid, b-hydroxybutyric acid, c-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, a-ketobutyric acid, a-ketoglutaric acid, a-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, urocanic acid and l-pyroglutamic acid.  No growth on amino acids: glucuriamide, alaninamide, d-alanine, l-alanyl-glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, hydroxy-l-proline, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, putrescine and phenylethylamine.  No growth on: 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol, l-a-glycerol phosphate, adonitol, d-arabitol and i-erythritol.  No growth on: Tween 40 and Tween 80, N-acetyl d-galactosamine and N-acetyl d-glucosamine.  Resistant to ampicillin and chloramphenicol, kanamycin, rifampicin, and streptomycin.  Sensitive to tetracycline and gentamicin.</description>
</treatment>
