<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Geoglobus_ahangari</taxon_name>
  <strain>234T (=ATCC BAA-425T)</strain>
  <reference>Geoglobus ahangari gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel hyperthermophilic archaeon capable of oxidizing organic acids and growing autotrophically on hydrogen with Fe(III) serving as the sole electron acceptor IJSEM 52:719-728</reference>
  <file>Geoglobus.ahangari.pdf</file>
  <description>The type strain was enriched from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent (chimney) sample from Guaymas Basin, Gulf of California (at a depth of 2000 m) with pyruvate as the electron donor and poorly crystalline Fe(III) oxide as the electron acceptor.  Grows by oxidizing H2, acetate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, formate, malate, glycerol, methanol, ethanol, yeast extract, peptone, isoleucine, aspartic acid, glutamic acid, arginine, l-cysteine, serine, glutamine, asparagine, propionate, butyrate, valerate, palmitate or stearate coupled to the reduction of Fe(III).  Only poorly crystalline Fe(III) oxide and Fe(III) citrate are used as electron acceptors.  Other electron acceptors such as S2O32-, SO42-, SO32-, S˚, NO3-, NO2-, O2, Mn(IV), AQDS, malate and fumarate are not utilized as electron acceptors.  Growth occurs at temperatures between 65 and 90 °C (optimum temperature, approximately 88 °C), in the presence of NaCl concentrations of 9.0-38.0 g per liter (optimum 19 g NaCl per liter) and at near-neutral pH (pH 6.8-7.0).  Sensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, penicillin G, phosphomycin, rifampicin and trimethoprim, but resistant to cycloheximide, kanamycin, neomycin sulfate, novobiocin, puromycin, streptomycin and vancomycin hydrochloride.  The type strain is strain 234T (=ATCC BAA-425T).  Electron donors not utilized: lactate, citrate, alanine, histidine, proline, glycine, L-Cysteine, aspartic acid, glutamic acid, DMSO, catechol, phenol, toluene, benzene, benzoic acid, and Fe(II).  Growth on sugars could not be investigated because the sugars reacted abiotically with the Fe(III) oxide at 85˚C.</description>
</treatment>
