<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haladaptatus_paucihalophilus</taxon_name>
  <strain>DX253T (=JCM 13897T=DSM 18195T=ATCC BAA-1313T=KCTC 4006T)</strain>
  <reference>Haladaptatus paucihalophilus gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from a low-salt, sulfide-rich spring IJSEM 57:19-24</reference>
  <file>Haladaptatus.paucihalophilus.pdf</file>
  <description>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.  Cells are approximately 1.2 µm in diameter.  Doubling time is approximately 12–13 h.  Nonmotile.  Colonies are small (0.2 mm), translucent, round and convex with entire margins.  Grows in NaCl at 0.8–5.1 M; optimum growth is at 2.6–3.1 M NaCl.  Optimal temperature for growth is 25–30 ˚C (range, 25–45˚C).  A minimum of 5 mM Mg2+ is required for growth.  Grows at pH 5.0–7.5, with an optimum at pH 6.0–6.5.  Does not grow anaerobically with NO3-, SO42-, elemental sulfur, S2O32-, DMSO or TMAO.  Does not ferment arginine.  Capable of using single carbon substrates.  Utilizes glutamic acid, histidine, norleucine, phenylalanine, D-glucuronic acid, dextrin, aesculin, salicin, trehalose, sucrose, fructose, xylose, glucose, starch, galactose, acetate, lactate, malate, fumarate, citrate, pyruvate, mannitol and glycerol.  Threonine, methionine, tyrosine, arginine, alanine, aspartic acid, glycine, lactose, succinate, sorbitol, dulcitol and 3,3-dimethylglutaric acid are not utilized as carbon sources.  Produces acid when grown on sucrose, xylose, glucose, starch, fructose, galactose, mannitol and glycerol.  Able to utilize complex carbon sources such as yeast extract and Casamino acids.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Indole is produced from tryptophan.  Does not reduce nitrate under aerobic conditions.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.5 mol%.  The type strain, DX253T (=JCM 13897T=DSM 18195T=ATCC BAA-1313T=KCTC 4006T), was isolated from Zodletone Spring in south-western Oklahoma, USA.  Hydrolyzes starch, casein, and Tween 80. Cells contain PG, PGP-Me and PGS. Two unidentified glycolipids are present.  Sensitive to novobiocin, bacitracin, anisomycin and aphidicolin.  Partially sensitive to rifampicin and trimethoprim.  Resistant to erythromycin, penicillin, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, neomycin, nalidixic acid and gentamicin.</description>
</treatment>
