<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haladaptatus_litoreus</taxon_name>
  <strain>RO1-28T (=CGMCC 1.7737T =JCM 15771T)</strain>
  <reference>Haladaptatus litoreus sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon from a marine solar saltern, and emended description of the genus Haladaptatus IJSEM 60:1085-1089</reference>
  <file>Haladaptatus.litoreus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are non-motile, coccus-shaped (1.0–1.5 µm) and Gram-stain-negative.  Colonies on MR2A agar plates containing 3.4 M NaCl are pink, elevated and round.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1.7–5.1 M, at Mg2+ concentrations of 0.05–0.7 M, at pH values in the range 6.0–8.5, and within the temperature range 25–55 ˚C.  Optimal NaCl concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 3.4 M, 7.0 and 37–40 ˚C, respectively.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine and DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed.  H2S is not produced from Na2S2O3.  Positive for indole formation.  Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed.  Positive for caseinase, amylase and gelatinase.  The following substrates are utilized as carbon sources for growth: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, starch, glycerol, D-mannitol, acetate, pyruvate, DL-lactate, fumarate, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate and L-ornithine.  D-Fructose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, lactose, D-sorbitol, succinate, L-malate, citrate, glycine and L-lysine are not utilized as carbon sources.  Produces acid when grown on D-glucose, D-galactose, sucrose, starch, maltose and glycerol.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg or IU per disc): rifampicin (5), novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU) and norfloxacin (10).  Resistant to the following antibiotics: erythromycin (15), neomycin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (10), penicillin G (10 IU), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The major polar lipids are PG, PGP-Me, PGS and three glycolipids, similar to the polar lipid profile of Haladaptatus paucihalophilus JCM 13897T.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 54.0% (HPLC).  The type strain is RO1-28T (=CGMCC 1.7737T =JCM 15771T), and was isolated from Rudong solar saltern in Jiangsu province, China.</description>
</treatment>
