<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halarchaeum_acidiphilum</taxon_name>
  <strain>MH1-52-1T (=JCM 16109T =DSM 22442T =CECT 7534T)</strain>
  <reference>Halarchaeum acidiphilum gen. nov., sp. nov., a moderately acidophilic haloarchaeon isolated from commercial solar salt IJSEM 60:2513-2516</reference>
  <file>Halarchaeum.acidiphilum.pdf</file>
  <description>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.  Cells are approximately 2.0 µm in diameter.  Colonies are approximately 1.0 mm in diameter, circular, smooth and non-pigmented.  Grows in 18–30% (w/v) NaCl, with optimum growth at 21–24% (w/v) NaCl.  A minimum of 1 mM Mg2+ is required for growth.  Optimal temperature for growth is 37 ˚C (range, 15– 45 ˚C).  Moderately acidophilic; grows at initial pH 4.0–6.0, with an optimum at pH 4.4–4.5.  Does not grow anaerobically with nitrate or DMSO.  Does not ferment arginine.  Capable of using the following single carbon substrates: arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, ribitol, raffinose, sucrose and xylose.  Lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, ribose, sorbitol, trehalose, citrate and glutamate are not utilized as carbon sources.  Able to utilize complex carbon sources such as yeast extract.  Sensitive to anisomycin, bacitracin, novobiocin, pravastatin, rifampicin and tetracycline.  Resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, penicillin, streptomycin and vancomycin.  Catalase- and oxidase-negative.  Gelatin, starch, casein and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  H2S is not produced from thiosulfate.  Does not reduce nitrate under aerobic conditions.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.4 mol%.  The type strain is MH1-52-1T (=JCM 16109T =DSM 22442T =CECT 7534T), isolated from solar salt imported into Japan from Australia.  Contained phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester as phospholipids, derived from both C20C20 and C20C25 archaeol, but not phosphatidylglycerol sulfate.  Contained at least four glycolipids that have yet to be identified, although the two overlapping spots might represent C20C20 and C20C25 moieties of a glycolipid.</description>
</treatment>
