<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halobacterium_noricense</taxon_name>
  <strain>A1 (=DSM 15987T, =ATCC BAA-852T, =NCIMB 13967T)</strain>
  <reference>Halobacterium noricense sp. nov., an archaeal isolate from a bore core of an alpine Permian salt deposit, classification of Halobacterium sp. NRC-1 as a strain of H. salinarum and emended description of H. salinarum Extremophiles 8:431-439</reference>
  <file>Halobacterium.noricense.pdf</file>
  <description>Rods 1.2–2.0 µm in length, growing in liquid media as single cells.  Gram-negative, motile, lyse in water, chemoorganotrophic and aerobic, facultatively anaerobic in the presence of L-Arginine or nitrate, but not DMSO.  Yeast extract and casamino acids support growth.  Requires at least 12.5% NaCl for growth, in the presence of 0.6 M MgCl2.  Optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 15.0–17.5%, in the presence of 0.7–0.8 M MgCl2.  Optimum temperature is 37–45 ˚C, pH range for growth is 5.2–7.0.  Small colonies (0.4 mm diameter after 18 days of incubation at 37 ˚C) on complex medium of neutral pH, light red, circular, entire margins.  Catalase positive, oxidase negative.  Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.  Gelatin is not liquefied.  Starch is not hydrolyzed.  The following compounds are not utilized: D-glucose, D-galactose, D-maltose, D-sucrose and D-xylose.  Glycerol and starch are utilized slowly.  Susceptible to anisomycin and novobiocin.  Resistant to ampicillin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, gentamycin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.  Main polar lipids are C20C20 derivatives of PG, Me-PGP, PGS, TGD and S-TeGD.  Menaquinones MK-8 and MK-8[H2] are the main components and MK-7, MK- 7[H2] and MK-9 are present in traces.  G+C content is 54.3– 54.5 mol%.  At least two plasmids of approximate sizes 200 kbp and 400 kbp are present.  The type strain was isolated from a dry bore core of Permian rock salt from the salt mine in Altaussee, Austria, approximately 470 m below surface.  The type strain is A1 (=DSM 15987T, =ATCC BAA-852T, =NCIMB 13967T).</description>
</treatment>
