<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Lisa Moore">
  <taxon_name>Halospirulina_tapeticola</taxon_name>
  <strain>NA</strain>
  <reference>The halotolerance and phylogeny of cyanobacteria with tightly coiled trichomes (Spirulina Turpin) and the description of Halospirulina tapeticola gen. nov., sp. nov. (Nubel, U., et al., 2000)</reference>
  <DOI>NA</DOI>
  <file>Nubel, U. et al. Halospirulina tapeticola.pdf</file>
  <description>tightly coiled trichomes, halotolerant, Cyanobacteria with tightly coiled trichomes are frequently found in thermal freshwater environments as well as in brackish, marine and hypersaline waters, Under favourable conditions they can form dense benthic populations and make major contributions to primary productivity., they are traditionally considered cosmopolitan micro-organisms with remarkable capabilities to acclimatize to broad ranges of environmental conditions, euryhaline cyanobacteria, from hypersaline waters, contained phycocyanin, Halotolerant, euryhaline cyanobacteria with trichomes coiled into a tight, closed helix, able to grow at salinities between 3 and 13 % or above, but not at freshwater salinities. Trichome widths are typically between 1±5 and 3 μ m, and helix widths vary between 4 and 6 lm. The cross walls are thin and invisible in live specimens. No sheath is visible under light microscopy. Gliding motility present, involving rotation. Found in sunlit hypersaline environments. Tolerate temperatures for growth of at least 38 °C. Type species is Halospirulina tapeticola., Halotolerant, euryhaline cyanobacteria with trichomes coiled into a tight, closed helix, able to grow at salinities between 3 and 20%, but not at freshwater salinities. Trichome and helix widths are 1±5 and 4 μ m, respectively. The cross walls are thin and invisible in live specimens. No sheath is visible under light microscopy. Gliding motility present, involving rotation. The axenic type strain is CCC Baja-95 Cl. 2T, which was isolated from a microbial mat in a hypersaline evaporation pond of a salina at the Pacific coast of Baja California, Mexico.</description>
</treatment>
