<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halobaculum_gomorrense</taxon_name>
  <strain>DSM 9297 (= DS2807)</strain>
  <reference>Halobaculum gomorrense gen. nov., sp. nov., a Novel Extremely Halophilic Archaeon from the Dead Sea IJSB 45:747-754</reference>
  <file>Halobaculum.gomorrense.pdf</file>
  <description>Rods are 5 to 10 by 0.5 to 1 µm.  Motile cells occur occasionally.  Gas vacuoles are not present.  Chemoorganotrophic and aerobic.  Yeast extract and Casamino Acids at low concentrations are good sources of organic nutrients.  No growth occurs anaerobically with nitrate or with arginine.  Requires at least 1 M NaCl for growth (in the presence of 0.8 M MgCl2).  The optimal NaCl concentration range is 1.5 to 2.5 M at 35 to 40°C; the optimal MgCl2, concentration range is 0.6 to 1 M (in the presence of 2.1 M NaCl).  The optimum temperature is 40°C (in medium containing 2.1 M NaCl and 0.8 M MgCl2).  Pigmented red because of carotenoids.  Purple membrane is not produced.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  No indole is produced from tryptophan.  Susceptible to novobiocin, bacitracin, anisomycin, vibriostatic agent 0/129, taurocholate, and deoxycholate.  Not susceptible to penicillin G, ampicillin, kanamycin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin sulfate, neomycin, and cycloheximide.  Glucose, maltose, sucrose, galactose, xylose, trehalose, starch, and glycerol stimulate growth with acid production.  Starch is hydrolyzed.  No acid is produced from mannose, fructose, ribose, lactose, arabinose, mannitol, and sorbitol.  Growth is stimulated by DL-lactate.  Growth is not stimulated by acetate, citrate, propionate, succinate, glycine, L-alanine, and L-glutamate.  Isolated from the Dead Sea.  The G+C content of the type strain is 70 mol% (as determined by HPLC).  The type strain is DSM 9297 (= DS2807).  Contained three polar lipids, the glycerol diether analogs of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerophosphate, and a single glycolipid.  The glycerol diether analog of phosphatidylglycerosulfate, which is present in all halophilic archaea except Haloferax species, was not detected.</description>
</treatment>
