<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_luteum</taxon_name>
  <strain>CGSA15T (=CGMCC 1.6783T =CECT 7303T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum luteum sp. nov., isolated from Lake Chagannor, Inner Mongolia, China IJSEM 58:1705-1708</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.luteum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are Gram-negative, pleomorphic (0.5–0.9 x 0.6– 1.5 µm) and motile.  Colonies growing on agar medium containing 4.0 M NaCl are small (1–2 mm in diameter), entire, smooth, round and orange.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 2.5– 5.2 M, at pH 7.5–10.5 and at 17–41 ˚C.  Optimal NaCl concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 4.0– 4.3 M, pH 9.5–10.0 and 33–37 ˚C.  Magnesium is not required for growth.  Cells lyse in distilled water.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate, arginine or DMSO does not occur.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed.  H2S is produced from Na2S2O3.  Indole formation is positive.  Tween 80, casein and starch are not hydrolysed.  Gelatin is not liquefied.  Glucose, mannose, maltose, lactose, mannitol and D-sorbitol are utilized but acid production is not clearly observed.  Growth occurs on succinate, L-aspartic acid, pyruvate, glycerol, DL-lactate, L-malate, fumarate, citrate, glycine, L-alanine, L-glutamate and L-ornithine.  The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: fructose, xylose, sorbose, galactose, D-ribose, sucrose, L-lysine, acetate, starch and L-arginine.  Sensitive to erythromycin (15 µg) and novobiocin (30 µg).  Resistant to neomycin (30 µg), rifampicin (5 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), bacitracin (0.04 IU), ampicillin (10 µg), penicillin G (10 IU), norfloxacin (10 µg), ciprofloxacin (5 µg), streptomycin (10 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), tetracycline (30 µg) and vancomycin (30 µg).  Cells contain phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, but lack phosphatidylglycerol sulfate and glycolipids.  The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 60.2 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, CGSA15T (=CGMCC 1.6783T =CECT 7303T), was isolated from Lake Chagannor in Inner Mongolia, China.</description>
</treatment>
