<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorhabdus_utahensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>AX-2T = DSM 12940T</strain>
  <reference>Halorhabdus utahensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic, extremely halophilic member of the Archaea from Great Salt Lake, Utah IJSEM 50:183-190</reference>
  <file>Halorhabdus.utahensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are extremely pleomorphic although most are rod-shaped.  Rod-shaped cells are 0.5-1 µm wide and 2-10 µm long.  Motile by a single flagellum.  Colonies are red and circular with an entire margin and a shiny surface.  Extremely halophilic and lyse in water.  Grows at 9-30% (1.5-5.1 M) NaCl; optimum growth at 27% (4.6 M) NaCl.  Grows between 0.05 and 20% MgSO4 (2-800 mM) in the presence of 27% NaCl.  Grows at temperatures from 17 to 55 °C, with an optimum at 50 °C.  The pH range for growth is 5.5-8.5, with an optimum between 6.7 and 7.1.  Ferments glucose.  Sulfur stimulates fermentative growth.  Amino acids are not required for growth; grows under aerobic or anaerobic conditions in defined media.  Gram-negative cell wall.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Amino acids are not decarboxylated or deaminated.  Produces b-glucosidase and lipase.  Does not produce b-galactosidase.  Hydrogen sulfide is produced.  Methyl red and Voges-Proskauer tests are negative.  No utilization of citrate (Simmons' citrate).  No production of indole.  PHB is produced.  Acid is produced from carbohydrates.  Cells are resistant to ampicillin, carbenicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, penicillin, polymyxins, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline but susceptible to bacitracin and novobiocin.  A limited number of organic substrates are used for growth.  Ether lipids are diphytanyl derivatives.  MK- 8 and MK-8(VIII-H2) are the only respiratory lipoquinones present.  The polar lipids present are PG, Me- PGP, TGD, S-TGD and an unknown component.  PGS is absent.  The following substrates (0.2%, w/v) are utilized for growth: glucose, xylose and fructose.  No growth on amylose, arginine, d-arabinose, d-galactose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, acetate, citrate, formiate, d-glucuronate, lactate, pyruvate, N-acetyl-glucosamine, l-alanine, betaine, l-lysine, phenylalanine, l-proline, l-serine, acetamide, ethanol, glycerol, methanol, d-sorbitol, glycogen, peptone, yeast extract, starch, casein, gelatin or Tween 80.  Aesculin is hydrolysed.  No hydrolysis of gelatin or starch.  Does not produce protease or urease.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase or tryptophan deaminase.  The G+C content of the DNA of the only strain known in the species is 64 mol%.  The type strain, strain AX-2T, isolated from Great Salt Lake, UT, USA, has been deposited in the Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen und Zellkulturen GmbH (Braunschweig, Germany) as strain DSM 12940T.</description>
</treatment>
