<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halogeometricum_rufum</taxon_name>
  <strain>RO1-4T (=CGMCC 1.7736T =JCM 15770T)</strain>
  <reference>Halogeometricum rufum sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon from a marine solar saltern, and emended description of the genus Halogeometricum IJSEM 60:2613-2617</reference>
  <file>Halogeometricum.rufum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile, pleomorphic (short and long rods and irregular cocci) under optimal growth conditions and stain Gram-negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 3.9 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at 25–55 ˚C (optimum 40– 42 ˚C), at 2.1–5.1 M NaCl (optimum 3.9 M NaCl), at 0.05–0.7 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.3 M MgCl2) and at pH 6.0–8.5 (optimum pH 7.0).  Cells lyse in distilled water and the minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis is 12% (w/v).  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is not observed.  Nitrite is reduced.  H2S is produced from sodium thiosulfate.  Positive for indole formation.  Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, casein, starch and gelatin are not hydrolysed.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources for growth: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, glycerol, D-sorbitol, acetate, pyruvate, DL-lactate, L-alanine and L-glutamate.  D-Fructose, succinate, L-malate, fumarate, L-ornithine, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, starch, D-mannitol, citrate, glycine, L-arginine, L-aspartate and L-lysine are not utilized as carbon sources.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): rifampicin (5), novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU per disc), anisomycin (20) and aphidicolin (20).  Resistant to the following antibiotics: erythromycin (15), neomycin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (10), penicillin G (10 IU per disc), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The major polar lipids are PG, PGP-Me, S-DGD-1 and DGD-1.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.9% (as determined by HPLC).  The type strain is RO1-4T (=CGMCC 1.7736T =JCM 15770T) and was isolated from Rudong solar saltern in Jiangsu province, China.</description>
</treatment>
