<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorussus_rarus</taxon_name>
  <strain>TBN4T (=CGMCC 1.10122T = JCM 16429T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorussus rarus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Halobacteriaceae isolated from a marine solar saltern Extremophiles 14:493-499</reference>
  <file>Halorussus.rarus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile and rod shaped (1.0–5.0 by 0.4–0.5 µm) under optimal growth conditions and stain Gram-negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 2.1 M NaCl are light red, elevated and round.  Chemoorganotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at 25–50 ˚C (optimum 37 ˚C), at 1.4–4.3 M NaCl (optimum 2.1 M NaCl), at 0–1.0 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.005 M MgCl2) and at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.0).  Cells lyse in distilled water and minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis is 8% (w/v).  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Do not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine and DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed and no gas formation from nitrate.  H2S is produced from sodium thiosulfate and positive for indole formation.  Tween 80, casein and gelatin are hydrolyzed, starch is hydrolyzed weakly.  Urease activity is detected but lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.  PHA (Poly-b-hydroxyalkanoate) is not produced.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources for growth: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, starch, glycerol, D-mannitol, acetate, pyruvate, DL-lactate, succinate, L-malate and citrate.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon, nitrogen or energy sources for growth: L-alanine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate and L-ornithine.  No growth occurred on D-fructose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, D-sorbitol, fumarate, glycine, L-arginine and L-lysine.  Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, sucrose and lactose.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU per disc), anisomycin (20), aphidicolin (20) and rifampin (5).  Resistant to the following antibiotics: erythromycin (15), penicillin G (10 IU per disc), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), neomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The polar lipids are PG (phosphatidylglycerol), PGP-Me (phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester), PGS (phosphatidylglycerol sulfate) and five glycolipids chromatographically identical to S-TGD-1 (sulfated galactosyl mannosyl glucosyl diether), S-DGD-1 (sulfated mannosyl glucosyl diether), TGD-1 (galactosyl mannosyl glucosyl diether), DGD-1 (mannosyl glucosyl diether) and DGD-2 (an unknown diglycosyl diether).  The DNA G+C content of TBN4T is 66.1 mol% (as determined by HPLC).  The type strain is TBN4T (=CGMCC 1.10122T = JCM 16429T), and was isolated from Taibei marine solar saltern near Lianyungang city of Jiangsu province, China.</description>
</treatment>
