<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloterrigena_daqingensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>JX313T (=CGMCC 1.8909T =NBRC 105739T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloterrigena daqingensis sp. nov., an extremely haloalkaliphilic archaeon isolated from a saline–alkaline soil IJSEM 60:2267-2271</reference>
  <file>Haloterrigena.daqingensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are coccoid, 0.8–1.3 µm in diameter.  Non-motile, occurring singly or in pairs or irregular clusters.  Cells do not lyse in distilled water.  Many cells are Gram-negative and a few others stain Gram-positive in young cultures.  Colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter after 7 days of incubation on S-G medium at 37 ˚C, orange-pigmented, smooth, circular and convex.  Haloalkaliphilic; growth occurs in 1.7–5.5 M NaCl (optimum at 2.0–2.5 M NaCl), at pH 8.0– 10.5 (optimum at pH 10.0) and at 20–50 ˚C (optimum at 35 ˚C).  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.  Anaerobic growth does not occur with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is not observed.  H2S is produced from Na2S2O3.  Indole formation is negative.  Negative for caseinase, amylase and gelatinase.  Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed.  The following substrates are utilized as carbon sources: glycerol, acetate, pyruvate, succinate, aspartate and glutamate.  Glucose, maltose, fructose, sucrose, trehalose, mannose, D-xylose, lactose, D-ribose, rhamnose, galactose, cellobiose, arabinose, starch, mannitol, sorbitol, inositol, citrate, lactate, fumarate, arginine, lysine, alanine and glycine are not utilized for growth.  Acid is produced from glycerol only.  Sensitive to (µg per disc) rifampicin (5), ciprofloxacin (5), erythromycin (15) and novobiocin (30).  Resistant to (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): streptomycin (10), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), kanamycin (30), lincomycin (2), neomycin (30), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), norfloxacin (10), penicillin G (10 IU) and bacitracin (0.04 IU).  The major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol methyl ester and S2-DGD.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 59.3 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, JX313T (=CGMCC 1.8909T =NBRC 105739T), was isolated from a saline and alkaline soil of Daqing, Heilongjiang, China.</description>
</treatment>
