<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halococcus_dombrowskii</taxon_name>
  <strain>H4T (=DSM 14522T=NCIMB 13803T=ATCC BAA-364T)</strain>
  <reference>Halococcus dombrowskii sp. nov., an archaeal isolate from a Permian alpine salt deposit IJSEM 52:1807-1814</reference>
  <file>Halococcus.dombrowskii.pdf</file>
  <description>Cocci of 0.8-1.2 µm in diameter, occurring as single cells, diplococci or small clusters of 2-5 cells.  Gram negative, non-motile and aerobic.  Small colonies (1-2 mm in diameter after 1 week incubation at 37 °C) when grown on complex medium of neutral pH, with light-red pigmentation and circular, entire margins.  Optimum temperature for growth is 37-40 °C; pH range for growth is 5.8-8.0.  Optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 20-25%; no growth observed below 15% NaCl.  Optimum growth when between 20 and 60 mM Mg2+ is available in the presence of 4 M NaCl.  Oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  Gelatin is liquefied.  Can utilize D-glucose, L-arginine, L-glutamic acid, L-methionine, and L-serine for growth.  Susceptible to bacitracin, novobiocin and rifampicin, slightly susceptible to anisomycin, chloramphenicol and tetracycline, and resistant to ampicillin, aphidicolin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.  The G+C content of the DNA is 61.3 mol%.  Main polar lipids are C20C20 and C20C25 derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol phosphate.  Sulfated mannosylglucosylglycerol diether is present; phosphatidylglycerol sulfate is absent.  Menaquinones MK-7(H2), MK-8(H2) and MK-8 are present.  Wholecell proteins are acidic with isoelectric points predominantly between pH 4.2 and 5.2.  The type strain was isolated from dry Permian rock salt from the salt mine in Bad Ischl, Austria, 650 m below the Earth's surface.  The type strain is H4T (=DSM 14522T=NCIMB 13803T=ATCC BAA-364T).</description>
</treatment>
