<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloarcula_amylolytica</taxon_name>
  <strain>BD-3T (=CGMCC 1.5335T=JCM13557T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloarcula amylolytica sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from Aibi salt lake in Xin-Jiang, China IJSEM 57:103-106</reference>
  <file>Haloarcula.amylolytica.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are rod-shaped (0.6–0.8 x 2.0–2.5 µm), motile and Gram-negative.  Colonies on salt-milk and standard growth agar plates containing 18% (w/v) NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 2.0–5.1 M, Mg2+ concentrations of 0.005–0.70 M, pH 6.5–9.0 and temperature of 20–52 ˚C.  Optimal NaCl concentration, Mg2+ concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 2.9–3.2 M, 0.10–0.30 M, pH 7.0–7.5 and 41 ˚C, respectively.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Anaerobic growth occurs in the presence of nitrate with formation of nitrite and gas.  No anaerobic growth in the presence of arginine or DMSO.  H2S is produced from Na2S2O3.  Indole formation is positive.  Tweens 20, 40, 60, 80 and starch are hydrolysed.  Casein is not hydrolysed.  Gelatin is liquefied.  Glucose, sucrose, galactose, sorbitol, mannose, mannitol and maltose are utilized and acids are produced.  No growth is observed on fructose, sorbose, xylose, lactose or D-ribose.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics: novobiocin (30 µg per disc) and bacitracin (0.04 IU per disc).  Resistant to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): ampicillin (10), rifampicin (5), erythromycin (15), tetracycline (30), ciprofloxacin (5), chloramphenicol (30), kanamycin (30), neomycin (30), vancomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), streptomycin (10) and penicillin G (10 IU per disc).  The molar G+C content of the DNA is 62.4% (Tm).  The major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, phosphatidylglycerosulfate, triglycosyl diether and an unknown diglycosyl diether.  The type strain, BD-3T (=CGMCC 1.5335T=JCM13557T), was isolated from Aibi salt lake in Xin-Jiang, China.</description>
</treatment>
