<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halomicrobium_zhouii</taxon_name>
  <strain>TBN51T (=CGMCC 1.10457T=JCM 17095T)</strain>
  <reference>Halomicrobium zhouii sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon from a marine solar saltern IJSEM 62:1235-1240</reference>
  <file>Halomicrobium.zhouii.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are Gram-staining-negative, motile and pleomorphic (rods and irregular shapes) under optimal growth conditions.  Colonies on agar plates containing 3.6 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Growth occurs at 20–55 ˚C (optimum 42 ˚C), in the presence of 1.4–5.1 M NaCl (optimum 2.6 M), with 0–1.0 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.05 M) and at pH 5.5–9.5 (optimum pH 7.0).  Cells lyse in distilled water.  The minimum NaCl concentration needed to prevent cell lysis is 8% (w/v).  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Reduces nitrate to nitrite and produces H2S from sodium thiosulfate.  Does not form indole or hydrolyse starch, gelatin, Tween 80 or casein.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources for growth: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, sucrose, lactose, glycerol, acetate, pyruvate and DL-lactate.  L-Glutamate is utilized as a single carbon, nitrogen or energy source for growth.  No growth occurs on the following substrates when offered as single carbon and energy sources: D-fructose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, maltose, starch, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, succinate, L-malate, fumarate and citrate.  The following substrates are not utilized as single carbon, nitrogen or energy sources for growth: glycine, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-aspartate, L-lysine and L-ornithine.  Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, sucrose and lactose.  Sensitive to the following antimicrobial compounds (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU per disc), rifampicin (5), mycostatin (100) and nitrofurantoin (300).  Resistant to the following antimicrobial compounds: trimethoprim (5), erythromycin (15), ampicillin (10), penicillin G (10 IU per disc), chloramphenicol (30), neomycin (30), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), vancomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), tetracycline (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  Major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, phosphatidylglycerol sulphate and a glycolipid that is chromatographically identical to sulfated mannosyl glucosyl diether.  Mannosyl glucosyl diether is present as a minor glycolipid.  The type strain is TBN51T (=CGMCC 1.10457T=JCM 17095T), which was isolated from Taibei marine solar saltern in Jiangsu province, China.  The genomic DNA G+C content of strain TBN51T is 69.1 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
