<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_arcis</taxon_name>
  <strain>AJ201T (=CGMCC 1.5343T=JCM 13916T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum arcis sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from a saline lake on the Qinghai–Tibet Plateau, China IJSEM 57:1069-1072</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.arcis.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram-negative and motile.  Young cultures show rod-like cells (0.5–1 x 2–4 µm).  Colonies on complex agar medium are 1–2 mm in diameter, smooth, circular, elevated and red.  Halophilic.  Cells lyse immediately in distilled water.  NaCl concentration required for growth is 2.2–5.2 M, with an optimum at 3.4–3.9 M.  Magnesium is not required for growth, and the optimum Mg2+ concentration is 20–200 mM.  The pH and temperature for growth are pH 6.0– 8.5 (optimum pH 7.5) and 25–55 ˚C (optimum 42 ˚C).  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Anaerobic growth does not occur with arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  H2S is produced from thiosulfate.  Starch is hydrolysed.  Tween 80 and casein are not hydrolysed.  Gelatin is not liquefied.  Casamino acids are required for growth.  The following substrates are utilized for growth: glucose, maltose, glycerol and starch.  No growth is observed on arabinose, fructose, galactose, lactose, mannitol, mannose, rhamnose, ribose, sorbitol, sucrose, xylose, alanine, arginine, aspartate, glycine, glutamate, lysine, ornithine, acetate, citrate, fumarate, lactate, malate, propionate, pyruvate or succinate.  Acid is produced from glucose, maltose and glycerol.  Sensitive to novobiocin, bacitracin, anisomycin and rifampicin, but not to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, neomycin or penicillin.  The major polar lipids are C20C20 derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, phosphatidylglycerol sulfate and sulfated mannosylglucosyl- glycerol diether.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.7 mol% (Tm).  The type strain is strain AJ201T (=CGMCC 1.5343T=JCM 13916T), isolated from a salt lake on the Qinghai–Tibet Plateau.</description>
</treatment>
