<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_litoreum</taxon_name>
  <strain>Fa-1T (=CGMCC 1.5336T =JCM 13561T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum litoreum sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon from a solar saltern IJSEM 57:2204-2206</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.litoreum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile, rod-shaped (0.3–0.5 x 2.0–5.0 µm) and Gram-negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 3.4 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemoorganotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 2.0–5.1 M, at Mg2+ concentrations of 0.03–0.7 M, at pH values in the range 6.5–9.0 and at temperatures in the range 20–55 ˚C.  The optimal NaCl concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 3.4 M, pH 7.0–7.5 and 37–42 ˚C.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed.  H2S is produced from Na2S2O3.  Negative for indole formation.  Tween 80 is hydrolysed weakly; negative for caseinase, amylase and gelatinase.  The following substrates are utilized as carbon sources for growth: glucose, galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, glycerol, acetate, pyruvate, malate, fumarate, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-glutamate and L-ornithine.  Mannose, fructose, sorbose, D-ribose, xylose, starch, mannitol, D-sorbitol, lactate, succinate, citrate, glycine, L-aspartate and L-lysine are not utilized as carbon sources.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg per disc): rifampicin (5), novobiocin (30).  Resistant to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), ciprofloxacin (5), erythromycin (15), kanamycin (30), neomycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), streptomycin (10), bacitracin (0.04 IU) and penicillin G (10 IU).  Major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, phosphatidylglycerol sulfate and sulfated diglycosyl diether.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.9 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, Fa-1T (=CGMCC 1.5336T =JCM 13561T), was isolated from the Fuqing solar saltern in Fujian Province, China.</description>
</treatment>
