<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorientalis_regularis</taxon_name>
  <strain>TNN28T (=CGMCC 1.10123T =JCM 16425T)</strain>
  <reference>Halobellus clavatus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Halorientalis regularis gen. nov., sp. nov., two new members of the family Halobacteriaceae IJSEM 61:2682-2689</reference>
  <file>Halobellus.clavatus.Halorientalis.regularis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile, pleomorphic, rod-shaped, ~0.5–1.0 x 1– 6 µm under optimal growth conditions and Gram-reaction negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 18–20% (w/v) NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at 20–50 ˚C (optimum 37 ˚C), in 15–30% (w/v) NaCl (optimum 18–20 %), with 0.005–1.0 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.01–0.3 M) and at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5).  Cells lyse in distilled water; minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis is 12% (w/v).  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Reduction of nitrate to nitrite is observed.  Hydrogen sulfide is produced from sodium thiosulfate and indole formation is positive.  Hydrolyses Tween 80 and weakly hydrolyses starch but does not hydrolyse gelatin or casein.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, sucrose, starch, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, acetate, pyruvate, DL-lactate, succinate, L-malate, fumarate, citrate, L-arginine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-lysine and L-ornithine.  D-Fructose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, maltose, lactose, glycine and L-alanine are not utilized as carbon sources.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU), anisomycin (20), aphidicolin (20) and rifampicin (5); resistant to: erythromycin (15), penicillin G (10 IU), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), neomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The polar lipids are PG, PGP-Me and one major GL, which is chromatographically identical to S-DGD-1; three to four minor unidentified glycolipids (GL2–GL5) are also detectable.  The DNA G+C content is 61.5– 61.9 mol%.  The type strain, TNN28T (=CGMCC 1.10123T =JCM 16425T), was isolated from the Taibei marine solar saltern near Lianyungang city, Jiangsu province, China.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.9 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
