<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halomicrobium_mukohataei</taxon_name>
  <strain>arg-2T (=JCM 9738T=DSM 12286T=ATCC 700874T=NCIMB 13541T).</strain>
  <reference>Halomicrobium mukohataei gen. nov., comb. nov., and emended description of Halomicrobium mukohataei IJSEM 52:1831-1835</reference>
  <file>Halomicrobium.mukohataei.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram-negative.  Motile by means of flagella inserted peritrichously and/or in tufts.  Short or longer rods in actively growing cultures (1-3 or 3-8 x 0.5 µm, depending on the composition of the medium and on growth conditions); pleomorphic in stationary cultures.  Colonies are about 2 mm in diameter after one week incubation at 40 °C on 1.5% agar plates containing 20% salt; they are translucent, entire, smooth and red-orange.  Chemo-organotrophic.  Grows aerobically or anaerobically in the presence of nitrate, with the formation of nitrite and gas.  Does not grow anaerobically in the presence of l-arginine.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Extremely halophilic, requiring between 2.5 and 4.5 M NaCl for growth and at least 2 M NaCl for structural stability.  Grows optimally in the presence of 3.0-3.5 M NaCl at 40-45 °C.  The pH range for growth is 6.2-8.0.  The minimum Mg2+ concentration required is 3 mM in solid medium; no concentration dependence for growth was observed at Mg2+ concentrations between 3 and 300 mM.  Acids are produced from glucose, galactose, mannose, ribose, sucrose, maltose and glycerol.  Glucose, galactose, sucrose, maltose and glycerol support growth as single carbon and energy sources.  Starch is hydrolysed.  Does not hydrolyse gelatin or casein.  Tween 80 is not hydrolysed.  Does not produce indole from tryptophan.  Polar lipids include phosphatidylglycerol, Mephosphatidylglycerophosphate, phosphatidylglycerosulfate and an unidentified monosulfated diglycosyl diether lipid.  Contains a retinal proton pump.  The fructose-1,6-bisphosphate aldolase is class I (EDTA insensitive).  Resistant to chloramphenicol (30 µg per mL), kanamycin (30 µg per mL) and penicillin (10 IU per mL).  Susceptible to anisomycin (10 µg per mL), novobiocin (5 µg per mL) and pravastatin (10 µg per mL).  The genomic DNA G+C content is 65 mol% (as determined by the thermal denaturation method).  The type strain, isolated from soil collected from a salt flat in Argentina, is strain arg-2T (=JCM 9738T=DSM 12286T=ATCC 700874T=NCIMB 13541T).</description>
</treatment>
