<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubellus_salinus</taxon_name>
  <strain>GX3T (=CGMCC 1.10384T = JCM 17115T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubellus salinus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Halorubellus litoreus sp. nov., novel halophilic archaea isolated from a marine solar saltern Syst Appl Microbiol 35:30-34</reference>
  <file>Halorubellus.salinus.litoreus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile, pleomorphic shaped under optimal growth conditions and stain Gram-negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 3.1 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemoorganotrophic and aerobic: growth occurs at 25–50 ˚C (optimum 37 ˚C), at 1.4–5.1 M NaCl (optimum 3.1 M), at 0–0.7 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.05 M) and at pH 5.5–9.5 (optimum pH 7.0).  Cells lyse in distilled water and the minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis is 8% (w/v).  Catalase- and oxidase-positive: do not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed.  H2S is produced from sodium thiosulfate.  Indole formation is negative.  Hydrolyze gelatin and casein but do not hydrolyze starch and Tween 80.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources for growth: glycerol, pyruvate, succinate and fumarate.  l-Lysine is utilized as single carbon, nitrogen or energy source for growth.  No growth occurred on the following substrates provided as single carbon and energy sources: d-glucose, d-mannose, d-galactose, d-fructose, l-sorbose, d-ribose, d-xylose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, starch, d-mannitol, d-sorbitol, acetate, dl-lactate, l-malate and citrate.  The following substrates are not utilized as single carbon, nitrogen or energy sources for growth: glycine, l-alanine, l-arginine, l-aspartate, l-glutamate and l-ornithine.  Acid is not produced from the sugars.  Sensitive to the following antimicrobial compounds (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU per disc), rifampin (5), mycostatin (100) and nitrofurantoin (300).  Resistant to the following antimicrobial compounds: trimethoprim (5), erythromycin (15), ampicillin (10), penicillin G (10 IU per disc), chloramphenicol (30), neomycin (30), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), vancomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), tetracycline (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The polar lipids are PA (phosphatidic acid), PG (phosphatidylglycerol), PGP-Me (phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester) and three major glycolipids chromatographically identical to STGD- 1 (sulfated galactosyl mannosyl glucosyl diether), S-DGD-1 (sulfated mannosyl glucosyl diether), and DGD-1 (mannosyl glucosyl diether), respectively.  The DNA G+C content of GX3T is 67.3 mol% (Tm).  The type strain GX3T (=CGMCC 1.10384T = JCM 17115T) was isolated from the Gangxi marine solar saltern near the Weihai city of Shandong Province, China.</description>
</treatment>
