<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_ezzemoulense</taxon_name>
  <strain>5.1T (=CECT 7099T=DSM 17463T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum ezzemoulense sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from Ezzemoul sabkha, Algeria IJSEM 56:1583-1588</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.ezzemoulense.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells stain Gram-negative, are motile, lyse in distilled water and are pleomorphic.  Cells occur mostly as single rods and exhibit a range of morphological types, including irregular rod-shaped, cocci and triangular forms.  Rods are 0.6 x 1.5– 3.0 µm.  Colonies on standard agar growth medium are 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter, circular, convex, entire and red.  Chemo-organotrophic, aerobic growth occurs at 15–25% (w/v) NaCl, pH 6.5–9.0 and 22–50 ˚C.  Optimum NaCl concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 20% (w/v), pH 7.0–7.5 and 37–40 ˚C, respectively.  Mg2+ is required for growth.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate or L-arginine does not occur.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  Indole is not produced.  Gelatin is not liquefied.  Starch, aesculin and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.  Lactose, xylose, rhamnose, galactose, raffinose, cellobiose, mannose, fructose, starch, inositol, sorbitol, dulcitol, adonitol, salicin, cellulose, malonate, fumarate, formate and amino acids are not utilized.  Glucose, sucrose, maltose, arabinose, mannitol, glycerol, acetate, oxalate, citrate and malate are used as carbon sources.  Acids are produced from glucose, lactose, xylose, galactose and rhamnose.  Sensitive to novobiocin and bacitracin, but resistant to penicillin, chloramphenicol, ampicillin, rifampicin, streptomycin and neomycin.  Polar lipids are C20C20 derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester.  Also contains phosphatidylglycerol sulfate and a sulfated diglycosyl diether.  The G+C content of genomic DNA of the type strain is 61.9 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, 5.1T (=CECT 7099T=DSM 17463T), was isolated from Ezzemoul sabkha in Algeria. Gas vacuoles absent.</description>
</treatment>
