<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorhabdus_tiamatea</taxon_name>
  <strain>SARL4BT (=DSM 18392T=JCM 14471T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorhabdus tiamatea sp. nov., a non-pigmented, extremely halophilic archaeon from a deep-sea, hypersaline anoxic basin of the Red Sea, and emended description of the genus Halorhabdus IJSEM 58:215-220</reference>
  <file>Halorhabdus.tiamatea.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram-negative, pleomorphic cells ranging from rods to coccoid or irregular forms (0.5–1 x 1–8 µm).  Flagella are not observed.  Colonies on HBM agar are round, nonpigmented and 2–3 mm in diameter.  Extremely halophilic: growth occurs at NaCl concentrations between 10 and 30% (w/v), with optimum growth occurring at approximately 27% (w/v) NaCl.  Growth occurs with MgSO4*7H2O at 0–25% (w/v).  The temperature range for growth is between 15 and 55 ˚C (optimal temperature, 45 ˚C) and the pH range is between approximately 5.5 and 8.5 (optimal pH, 6.5–7.0).  Grows under anaerobic and microaerophilic conditions; shows extremely poor aerobic growth.  Produces acid from maltose and yeast extract.  Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.  Methyl red test is positive and Voges–Proskauer test is negative.  Indole is not produced.  Poly-b-hydroxybutyrate is produced.  Gelatin and aesculin are hydrolysed; starch is weakly hydrolysed.  Casein and Tween 80 are not hydrolysed.  Maltose and yeast extract are used for growth.  Glucose, xylose, fructose, galactose, and proline are weakly assimilated.  Amylose, L-arabinose, lactose, sucrose, sodium acetate, sodium citrate, sodium formate, sodium glucuronate, sodium lactate, sodium pyruvate, N-acetylglucosamine, alanine, betaine, lysine, phenylalanine, serine, acetamide, ethanol, glycerol, methanol, sorbitol, glycogen and peptone are not utilized.  a-Glucosidase and b-glucosidase are present.  Weak reactions also detected for a-galactosidase, b-galactosidase and b-glucuronidase.  Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, a-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, N-acetyl-b-glucosaminidase, a-mannosidase and a-fucosidase are not detected.  Cells are resistant to ampicillin, cephalosporin C, chloramphenicol (25 µg per mL), erythromycin, neomycin, penicillin G and tetracycline, but susceptible to anisomycin, aphidicolin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol (50 µg per mL), novobiocin and rifamycin B.  The ether lipids are diphytanyl derivatives.  MK-8(VIII-H2) is the only respiratory lipoquinone present.  The major polar lipids present are phosphatidylglycerol, methylated phosphatidylglycerophosphate, triglycosyl diether, sulfated diglycosyl diether and an unknown component.  Phosphatidylglycerosulfate is absent.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.7 mol%.  The type strain, SARL4BT (=DSM 18392T=JCM 14471T), was isolated from the brine–sediment interface of the Shaban Deep in the Red Sea.</description>
</treatment>
