<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halovivax_asiaticus</taxon_name>
  <strain>EJ-46T (=CGMCC1.4248T=CECT 7098T)</strain>
  <reference>Halovivax asiaticus gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from Inner Mongolia, China IJSEM 56:765-770</reference>
  <file>Halovivax.asiaticus.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram-negative.  Cells are extremely pleomorphic, although most are rod-shaped.  Colonies are pale-pink pigmented.  Strictly aerobic; oxygen is used as the final electron acceptor.  Growth occurs at pH 6.0–9.0, 25–45 ˚C and in 15–25% (2.5–4.3 M) NaCl.  Optimum growth occurs at pH 7.0–7.5, 37 ˚C and 20% (3.4 M) NaCl.  Polar lipids include phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, two major and one minor glycolipids similar to those of Natrinema pellirubrum and a unidentified glycolipid.  Isolated from salt lakes.  Phylogenetically affiliated to the Halobacteriaceae.  The type species of the genus is Halovivax asiaticus. Cells are 0.4–0.5 x 4.0–5.0 µm.  Colonies are circular and 1–2 mm in diameter after incubation for 10 days at 37 ˚C.  Extremely halophilic and the cells lyse in water.  MgCl2 is not required.  Growth does not occur above 50 ˚C.  Amino acids are not required for growth.  Catalase-positive and weakly positive for oxidase.  Production of indole and methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons citrate tests are negative.  H2S is produced from cysteine.  Acid is produced from xylose.  Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.  Produces urease.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate or L-arginine does not occur.  Starch, aesculin, phosphatase and DNase are not hydrolysed.  Gelatin, Tween 80 and casein are hydrolysed.  Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.  The following substrates are utilized for growth: lactose, raffinose, xylose, propionate, glutamate, trehalose and acetate.  No growth occurs on mannitol, D-arabinose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, glycerol, sorbitol, fructose, D-glucose, ribose, starch, succinate, malate or fumarate.  Sensitive to bacitracin and novobiocin.  Resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline.  The G+C content of the DNA of the type and only strain is 60.3 mol%.  The type strain, EJ-46T (=CGMCC1.4248T=CECT 7098T), was isolated from the saline Lake Ejinor in Inner Mongolia, China.</description>
</treatment>
