<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_ejinorense</taxon_name>
  <strain>EJ-32T (=CECT 7194T=CGMCC 1.6782T=JCM 14265T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum ejinorense sp. nov., isolated from Lake Ejinor, Inner Mongolia, China IJSEM 57:2538-2542</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.ejinorense.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are Gram-negative rods 1.0–1.5 x 5.0–8.0 µm in size.  Colonies on agar plates containing 25% (w/v) total salt are red, elevated and round.  Growth occurs with 2.5–5.0 M NaCl at pH 6–10 and 25–50 ˚C.  The optimal NaCl concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 3.4 M, pH 7.5 and 37 ˚C, respectively.  Magnesium is not required for growth.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Catalase= and oxidase-positive.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate or L-arginine does not occur and nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed.  H2S is not produced from cysteine.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons citrate test results are negative.  Tween 80 and DNA are hydrolysed.  Casein, gelatin and starch are not hydrolysed.  Acid is not produced from D-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, sucrose, trehalose or D-xylose.  Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.  Growth occurs on trehalose as a single carbon and energy source.  The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: acetate, D-arabinose, fumarate, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-glutamate, glycerol, lactose, malate, maltose, D-mannitol, propionate, D-raffinose, D-ribose, D-sorbitol, succinate and D-xylose.  The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen or energy sources: L-asparagine, isoleucine, L-lysine and L-threonine.  Serine and glycine are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen or energy sources.  Susceptible to bacitracin (10 U) and novobiocin (30 µg).  Resistant to the following antibiotics (µg unless indicated otherwise): ampicillin (10), cephalothin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), nalidixic acid (30), neomycin (10), penicillin G (10 U), rifampicin (30), polymyxin (300 U), streptomycin (10), sulfamethoxazole (25), tetracycline (30) and vancomycin (30).  The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerophosphate methyl ester.  Glycolipids not detected.  The DNA G+C content is 64.0 mol%.  The type strain, EJ-32T (=CECT 7194T=CGMCC 1.6782T=JCM 14265T), was isolated from Lake Ejinor, a salt lake in Inner Mongolia, China.</description>
</treatment>
