<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halococcus_hamelinensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>100A6T (=JCM12892T=ACM 5227T)</strain>
  <reference>Halococcus hamelinensis sp. nov., a novel halophilic archaeon isolated from stromatolites in Shark Bay, Australia IJSEM 56:1323-1329</reference>
  <file>Halococcus.hamelinensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are cocci with a diameter of 0.8–1.2 µm and occur singly, in pairs, tetrads or as irregular clusters.  Gram negative, non-motile and strictly aerobic.  Small, bright orange–pink, circular colonies are formed after 1 week incubation at 37 ˚C on agar media.  The optimum NaCl concentration for growth is 15% (w/v), with a doubling time of 13–15 h; capable of growth in 12.5–30% (w/v) NaCl.  The optimum temperature and pH range for growth are 37 ˚C and pH 4–9.  0.5–50 mM MgCl2 is required for growth.  Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.  Hydrolyses starch.  Indole is not produced.  Negative for sulphide reduction, urease and gelatin liquefaction.  Utilizes glucose, sucrose, xylose, maltose, trehalose and glycerol as complex carbon sources in the presence of 0.1% yeast extract; and glucose, mannitol, galactose, sucrose, xylose, maltose, trehalose, glycerol and ethanol as a single carbon source.  Strong acidification occurs for sucrose, xylose, maltose and trehalose, whereas only slight acidification of glucose and glycerol occurs.  Sensitive to rifampicin, novobiocin and bacitracin, but resistant to kanamycin, tetracycline, streptomycin, neomycin and penicillin (50 µg per mL).  DNA G+C content is 60.0–60.5 mol% (Tm).  Main polar lipid is S-DGA-1, a sulphated glycolipid detected in all strains of the genera Haloferax and Halococcus.  The type strain, 100A6T (=JCM12892T=ACM 5227T), was isolated from stromatolites of Shark Bay, Hamelin Pool, Western Australia.  Does not utilize D-sorbitol, fumarate, lactose, mannose, raffinose, L-arginine, L-histidine, and L-lysine for growth.</description>
</treatment>
