<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halosarcina_pallida</taxon_name>
  <strain>BZ256T (=KCTC 4017T =JCM 14848T)</strain>
  <reference>Halosarcina pallida gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon from a low-salt, sulfide-rich spring IJSEM 58:856-860</reference>
  <file>Halosarcina.pallida.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are non-motile, Gram-negative cocci.  Cells form sarcina-like clusters during the exponential growth phase and occur singly or in pairs in late exponential and stationary phases.  Oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Chemo-organotrophic, growing on a wide range of substrates, including single and complex carbon sources.  Produce acid from carbohydrates.  Reduce nitrate to nitrite aerobically without the formation of gas.  Lyse in distilled water.  Cells contain phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, but phosphatidylglycerol sulfate is absent.  Two glycolipids are present that are chromatographically identical to S-DGD-1 and DGD-1. Colonies are small (0.2 mm), pink, translucent, round and convex with an entire margin.  Grows at 1.7–4.3 M NaCl, with optimal growth at 3.1 M NaCl.  Grows at 25–45 ˚C, with optimal growth at 30 ˚C.  Requires a minimum of 1 mM Mg2+ for growth.  Grows at pH values ranging from 5 to at least 8.5, with optimum growth at pH 6.5.  Does not grow anaerobically with nitrate, sulfate, elemental sulfur, thiosulfate, DMSO or trimethylamine oxide.  Does not ferment arginine.  Capable of using single carbon substrates.  Utilizes acetate, lactate, malic acid, fumaric acid, sucrose, L-glutamic acid, glucose, fructose, succinate, lactose, DL-aspartic acid, pyruvate, glycine, galactose, sorbitol, glycerol, starch, L-histidine, trehalose, DL-norleucine, D-glucuronic acid, DL-phenylalanine, aesculin and salicin, but not L-arginine, L-alanine, sodium citrate, xylose, mannitol, L-threonine, dulcitol, dextrin, L-methionine, 3,3-dimethylglutaric acid or L-tyrosine.  Produces acid when grown on sucrose, glucose, starch, fructose, lactose, galactose, sorbitol and glycerol, but not L-arginine, L-alanine, L-glutamic acid, DL-aspartic acid, glycine, acetate, lactate, malic acid, fumaric acid, citrate, succinate or pyruvate.  Able to utilize complex carbon sources such as yeast extract and Casamino acids.  Indole is produced from tryptophan.  Does not hydrolyse starch, casein, gelatin or Tween 80.  Sensitive to novobiocin, bacitracin, anisomycin, rifampacin and aphidicolin.  Resistant to erythromycin, penicillin, ampicillin, chloramphenicol, neomycin, nalidixic acid, kanamycin, gentamicin and trimethoprim.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 65.4 mol%.  The type strain, BZ256T (=KCTC 4017T =JCM 14848T), was isolated from Zodletone Spring in south-western Oklahoma, USA.</description>
</treatment>
