<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloferax_lucentensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>Aa 2.2T = JCM 9276 = NCIMB 13854 = CIP 107410 = DSM 14919 = CECT 5871 = CCM 7023</strain>
  <reference>Taxonomic characterization of Haloferax sp. (“ H. alicantei ”) strain Aa 2.2: description of Haloferax lucentensis sp. nov. Extremophiles 6:479-483</reference>
  <file>Haloferax.lucentensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are pleomorphic rods (0.6 x 2.5 µm).  Gram negative.  Motile.  Colonies are pink, circular, opaque convex with an entire margin.  Growth occurs in media containing 10–30% NaCl, with an optimum at 25% NaCl.  Grows between 10 and 45˚C (optimum at 37˚C) and pH 5–9 (optimum at 7.5).  Chemoorganotrophic.  Aerobic.  Acid is produced from arabinose, fructose, glucose, maltose, xylose and glycerol but not from galactose, lactose, sucrose or trehalose.  Oxidase and catalase positive.  Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.  Indole is produced from tryptophan.  Starch, gelatin and casein are not hydrolyzed.  H2S is produced.  Methyl red test is positive.  Voges-Proskauer negative.  Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.  The following compounds are used as sole carbon and energy sources: arabinose, cellobiose, esculin, fructose, glucose, glucosamine, rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, dulcitol, glycerol, acetate, g-aminobutyrate, butyrate, fumarate or glycerate.  The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: fucose, galactose, gluconolactone, inulin, lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, adonitol, erythritol, ethanol, mannitol, mesoinositol, propanol, sorbitol, aconitate, a-aminovalerate, caprilate, a-ketoglutarate, citrate, glutamate, malate, malonate, oxalate, propionate, saccharate or tartrate.  The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: L-alanine, L-glutamine, L-methionine, L-proline, L-serine or L-valine.  The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen and energy sources: L-arginine, L-asparagine, betaine, creatine, glycine, L-histidine, L-lysine, L-ornithine, putrescine, sarcosine or L-threonine.  The polar lipids are C20C20 derivatives of PG, PGP-Me, DGD-1 and S-DGD-1.  The G + C content of the DNA is 64.5 mol% (Tm method).  Isolated from salterns in Alicante, Spain.  Type strain is Aa 2.2T.  (= JCM 9276 = NCIMB 13854 = CIP 107410 = DSM 14919 = CECT 5871 = CCM 7023).</description>
</treatment>
