<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halopenitus_persicus</taxon_name>
  <strain>DC30T (=IBRC 10041T=KCTC 4046T)</strain>
  <reference>Halopenitus persicus gen. nov., sp. nov., an archaeon from an inland salt lake IJSEM 62:1932-1936</reference>
  <file>Halopenitus.persicus.pdf</file>
  <description>Exhibits the following properties in addition to those given in the genus description.  Cell size of 0.6–1.5 x 4.9–8.7 µm when grown in liquid MGM under optimum conditions.  Colonies are small (approximately 1.0 mm diameter).  Cells lyse in water.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite, and gas formation from nitrate are not observed.  Hydrolyses DNA, Tweens 20 and 40 but not Tweens 60 and 80, casein, gelatin or starch.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Acid is produced from D-glucose and D-maltose, but not from L-arabinose, D-fructose, sucrose, D-mannitol, D-galactose, lactose or D-ribose.  H2S is not produced from thiosulfate.  Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.  Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.  Utilizes D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, maltose, L-asparagine, L-glycine, L-proline, and L-valine as sole sources of carbon and energy, but not L-arabinose, sucrose, D-mannitol, D-ribose, L-arginine, L-methionine, L-aspartic acid, L-cysteine, L-phenylalanine or L-tyrosine.  Susceptible to the following antimicrobial compounds (µg per disc unless otherwise stated): anisomycin (35), bacitracin (10 U), nitrofurantoin (300) and novobiocin (5).  Resistant to amoxicillin (25), ampicillin (10), cephalotin (30), carbenicillin (100), cefoxitin (30), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (5), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (5), nalidixic acid (30), neomycin (30), penicillin G (10 U), polymyxin B (100 U), rifampicin (5), streptomycin (10), tetracycline (30) and tobramycin (10).  The type strain is DC30T (=IBRC 10041T=KCTC 4046T), and was isolated from Aran-Bidgol salt lake, Iran.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 66.0 mol% (HPLC).  Phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester were present but phosphatidylglycerol sulfate (PGS) was not observed.  One unidentified glycolipid and three minor phospholipids were also observed  MK-8(II-H2) was the only respiratory lipoquinone present.</description>
</treatment>
