<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halobacterium_denitrificans</taxon_name>
  <strain>S1 = ATCC 35960</strain>
  <reference>Halobacterium denitrificans sp. nov. an Extremely Halophilic Denitrifying Bacterium IJSB 36:66-70</reference>
  <file>Halobacterium.denitrificans.pdf</file>
  <description>Exponential- phase cells from liquid cultures are highly pleomorphic and disk shaped.  They are from 0.8 to 1.5 µm wide and 2.0 to 3.0 µm long.  Motility is not present.  Colonies on complex medium are 2 to 3 mm in diameter, round, convex, entire, and orange red.  Cells are gram-negative and extremely halophilic.  Cells lyse at NaCl concentrations less than 1.5 M.  Growth occurs between 1.5 M and at least 4.5 M NaCl.  Maximum growth rate between 2 and 3 M NaCl (at 37°C).  Temperature range for growth is 30 to 55˚C, with maximum growth rate at 50°C (in the presence of 3 M NaCl).  The pH range for growth is 6 to 8 (optimum, 6.7) at 37°C.  Cells are red because of the presence of a-bacterioruberin.  Polar lipids are diphytanyl-glycerol-ether derivatives.  Chemoorganotroph.  H. denitrificans is a facultative anaerobe capable of anaerobic growth only when nitrate (or nitrite) is present.  It reduces nitrate to nitrite, nitrous oxide, and dinitrogen when grown in the presence of 0.5% nitrate.  Only dinitrogen accumulates when it is grown in the presence of 0.1% nitrate.  Grows aerobically, but not anaerobically, in a mineral-salts medium containing 0.005% yeast extract, ammonium as the nitrogen source, and suitable carbon and energy sources such as D-glucose, D-galactose, D-fructose, maltose, sucrose, acetate, citrate, fumarate, glycerol, lactate, a-ketoglutarate, malate, succinate or pyruvate.  In unbuffered mineral-salts-yeast extract medium, sufficient acid is produced from utilizable carbohydrates and glycerol to change the pH from 6.7 to 4.9.  Growth.  Growth was inhibited by aphidicolin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, and novobiocin.  Oxidase and catalase positive.  Gelatin liquified, hydrogen sulfide produced from thiosulfate, and Tween 40 (palmitic acid ester) hydrolyzed.  Does not hydrolyze starch, urea, or Tween 80 (oleic acid ester).  Indole negative.  Habitat.  Solar evaporation ponds (salterns) in the San Francisco Bay area of California and probably in other salterns.  Type strain.  Strain S1 has been deposited as Halobacterium denitrificans in American Type Culture Collection, Rockville, Md. (ATCC 35960).  D-ribose, D-mannose, and lactose were not used as the sole carbon and energy source.</description>
</treatment>
