<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_chaoviator</taxon_name>
  <strain>Halo-G*T (=DSM 19316T =NCIMB 14426T =ATCC BAA-1602T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum chaoviator sp. nov., a haloarchaeon isolated from sea salt in Baja California, Mexico, Western Australia and Naxos, Greece IJSEM 59:1908-1913</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.chaoviator.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells stain Gram-negative.  Cells are pleomorphic, although most are rod-shaped.  Cells are approx.  2.0–5.0 x 0.5–0.8 µm.  Colonies are circular and red pigmented, 1.5–2 mm in diameter following incubation for 30 days at 37 ˚C.  Growth occurs at pH 7.0–8.5, 28–50 ˚C and NaCl concentrations of 2.0–5.0 M (12–30 %).  No growth at 10 ˚C.  Optimal growth occurs at pH 7.4, 37 ˚C and 4.3 M (25 %) NaCl.  Extremely halophilic; cells lyse in water.  The requirement for magnesium is variable among strains.  Chemo-organotrophic, aerobic and oxidase- and catalase-positive.  b-Galactosidase-positive; a-galactosidase activity is variable among strains.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate or L-arginine does not occur.  Tween 80, aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed.  Starch hydrolysis and nitrate reduction to nitrite are variable among strains.  Indole is not formed.  Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-galactose, lactose and maltose, but not from D-fructose or sucrose.  The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: D-galactose, D-glucose, D-fructose, maltose and lactose.  No growth occurs on sucrose, L-arginine, L-glutamic acid or DL-phenylalanine.  Polar lipids include phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglyceromethylphosphate and phosphatidylglycerolsulfate derived from C20C20 glycerol diethers and the sulfated glycolipid S-DGD.  Susceptible to bacitracin and novobiocin; not susceptible to ampicillin, anisomycin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, kanamycin, neomycin, rifampicin or tetracycline.  The DNA G+C content of the three known strains is 65.5– 66.5 mol% (Tm).  The type strain is strain Halo-G*T (=DSM 19316T =NCIMB 14426T =ATCC BAA-1602T), which was isolated from an evaporitic salt crystal from Baja California, Mexico.  Its G+C content is 65.5 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
