<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halomicrobium_katesii</taxon_name>
  <strain>Al-5T (=CECT 7257T=DSM 19301T)</strain>
  <reference>Halomicrobium katesii sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon IJSEM 58:2354-2358</reference>
  <file>Halomicrobium.katesii.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram-negative, non-motile and short-rod-shaped (1.80–2.25 x 2.25–2.80 µm).  Colonies are orange, circular with an entire margin and the surface is smooth with a diameter of 2.0 mm on medium containing 25% (w/v) NaCl after incubation for 5 days at 40 ˚C.  Growth occurs at 20–30% (3.4–5.2 M) NaCl, 35–50 ˚C and pH 6.5–10.0; optimal conditions are 37–40 ˚C, pH 7.0–7.5 and 25% (4.3 M) NaCl.  Magnesium is not required.  Reduces nitrate to nitrite and indole is not produced.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate or arginine does not occur.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Aesculin, starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are hydrolysed.  Gelatin is hydrolysed.  The following substrates are utilized for growth: D-glucose, D-fructose, D-galactose, maltose, cellobiose, starch, trehalose, adonitol, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, acetate and pyruvate.  No growth occurs on lactose, D-xylose, D-mannose, L-arabinose, raffinose, D-salicin, L-sorbose, L-rhamnose, sucrose, dulcitol, inositol, succinate, malate, gluconate, citrate, formate, oxalate, propionate, benzoate, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-aspartate, L-asparagine, L-cysteine, glycine, L-glutamate, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-lysine, L-methionine, L-ornithine, L-tryptophan, L-tyrosine or L-valine.  Acid is produced from D-fructose and D-arabinose.  Cells are resistant to penicillin G (10 U), chloramphenicol (30 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), ampicillin (10 µg), tetracycline (30 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), streptomycin (10 µg), polymyxin B (300 U), neomycin (30 µg), gentamicin (10 µg) and carbenicillin (50 µg), but susceptible to bacitracin (10 U) and novobiocin (30 µg).  The polar lipids present are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerophosphate methyl ester, sulfated diglycosyl diether and diglycosyl diether.  Phosphatidylglycerosulfate is absent.  DNA G+C content is 52.4– 52.9 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, Al-5T (=CECT 7257T=DSM 19301T), was isolated from Lake Tebenquiche in the Atacama Saltern, Chile.</description>
</treatment>
