<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloferax_sulfurifontis</taxon_name>
  <strain>M6T (=JCM 12327T=CCM 7217T= DSM 16227T=CIP 108334T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloferax sulfurifontis sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from a sulfide- and sulfur-rich spring IJSEM 54:2275-2279</reference>
  <file>Haloferax.sulfurifontis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are non-motile, extremely pleomorphic, occurring mainly as irregularly shaped cells (1.0–1.5 µm in diameter), particularly during the stationary phase, and as rods (1.5– 1.7 x 0.5–0.6 µm), especially during the exponential growth phase.  Occurs mostly as single cells, sometimes in pairs and clusters.  Gram-negative.  Colonies on agar medium with 150 g NaCl per liter are small (0.8–1.0 mm), salmon pink, transparent and elevated with undulate margin.  Halophilic.  Cells lyse immediately in distilled water, within 24 h in 10–20 g NaCl per liter and within 72 h in 30 g NaCl per liter.  Cells survive prolonged incubation in 40–50 g NaCl per liter.  Grows in a wide range of NaCl concentrations (60 g per liter to saturation).  Requires at least 1 mM Mg2+ for growth and grows best at 30 mM Mg2+ and above.  The optimum pH and temperature values for growth are pH 6.4–6.8 and 32– 37 ˚C.  The type strain, M6T, grows at 18–50 ˚C and at pH 4.5–9.0.  Cannot utilize SO42-, S2O32-, NO3-, DMSO or TMAO as electron acceptors.  Reduces elemental sulfur to sulfide under strictly anaerobic conditions.  Chemoorganotrophic.  Grows on complex media with yeast extract, Casamino acids and peptone as carbon sources.  Capable of growing in defined media.  The following substrates are utilized as carbon sources: acetate, benzoate, citrate, fumarate, L-glutamate, malate, succinate, glycerol, maltose, glucose, fructose, sucrose, arabinose, galactose and xylose.  Alanine, aspartate, arginine, glycine, lactose, mannitol, sorbitol, ribose and starch are not utilized as carbon sources.  Acid is produced in unbuffered medium from the following compounds: glycerol, xylose, maltose, sucrose, arabinose, fructose, glucose and galactose.  Acid is not produced from mannitol, arabinose, lactate or sorbitol.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Reduces thiosulfate aerobically to sulfide.  Capable of aerobic nitrate reduction.  Indole is formed from tryptophan.  Gelatin is hydrolysed, whereas starch, casein and urea are not.  Produces polyhydroxyalkanoates.  Phosphatase and b-galactosidase tests are negative.  Ornithine and lysine are not decarboxylated.  Resistant to ampicillin, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, carbenicillin, gentamicin, ceftriaxone, ciprofloxacin, doxycycline, cefaclor, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, oxytetracycline, penicillin G, rifampicin and bacitracin up to 100 µg per mL.  Sensitive to aphidicolin, anisomycin and novobiocin, and to high concentrations of bacitracin.  The major polar lipids in the membrane are the diphytanyl ether derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, the methyl ester of phosphatidylglycerophosphate, and S-DGD-1 as the main glycolipid.  Phosphatidylglycerosulfate is absent.  The type strain is M6T (=JCM 12327T=CCM 7217T= DSM 16227T=CIP 108334T).  The DNA G+C content of M6T is 60.5 mol%.  Isolated from the Zodletone spring in south-western Oklahoma, USA.</description>
</treatment>
