<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_orientale</taxon_name>
  <strain>EJ-52T (=CECT 7145T=JCM 13889T= CGMCC 1.6295T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum orientale sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from Lake Ejinor, Inner Mongolia, China IJSEM 56:2559-2563</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.orientale.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are pleomorphic, 1.5–2 x 1–2 µm in size and motile.  Colonies are small, entire, smooth and red-pigmented.  Growth occurs in the presence of 2.5–5.0 M NaCl, with optimum growth occurring at 3.4 M NaCl.  MgCl2 is not required.  Growth occurs between 25 and 50 ˚C (optimum, 35–45 ˚C) and at pH 6.0–10.0 (optimum, pH 8.0).  Chemoorganotrophic.  Oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  Tween 80 and urea are hydrolysed, whereas starch, casein and gelatin are not.  H2S is not produced.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  The Voges–Proskauer test is negative.  Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate or arginine does not occur.  Acid is not produced from lactose, glycerol, D-glucose, sucrose, D-fructose, D-arabinose, maltose, D-xylose, D-galactose, D-trehalose and D-mannose.  Growth occurs on glycerol, D-fructose, maltose, D-glucose, starch, L-glutamate and fumarate as single carbon and energy sources.  The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, lactose, D-arabinose, D-raffinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, succinate, propionate, malate and acetate.  The following compounds are used as sole carbon, nitrogen or energy sources: L-asparagine, glycine, L-lysine, L-serine and L-threonine.  Susceptible to novobiocin, bacitracin, gentamicin, ampicillin, neomycin, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, nalidixic acid and streptomycin; resistant to penicillin G and rifampicin.  The polar lipids are C20C20 derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester and a sulfated mannosylglucosylglycerol diether.  The DNA G+C content is 64.2 mol% (Tm method).  The type strain, EJ-52T (=CECT 7145T=JCM 13889T= CGMCC 1.6295T), was isolated from Lake Ejinor, a saline lake in Inner Mongolia, China.</description>
</treatment>
