<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloferax_alexandrinus</taxon_name>
  <strain>TMT (=JCM 10717T=IFO 16590T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloferax alexandrinus sp. nov., an extremely halophilic canthaxanthin-producing archaeon from a solar saltern in Alexandria (Egypt) IJSEM 52:729-738</reference>
  <file>Haloferax.alexandrinus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells stain Gram-negative, and are chemo-organotrophic, strictly aerobic, non-motile and pleomorphic (1.1-1.5 x 1.6-2.0 µm; rod-shaped cells 1.1-1.5 x 3.5-4 µm).  Cells occur mostly singly and exhibit a range of morphological types, including triangular forms, square forms, irregular cocci and rod-shaped cells.  Gas vacuoles are not formed.  Colonies on standard agar growth medium are 0.5-1 mm in diameter, circular, convex, entire, translucent, smooth and red.  Incapable of anaerobic growth with nitrate, DMSO or l-arginine.  Extremely halophilic, growth occurring at NaCl concentrations between 100 g per liter and saturation.  Optimum growth occurs at 250 g NaCl per liter with a high requirement of MgSO4 (40 g per liter).  Tolerates the elevated concentrations of MgSO4 up to 409 g per liter.  Cells lyse in water.  The temperature range is 20-55 °C in the presence of 250 g NaCl per liter.  The pH range is 5.5-7.5, the optimum being pH 7.2 (at 37 °C).  Cells grow aerobically in a chemically defined medium containing ammonium chloride and a single carbon source such as glucose, glycerol or succinate.  Acidification of the unbuffered medium occurs when growth occurs in the presence of sugars or glycerol.  Reduction of nitrate occurs under aerobic conditions.  Aerobic reduction of nitrate and nitrite without gas production was detected.  Tween 80 and gelatin are hydrolysed, and sulfide is produced from thiosulfate.  Does not hydrolyse urea, starch or casein.  Catalase and oxidase tests are positive.  Arginine dihydroxylase and urease tests are negative.  Tests for b-galactosidase and phosphatase are positive.  Lysine decarboxylase and ornithine ornithine decarboxylase tests are negative.  The strain can utilize various complex carbon and nitrogen sources such as amino acids and yeast extract.  The strain is unable to utilize peptone, casein or starch.  The major isoprenoid neutral lipids are the carotenoids (bacterioruberins, b-carotene and 3-hydroxy echinenone), including a large amount of canthaxanthin [700 µg per g dry cells].  Acid hydrolysis of whole cells releases a single diether component identical to 2,3-di-O-phytanyl- sn-glycerol.  The major polar lipids are the diether analogues of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerolphosphate- methyl ester, a diglycosyl glycerol diether and sulfate diglycosyl diether.  The G+C content of the DNA is 59.5 mol%.  The type strain is TMT (=JCM 10717T=IFO 16590T).  Sensitive to novobiocin and bacitracin.  Resistant to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, neomycin, josamycin, rifampicin and tetracycline.</description>
</treatment>
