<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halosarcina_limi</taxon_name>
  <strain>RO1-6T (=CGMCC 1.8711T =JCM 16054T)</strain>
  <reference>Halosarcina limi sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon from a marine solar saltern, and emended description of the genus Halosarcina IJSEM 60:2462-2466</reference>
  <file>Halosarcina.limi.pdf</file>
  <description>Displays the following properties in addition to those given in the emended genus description.  Cells are motile and pleomorphic (rods and deformed cocci) when grown in CM2 liquid medium.  Colonies on agar plates containing 3.9 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemoorganotrophic.  Growth occurs at 20–50 ˚C (optimum 37 ˚C), in 2.1–5.1 M NaCl (optimum 3.9 M NaCl), in 0.05–0.70 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.30 M MgCl2) and at pH 6.5–8.0 (optimum pH 7.0).  Minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis in distilled water is 12% (w/v).  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed and nitrite is reduced.  H2S is produced from sodium thiosulfate.  Negative for indole formation.  Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, casein and gelatin are not hydrolysed; starch is hydrolysed weakly.  Able to grow in defined and complex media.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources for growth: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, sucrose, lactose, starch, glycerol, acetate, pyruvate, DL-lactate, L-alanine and L-glutamate.  D-Fructose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, succinate, L-malate, fumarate, citrate, glycine, L-arginine, L-aspartate, L-lysine and L-ornithine are not utilized as carbon sources.  Acid is produced during growth on carbohydrates.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): rifampicin (5), novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU), anisomycin (20) and aphidicolin (20).  Resistant to the following antibiotics: erythromycin (15), neomycin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (10), penicillin G (10 IU), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The major polar lipids are PG, PGP-Me and two major glycolipids that are chromatographically identical to S-DGD-1 and S2-DGD.  The type strain is RO1-6T (=CGMCC 1.8711T =JCM 16054T), isolated from Rudong solar saltern, Jiangsu Province, China.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.2 mol% (as determined by HPLC).</description>
</treatment>
