<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halobellus_clavatus</taxon_name>
  <strain>TNN18T (=CGMCC 1.10118T =JCM 16424T)</strain>
  <reference>Halobellus clavatus gen. nov., sp. nov. and Halorientalis regularis gen. nov., sp. nov., two new members of the family Halobacteriaceae IJSEM 61:2682-2689</reference>
  <file>Halobellus.clavatus.Halorientalis.regularis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile, rod-shaped, ~0.5–1.0 x 1–6 µm under optimal growth conditions and Gram-reaction-negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 2.6 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at 20–50 ˚C (optimum 37 ˚C), in 10–30% (w/v) NaCl (optimum 15%), with 0–1.0 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.05 M MgCl2) and at pH 5.5–9.0 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5).  Cells lyse in distilled water; minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis is 10% (w/v).  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed in the type strain.  Hydrogen sulfide is not produced from sodium thiosulfate.  Indole formation is negative.  Does not hydrolyse starch, gelatin, Tween 80 or casein.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon, nitrogen or energy sources: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, glycerol, pyruvate, DL-lactate, succinate, L-malate and fumarate.  No growth occurs on D-fructose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, starch, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, acetate, citrate, glycine, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate, L-lysine or L-ornithine.  Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, maltose, sucrose and lactose.  Sensitive to the following antimicrobial compounds (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU), anisomycin (20), aphidicolin (20) and rifampicin (5); resistant to erythromycin (15), penicillin G (10 IU), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), neomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The major polar lipids are PG, PGP-Me, PGS, and one major GL, which is chromatographically identical to S-DGD-1.  Minor amounts of other lipids (GL0, GL2, GL3 and GL4) are also detectable.  The DNA G+C content is 61.5–62.4 mol%.  The type strain, TNN18T (=CGMCC 1.10118T =JCM 16424T), was isolated from the Tainan marine solar saltern near Lianyungang city, Jiangsu province, China.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.5 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
