<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_aquaticum</taxon_name>
  <strain>EN-2T (=CECT 7174T =CGMCC 1.6377T =JCM 14031T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum aquaticum sp. nov., an archaeon isolated from hypersaline lakes IJSEM 61:1144-1148</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.aquaticum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are rods (1.0–1.2 x 2.0–6.0 µm).  Non-motile.  Colonies are circular, entire, smooth, red and 0.5–1.5 mm in diameter on MH agar after 7 days at 37 ˚C.  Growth occurs with 2.5–5.0 M NaCl (optimum 3.4 M NaCl).  MgCl2 is not required.  Strict aerobe.  Growth occurs at 25–50 ˚C (optimum 35–40 ˚C) and pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum pH 7.5).  Chemo-organotrophic.  Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.  Nitrate and nitrite are reduced.  Tween 80, urea and aesculin are hydrolysed, but casein, DNA, starch and gelatin are not.  H2S is not produced.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.  Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate or arginine does not occur.  Acid is not produced from lactose, glycerol, D-glucose, D-fructose, D-arabinose, maltose, D-xylose, D-galactose, trehalose or D-mannose.  Growth occurs with glycerol, D-mannitol, D-fructose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, trehalose, D-glucose, D-arabinose, starch, L-glutamate and fumarate as single carbon and energy sources, but not with D-sorbitol, mannose, raffinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, succinate, propionate, malate or acetate.  Growth occurs with glycine as a sole carbon, nitrogen and energy source, but not with L-asparagine, L-lysine, L-serine or L-threonine.  Susceptible to (µg per disc unless otherwise stated) novobiocin (30), bacitracin (10 U), erythromycin (15) and streptomycin (10) and resistant to rifampicin (5), ampicillin (10), neomycin (30), chloramphenicol (30) and nalidixic acid (30).  The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, sulfated diglycosyl diethers and several unidentified glycolipids.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.1 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, EN-2T (=CECT 7174T =CGMCC 1.6377T =JCM 14031T), was isolated from a saline lake, Lake Erliannor, in Inner Mongolia, China.  Strain SH-4, from a similar source, is a second strain of the species.</description>
</treatment>
