<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halosimplex_carlsbadense</taxon_name>
  <strain>2–9-1 (ATCC BAA 75; JCM 11222)</strain>
  <reference>Halosimplex carlsbadense gen. nov., sp. nov., a unique halophilic archaeon, with three 16S rRNA genes, that grows only in defined medium with glycerol and acetate or pyruvate</reference>
  <file>Halosimplex.carlsbadense.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram-negative, primarily rod shaped cells, some pleomorphic forms can be found.  Colonies are pink to red, small, circular, opaque, smooth, shiny and raised, with entire margins.  Colonies become wrinkled with age.  Aerobic, oxygen is used as the final electron acceptor.  Cannot use nitrate, nitrite, or any other alternate electron acceptors.  Growth occurs only between pH 7.0 and 8.0, temperature 22–50˚C.  Optimal growth occurs between 37 and 40˚C.  Extremely fastidious.  Grows only on pyruvate, pyruvate plus glycerol, or glycerol plus acetate as carbon sources in defined medium.  Pyruvate plus acetate will not support growth.  Unable to grow on any other organic compounds tested, including amino acids, methanol, formaldehyde, vitamins, nucleotides, fatty acids, proteins, or Krebs cycle intermediates.  Complex nutrients such as yeast extract, casamino acids, starch, or casein do not stimulate growth and may be inhibitory.  Unable to ferment arginine or to grow autotrophically in the light.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Phosphatidyl glycerol and methylated phosphatidyl glycerol are produced.  Possesses a total of four sulfated glycolipids.  Two of the glycolipids have been identified as STeGD and S2-DGD.  The other two lipids are unidentified.  Guanine plus cytosine content 64.4 mol% by HPLC.  Possesses three divergent 16S rRNA genes.  Requires at least 0.5% (w/v) Mg2+, which can be supplied as either MgSO4 or MgCl2.  Optimum growth occurs in the presence of 1–2% (w/v) magnesium.  Sensitive to bacitracin (10 µg), sulfasoxazole (300 µg), novobiocin (30 µg), rifampin (5 µg), and monensin (100 µg per mL).  Resistant to chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamycin, penicillin G, tetracycline, vancomycin, clindamycin, kanamycin, anisomycin, aphidocolin, neomycin, and valinomycin.  The type strain is 2–9-1 (ATCC BAA 75; JCM 11222).  Genes A and B are related to each other at 97.7% similarity.</description>
</treatment>
