<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halolamina_pelagica</taxon_name>
  <strain>TBN21T (=CGMCC 1.10329T =JCM 16809T)</strain>
  <reference>Halolamina pelagica gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Halobacteriaceae IJSEM 61:1317-1621</reference>
  <file>Halolamina.pelagica.pdf</file>
  <description>Displays the following properties in addition to those described for the genus.  Colonies on agar plates containing 3.4–3.9 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemoorganotrophic.  Growth occurs at 25–50 ˚C (optimum 37 ˚C), 1.4–5.1 M NaCl (optimum 3.4–3.9 M), 0–0.7 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.01–0.05 M) and pH 5.5–9.5 (optimum pH 7.0–7.5).  Minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis is 8% (w/v).  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed in some strains.  H2S is not produced from sodium thiosulfate.  Indole formation is negative.  Hydrolyses starch weakly but does not hydrolyse gelatin, casein or Tween 80.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources for growth: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, starch, acetate, pyruvate and DL-lactate.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon, nitrogen or energy sources for growth: L-alanine, L-arginine, L-glutamate and L-ornithine.  No growth occurs on D-fructose, L-sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, glycerol, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, succinate, L-malate, fumarate, citrate, glycine, L-aspartate or L-lysine.  Acid is produced from D-glucose, D-mannose and D-galactose.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless indicated): novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU), anisomycin (20), aphidicolin (20) and rifampicin (5).  Resistant to erythromycin (15), penicillin G (10 IU), ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), neomycin (30), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 64.8 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, TBN21T (=CGMCC 1.10329T =JCM 16809T), were isolated from Taibei marine solar saltern near Lianyungang city, Jiangsu province, China.  The polar lipids were phosphatidic acid, phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, phosphatidylglycerol sulfate and eight glycolipids; three of these glycolipids (GL3, GL4 and GL5) were chromatographically identical to S-DGD-1 (sulfated mannosyl glucosyl diether 1), TGD-1 (galactosyl mannosyl glucosyl diether 1) and DGD-1 (mannosyl glucosyl diether 1), respectively.</description>
</treatment>
