<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_kocurii</taxon_name>
  <strain>BG-1T (=CECT 7322T =CGMCC 1.7018T =JCM 14978T)</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum kocurii sp. nov., an archaeon isolated from a saline lake IJSEM 58:2031-2035</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.kocurii.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are non-motile, rod-shaped (2–5 x 0.9–1.1 µm) and Gram-negative.  Colonies are circular, smooth, entire, opaque, red-pigmented and 0.5–1.5 mm in diameter after 5 days at 37 ˚C on plates containing 20% (w/v) total salts.  Cells are extremely halophilic and lyse in water.  At least 2.5 M NaCl is required for growth, the optimum concentration being 3.4 M NaCl.  MgCl2 is not required for growth.  The pH and temperature ranges for growth are pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.5) and 25–55 ˚C (optimum, 37 ˚C).  Chemo-organotrophic, aerobic and oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons’ citrate tests produce negative results.  Acid is not produced from lactose, glycerol, D-glucose, sucrose, D-fructose, D-arabinose, maltose, D-galactose, trehalose or D-mannose.  Does not grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate or L-arginine.  Starch, gelatin, DNA, aesculin and casein are not hydrolysed.  Urea is hydrolysed.  Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite; gas is not produced from nitrite.  Utilizes D-xylose.  No growth is observed on D-glucose, D-fructose, glycerol, maltose, trehalose, starch, propionate, fumarate, acetate, L-lysine, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, lactose, D-arabinose, D-galactose, D-mannose, raffinose, D-ribose, malate, succinate, glutamate, isoleucine, L-serine or glycine.  Sensitive to bacitracin, novobiocin and rifampicin.  Resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, penicillin G, streptomycin and tetracycline.  The polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester and the glycolipid mannosyl-2-sulfate-(1-4)- glycosyl-archaeol.  The DNA G+C content is 69.4 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, BG-1T (=CECT 7322T =CGMCC 1.7018T =JCM 14978T), was isolated from saline Lake Bagaejinnor in Inner Mongolia, China.</description>
</treatment>
