<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halogeometricum_borinquense</taxon_name>
  <strain>ATCC 700274T</strain>
  <reference>Halogeometricum borinquense gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel halophilic archaeon from Puerto Rico IJSB 48:1305-1312</reference>
  <file>Halogeometricum.borinquense.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are extremely pleomorphic (rods are 1-3 x 1-2 µm), showing different shapes (short and long rods, squares, triangles and ovals).  Motile by peritrichous flagella.  Gas vesicles are present creating a milky appearance.  The colonies are pink, small (0.5-1 mm) and very mucoid.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Anaerobic growth occurs with nitrate.  Arginine not fermented.  Requires at least 8 % (w/v) NaCl for growth.  The optimal NaCl concentration range is 20-25% (w/v) at 40 ˚C; the optimal Mg2+ concentration range is 40-80 mM.  The optimal temperature is 40 ˚C (in medium containing 20-25 % (w/v) NaCl and 40-80 mM Mg2+).  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite with the production of gas.  Indole is produced from tryptophan.  Gelatin is strongly hydrolysed.  Starch is not hydrolysed.  Resistant to penicillin, kanamycin, ampicillin, vancomycin, tetracycline, erythromycin and chloramphenicol.  Susceptible to novobiocin, bacitracin and sulfamethazone plus trimethoprim.  Glucose, mannose, fructose, xylose, maltose, trehalose, cellobiose, raffinose and glycerol are used as carbon sources.  Acid is produced from fructose, arabinose, ribose, xylose, lactose and sucrose.  Isolated from the solar salterns of Cabo Rojo, Puerto Rico.  The G+C content of the type strain is 59-1 mol % (as determined by HPLC).  The type strain is ATCC 700274T.  Nitrite was produced from nitrate with gas production.  Contains glycerol diether moieties.  Contains the glycerol diether analogues of phosphatidylglycerol (PG), phosphatidylglycerophosphate (PGP) and a single glycolipid.  This glycolipid runs somewhat faster on the TLC plate than TGD-2, the glycolipid marker of Haloarcula.  Phosphatidylglycerosulfate (PGS) was not detected.</description>
</treatment>
