<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halovenus_aranensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>EB27T (=IBRC-M 10015T=CGMCC 1.11001T)</strain>
  <reference>Halovenus aranensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon from Aran-Bidgol salt lake IJSEM 62:1331-1336</reference>
  <file>Halovenus.aranensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Has the following properties in addition to those given for the genus.  Cells are 0.6–1.3 x 4.9–10.7 µm when grown in MGM liquid medium at optimum conditions.  Colonies are small (about 1.0 mm in diameter), shiny and intensely red pigmented.  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 2.5– 5.0 M (optimum 4.0 M), at Mg2+ concentrations of 0.2– 1.0 M (optimum 0.5 M), at pH 6.0–8.0 (optimum pH 7.5) and at 25–50 ˚C (optimum 40 ˚C).  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite and gas formation from nitrate are not observed.  Does not hydrolyse Tweens 20, 40, 60 or 80, casein, gelatin or starch.  Utilizes D-glucose and D-galactose as carbon sources for growth but not lactose, L-glycine, L-proline or L-cysteine.  Produces acid from D-glucose, but not from D-galactose, sucrose, D-fructose, D-xylose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, trehalose, D-arabinose or lactose.  Indole is not produced.  H2S is not produced from thiosulfate.  Sensitive to (µg per disc unless otherwise noted) bacitracin (10 U), nitrofurantoin (300), novobiocin (30), polymixin B (100 U), rifampicin (5), streptomycin (10) and anisomycin (30), but resistant to amikacin (30), amoxicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), gentamicin (30), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), tobramycin (10), nalidixic acid (30), cephalothin (30), penicillin G (10 U), ampicillin (10) and neomycin (10).  The type strain, EB27T (=IBRC-M 10015T=CGMCC 1.11001T), was isolated from Aran-Bidgol salt lake, Iran.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.0 mol% (as determined by HPLC).  Contained phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester and two minor phospholipids.  Did not contain any glycolipid derivatives.  MK-8(II-H2) was the only respiratory lipoquinone present.</description>
</treatment>
