<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_alkaliphilum</taxon_name>
  <strain>DZ-1T = AS 1.3528T = JCM 12358T</strain>
  <reference>Halorubrum alkaliphilum sp. nov., a novel haloalkaliphile isolated from a soda lake in Xinjiang, China IJSEM 55:149-152</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.alkaliphilum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are short rods (0.8–1.0 x 1.8–2.0 µm) and Gram-negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 20% (w/v) total salts are red, elevated and round.  Growth is chemoorganotrophic, aerobic and occurs at concentrations of 1.8–5.2 M NaCl, at pH 8.0–10.5 and at 20–44 ˚C.  Optimal NaCl concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 3.9–4.3 M, pH 9.0–10.0 and 38˚C, respectively.  Magnesium is not required for growth.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate, arginine or DMSO does not occur.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is observed and H2S is produced from cystein.  Indole formation is positive.  Tween 80, casein and starch are not hydrolysed.  Gelatinase negative.  Amino acids are required for growth.  Fructose, glucose, mannose and maltose are utilized with the production of acids.  Glycerol is utilized without acid production.  No growth or acid production is observed on sucrose, lactose, raffinose, rhamnose, galactose, D-ribose, mannitol or sorbitol.  Lactate and glutamic acid are utilized.  Resistant to penicillin G, rifampicin, chloramphenicol, neomycin and bacitracin.  Cells contain C20C20 and C20C25 derivatives of phosphatidyl glycerol and phosphatidyl glycerol phosphate methyl ester, but lack phosphatidyl glycerol sulfate and sulfated glycolipid.  The DNA G+C content is 62.1 mol% (Tm).  Isolated from a soda lake in Xinjiang, China.  The type strain is DZ-1T and has been deposited in the China General Microbiological Culture Collection Center (CGMCC) as AS 1.3528T and in the Japanese Collection of Microorganisms as JCM 12358T.  Gas vacuoles absent.</description>
</treatment>
