<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halobacterium_NRC-1</taxon_name>
  <strain>NRC-1 = DSM 670</strain>
  <reference>Bergey’s Manual</reference>
  <file>Rod-shaped.  0.5-1.0 x 1.0-6.0 µm or more in length.  Displaying a multitude of pleomorphic forms, especially in deficient media or at elevated temperatures.  Some strains contain gas vacuoles.  Motile by tufts of polar flagella.  Generally aerobic, but may grow anaerobically in the presence of dimethylsulfoxide, trimethylamine N-oxide, or fumarate.  Grows fermentatively in the presence of arginine.  Fastest growth occurs at 3.5-4.5 M NaCl; good growth occurs in saturated NaCl (~5.2 M); no growth occurs below 3 M NaCl.  Temperature range for growth: 20-55˚C, optimum 50˚C.  Mg2+ requirements 0.05-0.1 M.  pH range 5.5-8.0.  Chemoorganotrophic.  Amino acids are required for growth.  Carbohydrates are not utilized, but stimulation of growth is observed in the presence of glycerol.  Starch is not hydrolyzed.  Indole positive.  Gelatin is hydrolyzed. Urease negative.  Arginine dehyrolase present.  Commonly found in neutral salt lakes, marine salterns, and proteinaceous products heavily salted with crude solar salt.  Also found in ancient evaporite deposits.  The mol% G+C of the DNA is 66-70.9% and 57-60% (Bd) (minor component).  Oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Has gas vacuoles. Characteristic sulfated triglycosyl and tetraglycosyl diethers present.  Polar lipids based on 2,3-di-O-phytanyl-sn-glycerol (C20C20) ethers.  All strains have C20C20 forms of PG 9phosphatidyl glycerol), PGP-Me (phosphatidyl glycerol phosphate methyl ester), PGS (phsophatidyl glyercol sulfate), TGD-1 (galactosyl mannosyl glucosyl diether), S-TGD-1 (sulfated triglycosyl diether), and S-TeGD (sulfated tetraglycosyl diether).  Resistant to penicillin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin, erythromycin, and tetracycline.  Sensitive to anisomycin, aphidicolin, bacitracin, novobiocin, and vibriostat reagent (0/129).</file>
</treatment>
