<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halopiger_aswanensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>56T (=DSM 13151T=JCM 11628T)</strain>
  <reference>Halopiger aswanensis sp. nov., a polymer producing and extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from hypersaline soil IJSEM 60:633-637</reference>
  <file>Halopiger.aswanensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile, Gram-negative, pleomorphic rods (short and long) measuring 1.25–6.50 x 0.6–0.9 µm and 0.9–3.75 x 0.6–0.9 µm from liquid and solid cultivation media under optimum conditions, respectively.  Colonies may be pink-pigmented and small.  Cells require at least 1.7 M (10% w/v) NaCl for growth.  Optimum growth occurs at 3.8–4.3 M (22.5–25 %) NaCl with an optimum pH of 7.5 and an optimum temperature of 40 ˚C.  Cells are able to grow over a pH range of 6–9.2.  The maximum temperature for growth is 55 ˚C.  Oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Cells lyse in distilled water.  Strictly aerobic.  Anaerobic growth does not occur even in the presence of KNO3 or arginine.  Mg2+ is not required for growth.  Indole was produced from tryptone, sulfide was produced from cysteine, and starch, Tween 20, Tween 40 and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.  Casein, gelatin or lipids from egg yolk are not hydrolysed.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  Acid is produced from xylose, arabinose, glucose, fructose, sucrose, maltose and starch, but not from lactose.  Susceptible to fusidic acid, bacitracin, nitrofurantoin, novobiocin, anisomycin, trimethoprim and rifampicin.  Resistant to nystatin, tetracycline, nalidixic acid, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin and penicillin.  Proteose peptone, tryptone, Casamino acids and non-nitrogenous compounds such as some carbohydrates and acetate, gluconate and pyruvate can be used as the carbon and energy source.  Menaquinones are the only respiratory lipoquinones present and comprise MK-8 (67.5%) and MK-8(VIII-H2) (32.5 %).  Polar lipid analysis shows the presence of the bis-sulfated glycolipid S2-DGD-1 as the sole glycolipid and the glycerol diether analogue of phosphatidylglycerosulfate is absent.  Growth occurs with starch or other compounds as the sole carbon and energy source in the presence of NH4Cl as the sole nitrogen source.  The type strain, strain 56T (=DSM 13151T=JCM 11628T), was isolated from the surface of hypersaline salt soils close to Aswan, Egypt.  The DNA G+C content of type strain is 67.1 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
