<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloferax_mucosum</taxon_name>
  <strain>PA12T (=JCM 14792T=ATCC BAA- 1512T=UNSW 104200T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloferax elongans sp. nov. and Haloferax mucosum sp. nov., isolated from microbial mats from Hamelin Pool, Shark Bay, Australia IJSEM 58:798-802</reference>
  <file>Haloferax.elongans.mucosum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are pleomorphic and non-motile.  Gram-negative.  Colonies on complex agar medium are 3–5 mm in diameter, pink–red, entire, opaque, mucoid and domed.  Growth occurs in 1.7–5.1 M NaCl, with optimum growth at 2.6–3.4 M.  Growth occurs in media containing at least 0.2 M Mg2+ or more.  Greater than 0.04 M Mg2+ is required for maintenance of native cell morphology and cell lysis occurs in NaCl solutions of 0.85 M or less.  Grows at pH 6.0–10.0 and 23–55 ˚C, with optimum growth at pH 7.4 and 42–53 ˚C.  The generation time at 48 ˚C is 57±3 min.  Chemo-organotrophic.  Aerobic.  Oxidase-negative and catalase-positive.  Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.  Does not produce gas from nitrate.  Indole is produced from tryptophan.  H2S is not produced from thiosulfate.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate, DMSO or arginine does not occur.  Gelatin and casein are hydrolysed, but starch and Tween 80 are not.  The following substrates are used as carbon sources: glucose, glycerol, maltose, sucrose and trehalose.  Acid is produced from glucose, glycerol, maltose, sucrose and trehalose.  The following substrates are not used as carbon sources: ethanol, fumarate, galactose, glycine, lactose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, xylose, L-arginine, L-histidine, L-lysine, L-ornithine and D-sorbitol.  Sensitive to novobiocin (50 µg per mL).  Resistant to ampicillin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, cycloheximide, erythromycin, gentamicin, neomycin, penicillin, streptomycin and tetracycline (all at 50 µg per mL), ciprofloxacin (2.5 µg per disk), norfloxacin (10 µg per disk) and rifampicin (1 µg per disk).  Lipids S-DGA-1, DGA-1, PGP-Me and PG are present, but PGS is not present.  The type strain is PA12T (=JCM 14792T=ATCC BAA- 1512T=UNSW 104200T), isolated from a pustular mat, Hamelin Pool, Shark Bay, Western Australia.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 60.8 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
