<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloterrigena_salina</taxon_name>
  <strain>XH-65T (=CGMCC 1.6203T =JCM 13891T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloterrigena salina sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from a salt lake IJSEM 58:2880-2884</reference>
  <file>Haloterrigena.salina.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are non-motile and coccoid, occurring in pairs or irregular clusters, 1.2–1.6 µm in diameter, and Gram-negative.  Colonies are circular, smooth, entire, opaque and light-red pigmented, 0.2 mm in diameter after 7 days at 37 ˚C on plates containing 20% (w/v) total salts.  Extremely halophilic.  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 2.5–5.0 M, at pH 6.0–9.0 and at 25–50 ˚C.  The optimal NaCl concentration, pH and temperature for growth are 3.4 M, pH 7.0–8.0 and 37 ˚C.  MgCl2 is not required for growth.  Chemo-organotrophic, aerobic and oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons’ citrate tests are negative.  Acid is not produced from lactose, glycerol, D-glucose, sucrose, D-fructose, D-arabinose, maltose, D-galactose, trehalose or D-mannose.  Does not grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate or L-arginine.  Aesculin is hydrolysed.  Starch, gelatin, DNA, urea and casein are not hydrolysed.  Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite; gas is not produced from nitrite.  The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: D-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, starch, D-xylose, aspartic acid, acetate, glutamate and threonine.  No growth is observed on D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, trehalose, raffinose, succinate or malate.  Resistant to ampicillin (10 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), neomycin (10 µg), penicillin G (10 U), streptomycin (10 µg) and tetracycline (30 µg).  Major polar lipids are C20C20 and C20C25 derivatives of PG, PGP-Me and S2-DGD.  The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 67.0 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, strain XH-65T (=CGMCC 1.6203T =JCM 13891T), was isolated from the saline Lake Xilinhot in Inner Mongolia, PR China.</description>
</treatment>
