<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halopelagius_inordinatus</taxon_name>
  <strain>RO5-2T (=CGMCC 1.7739T =JCM 15773T)</strain>
  <reference>Halopelagius inordinatus gen. nov., sp. nov., a new member of the family Halobacteriaceae isolated from a marine solar saltern IJSEM 60:2089-2093</reference>
  <file>Halopelagius.inordinatus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile, pleomorphic when grown in NOM-1 liquid medium and stain Gram-negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 3.9 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at 20– 50 ˚C (optimum 37 ˚C), at 2.6–4.8 M NaCl (optimum 3.4– 3.9 M NaCl), at 0.03–0.7 M MgCl2 (optimum 0.5 M MgCl2) and at pH 5.5–8.0 (optimum pH 6.5–7.0).  Cells lyse in distilled water and the minimal NaCl concentration to prevent cell lysis is 12% (w/v).  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine and DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is not observed.  Nitrite is reduced.  H2S is produced from Na2S2O3.  Positive for indole formation.  Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are not hydrolysed.  Negative for caseinase, amylase and gelatinase.  The following substrates are utilized as single carbon and energy sources for growth: D-glucose, D-mannose, D-galactose, D-fructose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, glycerol, D-sorbitol, acetate, pyruvate, DL-lactate, succinate, L-malate, fumarate, L-alanine, L-glutamate and L-ornithine.  L-Sorbose, D-ribose, D-xylose, starch, D-mannitol, citrate, glycine, L-arginine, L-aspartate and L-lysine are not utilized as carbon sources.  Sensitive to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): rifampicin (5), novobiocin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU per disc), anisomycin (20) and aphidicolin (20).  Resistant to the following antibiotics: erythromycin (15), neomycin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (10), penicillin G (10 IU per disc), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10) and nalidixic acid (30).  The major polar lipids are PG, PGP-Me, S-DGD-1 and DGD-1.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 61.0% (as determined by HPLC).  The type strain is RO5-2T (=CGMCC 1.7739T =JCM 15773T), and was isolated from the Rudong solar saltern in Jiangsu province, China.</description>
</treatment>
