<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halobacterium_piscisalsi</taxon_name>
  <strain>HPC1-2T (=BCC 24372T=JCM 14661T=PCU 302T),</strain>
  <reference>Halobacterium piscisalsi sp. nov., from fermented fish (pla-ra) in Thailand IJSEM 58:2136-2140</reference>
  <file>Halobacterium.piscisalsi.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are rod-shaped (0.5–1.0 x 1.0–2.0 µm) and motile by means of peritrichous flagella.  Cells stain Gram-negative and are chemo-organotrophic.  Colonies on plates of halophilic agar medium are red, smooth, circular and elevated.  Requires at least 2.6 M NaCl for growth; optimal growth occurs at 3.4–4.3 M NaCl.  Cell lysis occurs upon hypotonic treatment with less than 1.7 M NaCl.  Growth occurs at 0–1 M MgCl2, optimally at around 0.5–0.6 M MgCl2.  The temperature and pH ranges for growth are 20– 60 ˚C (optimum at 37–40 ˚C) and 5.0–8.0 (optimum at pH 7.0–7.5).  Grows anaerobically in the presence of nitrate, L-arginine and DMSO.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced.  Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer reaction and indole production are also negative.  Casein, gelatin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but starch is not.  The following substrates are utilized for growth: lactose, melezitose, glycerol and citrate.  Acid is produced from glycerol.  Does not utilize L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, myo-inositol, inulin, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, D-ribose, salicin, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, D-xylose, acetate, L-glycine, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-aspartate, L-glutamate or L-lysine.  Produces alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, but not leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, a-galactosidase, b-galactosidase, b-glucuronidase, a-glucosidase, b-glucosidase, N-acetyl- b-glucosaminidase, a-mannosidase, a-fucosidase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease or DNase.  Sensitive to bacitracin (10 U), neomycin (30 µg) and novobiocin (5 µg), but not to ampicillin (10 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), kanamycin (30 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), rifampicin (30 µg), streptomycin (10 µg) or tetracycline (30 µg).  The major polar lipids are C20C20 derivatives of PG, PGP-Me, PGS, TGD, STGD and S-TeGD.  The predominant menaquinone is MK- 8.  The G+C content of the DNA is 65.5 mol%.  The type strain, HPC1-2T (=BCC 24372T=JCM 14661T=PCU 302T), was isolated from pla-ra (salt fermented fish product) in Thailand.</description>
</treatment>
