<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halococcus_thailandensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>HDB5-2T (=BCC 20213T =JCM 13552T =PCU 278T)</strain>
  <reference>Halococcus thailandensis sp. nov., from fish sauce in Thailand IJSEM 57:2199-2203</reference>
  <file>Halococcus.thailandensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, strictly aerobic cocci, 0.8–1.2 µm in diameter, occurring singly, in pairs, tetrads or sarcina packets.  Colonies are small, red-pigmented and circular with entire margins (1–2 mm in diameter after 1 week of incubation at 37 ˚C) when grown on complex medium of neutral pH.  No lysis in distilled water.  Grows aerobically but not anaerobically even in the presence of nitrate or arginine.  Grows between 15 and 45 ˚C (optimally at 37 ˚C) and between pH 6 and 10 (optimally at pH 6–8).  Extremely halophilic; requires at least 15% (w/v) NaCl for growth and grows optimally at 20–30% (w/v) NaCl.  Does not require MgCl2 for growth.  Catalase-, oxidase- and urease-positive.  Nitrate is reduced but gas is not formed.  Does not hydrolyse arginine, casein, gelatin, Tween 80 or starch.  Produces acids from L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-glucose, lactose, D-mannitol, melibiose, sucrose and trehalose.  Utilizes L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-xylose and glutamic acid, but not D-galactose or serine as the sole energy source.  The type strain is susceptible to bacitracin, novobiocin and rifampicin but resistant to chloramphenicol, tetracycline, ampicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid and streptomycin.  The DNA G+C content is 60.2–61.8 mol%.  Possesses C20C20 and C20C25 diether core lipids.  MK-8(H2) is the predominant menaquinone component.  Possesses phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol methylphosphate as major polar lipid components.  S-DGD-1, a sulfated mannosylglucosylglycerol diether, and unidentified glycolipids are also present.  The type strain, HDB5-2T (=BCC 20213T =JCM 13552T =PCU 278T), was isolated from fish sauce fermentation in Thailand.</description>
</treatment>
