<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloarchaeobius_iranensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>EB21T (=IBRC-M 10013T =KCTC 4048T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloarchaeobius iranensis gen. nov., sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from a saline lake IJSEM 62:1021-1026</reference>
  <file>Haloarchaeobius.iranensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are motile rods.  Gram-negative.  Colonies are pigmented orange–red.  Strictly aerobic; oxygen is used as the terminal electron acceptor.  Growth occurs at pH 6.0– 8.0, 25–50 ˚C and 2.0–5.0 M (12–30 %) NaCl.  MgCl2 is not required.  Optimal growth occurs at pH 7.5, 40 ˚C, 3.5 M (20 %) NaCl and 0.2 M MgCl2.  Extremely halophilic.  Polar lipids include phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, phosphatidylglycerol sulfate, three unidentified glycolipids and one minor phospholipid.  MK-8(II-H2) is the only respiratory lipoquinone present.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.7 mol% (HPLC method). Cells are 1.5–2.0 x 3–7 µm when grown in MGM liquid medium under optimum conditions.  Colonies are small (about 1.0–2.0 mm diameter).  Cells lyse in water.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not grow under anaerobic conditions with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite and gas formation from nitrate are not observed.  Gelatin and Tweens 20 and 40 are hydrolysed, whereas Tweens 60 and 80, casein, starch and DNA are not.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Acid is produced from D-glucose and maltose but not from L-arabinose, D-fructose, sucrose, D-mannitol, D-galactose, lactose or D-ribose.  H2S is not produced from thiosulfate.  Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.  Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative.  D-Fructose, D-glucose, D-galactose, maltose, lactose, L-asparagine, L-glycine, L-proline, L-phenylalanine and L-tyrosine are utilized as sole source of carbon and energy, while L-arabinose, sucrose D-mannitol, D-ribose, L-arginine, L-methionine, L-aspartic acid, L-cysteine and L-valine are not.  Susceptible to the following antimicrobial compounds: anisomycin (35 µg), bacitracin (10 U), nitrofurantoin (300 µg), novobiocin (5 µg) and rifampicin (5 µg).  Resistant to amoxicillin (25 µg), ampicillin (10 µg), cephalotin (30 µg), carbenicillin (100 µg), cefoxitin (30 µg), chloramphenicol (30 µg), erythromycin (5 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), kanamycin (5 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), neomycin (30 µg), penicillin G (10 U), polymyxin B (100 U), streptomycin (10 µg), tetracycline (30 µg) and tobramycin (10 µg).  The type strain, EB21T (=IBRC-M 10013T =KCTC 4048T), was isolated from Aran-Bidgol salt lake, Iran.</description>
</treatment>
