<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halomarina_oriensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>KeC-11T (=JCM 16495T =KCTC 4074T)</strain>
  <reference>Halomarina oriensis gen. nov., sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from a seawater aquarium IJSEM 61:942-946</reference>
  <file>Halomarina.oriensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are 0.6–2.0 µm in size.  Colonies are about 0.5 mm in diameter after 15 days of incubation at 37 ˚C on 1.5% agar plates containing 2.7 M (16 %) NaCl; they are circular, entire, smooth, convex and pink.  Cells are irregular cocci or discs, occurring singly or in pairs.  Growth occurs in 1.7– 5.0 M NaCl (optimum, 2.6 M), in 0.01–1.0 M Mg2+ (optimum, 0.2–0.5 M), at pH 7.0–9.0 (optimum, pH 7.0– 8.0) and at 20–42 ˚C (optimum, 37 ˚C).  Chemo-organotrophic.  Gelatin and Tween 40 are hydrolysed, whereas starch and casein are not.  Reduces nitrate to nitrite.  Anaerobic growth does not occur in the presence of nitrate, arginine, DMSO or TMAO.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  H2S is produced from elemental sulfur.  The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon and energy sources: glucose, mannose, galactose, fructose, D-ribose, D-xylose, maltose, sucrose, lactose, starch, glycerol, pyruvate and L-aspartate.  No growth occurs on mannitol, sorbitol, acetate, DL-lactate, succinate, L-malate, fumarate, citrate, glycine, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-glutamate or L-lysine.  Acid is produced when grown on utilizable carbohydrates.  The polar lipids are C20C20 and C20C25 diether derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, a glycolipid chromatographically identical to the glycosyl-mannosyl-glucosyl diether (TGD-2) and at least one unidentified glycolipid.  Resistant to novobiocin, erythromycin, penicillin, ampicillin, chloramphenicol and neomycin.  Sensitive to bacitracin, anisomycin, aphidicolin and rifampicin.  The type strain is KeC-11T (=JCM 16495T =KCTC 4074T), isolated from a seawater aquarium located at the Ocean Research Institute, University of Tokyo, Japan.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 67.7 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
