<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halobiforma_haloterrestris</taxon_name>
  <strain>135T (=DSM 13078T=JCM 11627T)</strain>
  <reference>Characterization of a novel halophilic archaeon, Halobiforma haloterrestris gen. nov., sp. nov., and transfer of Natronobacterium nitratireducens to Halobiforma nitratireducens comb. nov. IJSEM 52:2271-2280</reference>
  <file>Halobiforma.haloterrestris.nitratireducens.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are pigmented and are rods that measure 0.5-1.5 x 2-8 µm, pleomorphic and cocci that measure 1.25-2.0 µm in diameter.  Cells are Gram-negative and are motile.  Only rods lyse in distilled water or 1% (w/v) bacto-peptone.  The optimum temperature for growth is 42 °C.  The pH range for growth is pH 6-9.2, with an optimum at pH 7.5.  The NaCl range for growth is 2.2 M to saturation, with an optimum of 3.4 M NaCl.  NaCl may be replaced to a large extent by KCl.  Aerobic, catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Acid is produced from xylose, arabinose, glucose, sucrose and maltose, but not from lactose, fructose, galactose or starch or urea.  Casein and gelatin are hydrolysed, but not starch.  Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are also hydrolysed, but not egg yolk (lecithin).  NH4 cannot serve as a nitrogen source, while organic nitrogen compounds such as proteose peptone, Casamino acids and tryptone can serve as nitrogen, carbon and energy sources.  The strain accumulates PHB.  The G+C content of the DNA is 66.9 mol%.  Isolated from a salt soil close to Aswan (Egypt).  The type strain is strain 135T (=DSM 13078T=JCM 11627T).  Sensitive to fusidic acid, bacitracin, nitrofurantoin, novobiocin, anisomycin, and rifampicin.  Resistant to nystatin, tetracycline, nalidixic acid, trimethoprim, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, streomycin, and penicillin G.  The ether lipids comprised only diether lipids, tetraether lipids being absent.  The diether lipids present were the diphytanyl derivative C20:C20 and the phytanyl sesterterpanyl derivative C20:C25, in almost equal amounts.  Menaquinones were the only respiratory lipoquinones present and comprised MK-8 and MK-8(VIII-H2).  Furthermore, a sulfated triglycosyl diether and a triglycosyl diether were produced as sole glycolipids.</description>
</treatment>
