<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloarcula_tradensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>HST03T (=BCC 40030T=JCM 15760T =PCU 314T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloarcula salaria sp. nov. and Haloarcula tradensis sp. nov., isolated from salt in Thai fish sauce IJSEM 61:231-236</reference>
  <file>Haloarcula.salaria.tradensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are Gram-stain negative, non-motile, strictly aerobic pleomorphic rods, 0.8–1.2 µm in width and 1.0–2.5 µm in length.  When grown on a complex medium of neutral pH, colonies are small, entire, translucent and convex (0.9– 2.3 mm in diameter) after 1 week of incubation at 37 ˚C and show red pigmentation.  Cells lyse in distilled water.  Grows at between 15 and 45 ˚C (optimally at 37 ˚C) and at between pH 6.0 and pH 8.0 (optimally at pH 7.0).  Grows aerobically, but does not grow anaerobically, even in the presence of nitrate.  Tests for nitrate reduction, the methyl red/Voges–Proskauer reaction and the formation of indole are negative.  Extremely halophilic, requires at least 15% (w/v) NaCl for growth and optimal growth occurs at 20– 25% (w/v) NaCl.  Growth occurs at Mg2+ concentrations of 2–10% (w/v).  Catalase and oxidase reactions are positive.  Tween 80 and starch (weak reaction) are hydrolysed, but skimmed milk, gelatin, tyrosine and xanthine are not hydrolysed.  No acid production from cellobiose, glycerol, D-glucose, raffinose, D-sorbitol or trehalose.  Utilizes cellobiose, glycerol, D-glucose, D-galactose, raffinose, D-sorbitol, glutamic acid, aspartic acid and lysine, but not trehalose as sole energy sources.  The type strain is susceptible to bacitracin (10 µg) and novobiocin (5 µg), but resistant to chloramphenicol (30 µg), tetracycline (30 µg), ampicillin (30 µg), gentamicin (30 µg), rifampicin (30 µg), streptomycin (30 µg) and novobiocin (5 µg).  Possesses C20C20 diether core lipids.  MK-8 (91.8 %) and MK-8(H2) (8.2%) are present.  Possesses PG, PGP-Me, PGS, TGD-2, DGD and two unknown phospholipids.  The type strain, HST03T (=BCC 40030T=JCM 15760T =PCU 314T) was isolated from salt from a sample of fish sauce in Thailand.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.2 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
