<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halostagnicola_larsenii</taxon_name>
  <strain>XH-48T(=DSM 17691T=CGMCC 1.5338T=JCM 13463T=CECT 7116T)</strain>
  <reference>Halostagnicola larsenii gen. nov., sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon from a saline lake in Inner Mongolia, China IJSEM 56:1519-1524</reference>
  <file>Halostagnicola.larsenii.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram-negative.  Cells are pleomorphic although most are rod-shaped.  Colonies are pink-pigmented.  Strictly aerobic; oxygen is used as the terminal electron acceptor.  Growth occurs at pH values between 6.0 and 9.0, at temperatures between 25 and 50 ˚C and at salinities between 15 and 30% (2.5–5.0 M) NaCl.  Optimal growth occurs at pH 7.0–8.0, 37 ˚C and 20% (3.4 M) NaCl.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain of the only species in the genus is 61.0 mol% (Tm method).  Polar lipids include phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglyceromethylphosphate, derived from both C20C20 and C20C25 glycerol diethers, and two unidentified glycolipids.   Cells are 0.5–1.0 µm wide and 1.0–3.0 µm long.  Colonies are circular and 1–2 mm in diameter after incubation for 10 days at 37 ˚C.  Extremely halophilic and the cells lyse in water.  Magnesium is not required for growth.  Growth does not occur above 50 ˚C.  The pH range for growth is 6.0–9.0.  Amino acids are not required for growth.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Negative for indole production and in methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons’ citrate tests.  H2S is not produced from cysteine.  Acid is produced from sucrose.  Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.  Produces urease and phosphatase.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate or arginine does not occur.  Gelatin, Tween 80, casein and aesculin are not hydrolysed.  Starch and DNA are hydrolysed.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  The following substrates are utilized for growth: glycerol, fructose, maltose, trehalose, lactose, glucose, arabinose, galactose, mannitol, ribose, starch, xylose, propionate, glutamate and acetate.  No growth occurs on mannitol, sorbitol, raffinose, succinate, malate or fumarate.  Susceptible to bacitracin and novobiocin.  Resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline.  The type strain is strain XH-48T(=DSM 17691T=CGMCC 1.5338T=JCM 13463T=CECT 7116T), isolated from the saline Lake Xilinhot in Inner Mongolia, China.</description>
</treatment>
