<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Haloterrigena_longa</taxon_name>
  <strain>ABH32T (=CGMCC 1.5334T=JCM 13562T)</strain>
  <reference>Haloterrigena longa sp. nov. and Haloterrigena limicola sp. nov., extremely halophilic archaea isolated from a salt lake IJSEM 56:1837-1840</reference>
  <file>Haloterrigena.longa.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are non-motile, rod-shaped (0.5–0.6 x 2.8–11 µm) and Gram-negative.  Colonies on agar plates containing 3.1 M NaCl are red, elevated and round.  Chemo-organotrophic and aerobic.  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1.7–5.1 M, at Mg2+ concentrations of 0–1.0 M, at pH values in the range 6.5–9.0 and at temperatures of 30– 56 ˚C.  The optimal NaCl and Mg2+ concentrations for growth are 3.1 M and 0.1 M, respectively.  Optimal pH and temperature values are 7.0–7.5 and 41–45 ˚C, respectively.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate, arginine or DMSO does not occur.  Nitrate reduction to nitrite is not observed.  H2S is produced from Na2S2O3.  Positive for indole formation.  Tweens 20, 40 and 60 are hydrolysed but Tween 80 is not.  Negative for caseinase, amylase and gelatinase.  The following substrates are utilized as carbon sources: glucose, sucrose, maltose, pyruvate and acetate.  Fructose, sorbose, xylose, galactose, mannose, D-ribose, lactose, mannitol and sorbitol are not utilized as carbon sources.  Acid is produced in unbuffered medium from glucose and sucrose.  Sensitive to rifampicin (5 µg per disc) and novobiocin (30 µg per disc).  Resistant to the following antibiotics (µg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): erythromycin (15), neomycin (30), chloramphenicol (30), ampicillin (10), norfloxacin (10), ciprofloxacin (5), streptomycin (10), kanamycin (30), tetracycline (30), vancomycin (30), bacitracin (0.04 IU per disc) and penicillin G (10 IU per disc).  The major polar lipids are the C20C20 and C20C25 derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester and S2-DGD.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63.2 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, strain ABH32T (=CGMCC 1.5334T=JCM 13562T), was isolated from Aibi salt lake in Xin-Jiang, China.</description>
</treatment>
