<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halonotius_pteroides</taxon_name>
  <strain>1.15.5T (=JCM 14355T =CECT 7525T =DSM 18729T)</strain>
  <reference>Halonotius pteroides gen. nov., sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon recovered from a saltern crystallizer IJSEM 60:1196-1199</reference>
  <file>Halonotius.pteroides.pdf</file>
  <description>Displays the following properties in addition to those given for the genus.  Cells are flattened and display some variability in morphology, but many are flat rods, 0.7– 1.5 µm wide and 2–6 µm long.  The ends of the rods are often rounded.  Weakly motile with polar flagella.  Colonies on agar medium are red with entire edges.  Strictly aerobic; only oxygen is used as the final electron acceptor.  Cannot utilize nitrate or DMSO as alternative electron acceptors.  Growth occurs at pH 5.5–8.5, 25–45 ˚C and 16– 36% (w/v) NaCl.  Cells lyse immediately in distilled water.  Optimal growth occurs under neutrophilic conditions, above 18% (w/v) salinity.  Capable of growing in defined media, but very restricted in the substrates utilized.  Grows best on pyruvate, but also capable of utilizing glucose or glycerol as sole carbon sources.  Does not grow with any of the following substrates as the sole carbon and energy source (all at 10 mM): acetate, alanine, arabinose, arginine, aspartate, benzoate, betaine, butanol, butyrate, cellobiose, citrate, ethanol, formate, fructose, fumarate, galactose, galacturonate, gluconuronate, glycine, glycolate, lactate, lactose, leucine, lysine, malate, malonate, mannitol, mannose, methanol, propanol, propionate, ribose, serine, succinate, sucrose, tartrate, threonine, urea, valine and xylose.  Does not grow on cellulose, chitin or starch (each at 0.1 % w/v).  Acid is not produced from carbohydrate utilization.  Negative for b-galactosidase activity and indole production.  Sensitive to anisomycin, novobiocin, rifampicin and simvastatin, and resistant to ampicillin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, cycloheximide, erythromycin, kanamycin, mycostatin, neomycin, streptomycin and tetracycline at 50 µg per mL.  All four known strains were isolated from solar saltern crystallizer ponds.  The type strain is 1.15.5T (=JCM 14355T =CECT 7525T =DSM 18729T), isolated from Cheetham Salt Works, Geelong, Australia.  In addition to phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerophosphate methyl ester, the isolates possessed a glycolipid with the same mobility as the sulfated diglycosyl diether lipid S-DGD-1 of Halomicrobium mukohataei JCM 9738T.</description>
</treatment>
