<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Halorubrum_terrestre</taxon_name>
  <strain>4pT (=VKM B-1739T=JCM 10247T)</strain>
  <reference>Taxonomic study of Halorubrum distributum and proposal of Halorubrum terrestre sp. nov. IJSEM 54:389-392</reference>
  <file>Halorubrum.terrestre.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are pleomorphic, flat and disc-shaped, 1.0–1.5 x 1.5– 2.5 µm in size.  Motile.  Gas vacuoles are not produced.  Colonies are orange–red.  Growth occurs in media that contain 15–30% NaCl, with optimum growth at 25% NaCl.  Growth occurs between 28 and 50 ˚C (optimum, 37– 45 ˚C) and pH 5–9 (optimum, 7.5).  Chemo-organotrophic.  Aerobic.  Oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Acid is produced from glycerol, but not from arabinose, fructose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, sucrose or trehalose.  Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Voges–Proskauer test is negative.  Starch, gelatin and casein are not hydrolysed.  H2S is not produced.  Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase are not produced.  The following compounds are not used as sole carbon and energy sources: arabinose, cellobiose, aesculin, fructose, fucose, gluconolactone, glucose, glucosamine, inulin, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, adonitol, dulcitol, erythritol, ethanol, glycerol, mannitol, meso-inositol, propanol, sorbitol, a-aminovalerate, butyrate, caprylate, citrate, fumarate, glutamate, glycerate, 2-oxoglutarate, malate, malonate, oxalate, propionate, saccharate and tartrate.  The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen or energy sources: L-alanine, L-arginine, L-asparagine, betaine, creatine, L-glutamine, glycine, L-histidine, L-lysine, L-methionine, L-ornithine, L-proline, putrescine, sarcosine, L-serine, L-threonine and L-valine.  Susceptible to anisomycin, bacitracin and novobiocin; resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, penicillin G, polymyxin, streptomycin and tetracycline.  Polar lipids are C20C20 derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester, phosphatidylglycerol sulfate and a sulfated diglycosyl diether.  DNA G+C content is 64.2–64.9 mol% (Tm method).  Type strain is 4pT (=VKM B-1739T=JCM 10247T).  DNA G+C content of this strain is 64.4 mol% (Tm method).  Isolated from saline soils.</description>
</treatment>
