<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Hyperthermus_butylicus</taxon_name>
  <strain>DSM 5456</strain>
  <reference>Hyperthermus butylicus gen. nov. sp. nov. a Hyperthermophilic, Anaerobic, Peptide-Fermenting, Facultatively H2S-Generating Archaebacterium IJSB 41:169-170</reference>
  <file>Hyperthermus.butylicus.pdf</file>
  <description>Shape and size as described above for the genus.  About 1% diploforms.  Projections, probably pili and not flagella, extend from the whole surface.  Often there are short “tails,” which are probably remnants from division.  About 25% of late-log-phase cells grown at 107 to 108°C have long appendages.  Many cells in the late log phase of growth have vacuoles.  The lattice constant of the hexagonal S-layer is 25.9 nm and is distinct from the lattice constants of other archaebacteria.  Obligate anaerobe.  Grows by fermentation of proteolysis products (e.g., tryptones and gelatin).  The products are CO2 (2.6 mmol/g [dry weight]) and n-butanol, (33 mmol/g [dry weight]), as well as acetic acid, propionic acid, and phenylacetic acid (equal amounts).  Growth is stimulated about 10-fold by S˚ plus H2, with massive production of H2S.  No stimulation by CO2.  No chemolithoautotrophic growth.  Optimal growth occurs with 6 g of tryptone per liter, 10 g of S˚ per liter under CO2 or N2 containing 20% (vol/vol) H2, and 17 g of NaCl per liter at pH 7 between 95 and 107°C.  The generation times are 2 to 3 h; at 85˚C, the generation time is 4.5 h.  No growth occurs at 75°C.  Slow growth occurs at 108°C.  Cells contain DNA-dependent RNA polymerase which is not sensitive to rifampin and is stable at 102°C.  The component pattern is distinct on the basis of the apparent molecular weights of the components but corresponds in principle to the component patterns of other thermophilic sulfur archaebacteria.  The polyisoprenoid tetraether lipids of the membrane consist of only two major components (mainly tetraether lipids with 0 to 2 cyclopentane rings in isoprenoid chains).  The guanine-plus-cytosine content of the DNA is 56 mol%.  The type strain is strain DSM 5456.</description>
</treatment>
