<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Ignisphaera_aggregans</taxon_name>
  <strain>AQ1.S1T (=DSM 17230T=JCM 13409T)</strain>
  <reference>Ignisphaera aggregans gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel hyperthermophilic crenarchaeote isolated from hot springs in Rotorua and Tokaanu, New Zealand IJSEM 56:965-971</reference>
  <file>Ignisphaera.aggregans.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are regular to irregular cocci that occur singly, in pairs or as aggregates.  Hyperthermophilic anaerobe.  Moderate acidophile.  Heterotrophic.  Electron acceptor is not absolutely necessary.  Elemental sulphur and NaCl inhibit growth.  Cells are approximately 1–1.5 µm in size when grown on starch.  Temperature and pH ranges for growth are 85–98 ˚C (optimum at 92–95 ˚C) and pH 5.4–7.0 (optimum pH 6.4).  Obligate anaerobe.  Ferments both poly- and disaccharides.  Grows at low salinity (&lt;0.5% NaCl) and optimally without addition of NaCl.  Resistant to novobiocin and streptomycin but sensitive to erythromycin, chloramphenicol and rifampicin.  The G+C content of the DNA is 52.9 mol%.  The type strain is Ignisphaera aggregans AQ1.S1T (=DSM 17230T=JCM 13409T), which was isolated from a near-neutral pH, boiling spring in Kuirau Park, Rotorua, New Zealand.  Utilized starch, trypticase peptone, lactose, glucose, konjac glucomannan, mannose, galactose, maltose, glycogen and b-cyclodextrin.  Weak growth was evident on beef extract and sucrose.  Growth was not observed on yeast extract, cellobiose, methanol, ethanol, trehalose, pyruvate, acetate, malate, Casamino acids (0.1% w/v), carboxymethylcellulose, amylopectin (corn), xanthan gum, locust gum (bean), guar gum, dextran, xylan (oat spelts, larch or birch), xylitol, xylose or amylose (corn and potato).  The strain could also grow in the standard growth medium without the addition of starch. Thioglycolate, nitrate, nitrite, sulphite, thiosulphate and elemental sulphur were inhibitory at a concentration of 10 mM (including cystine) and at 2.5 mM.  Both sulphite and thioglycolate also inhibited growth.  Growth was inhibited by sulphur.  No growth was detected in serum bottles under autotrophic conditions.  All isolates were strict anaerobes.</description>
</treatment>
