<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Lisa Moore">
  <taxon_name>Marsacia_ferruginose</taxon_name>
  <strain>JSC-1</strain>
  <reference>Polyphasic Characterization of a Thermotolerant Siderophilic Filamentous Cyanobacterium That Produces Intracellular Iron Deposits (Brown, I., et al., 2010)</reference>
  <DOI>10.1128/AEM.00662-10</DOI>
  <file>Brown, I. et al. Marsacia ferruginose.pdf</file>
  <description>isolated from an iron-depositing hot spring, Strain JSC-1 exhibited an unusually high ratio between photosystem (PS) I and PS II, was capable of complementary chromatic adaptation, and is apparently capable of nitrogen fixation. Furthermore, it synthesized a unique set of carotenoids, but only chlorophyll a. Strain JSC-1 not only required high levels of Fe for growth (&gt;40 μM), but it also accumulated large amounts of extracellular iron in the form of ferrihydrite and intracellular iron in the form of ferric phosphates., siderophilic cyanobacteria, thermotolerant, Filaments were ~500 to 2,500 μm in length, with multiple loops and reversions, Two morphotypes were observed in the JSC-1 culture. The first morphotype had almost isometric cells with an average length of 2.52 +/- 0.41 μm, width of 2.16 +/- 0.13 μm, and a length-to-width (L/W) ratio of ~1.17. The second morphotype had slightly elongated cylindrical cells with a length of 2.89 +/- 0.27 μm, width of 1.62 +/- 0.17 μm, and a length/width ratio of 1.78. TEM studies showed that the cross walls in JSC-1 were approximately 22 nm thick, and neither junctions nor cytoplasmic membrane pores were observed. However, two basic patterns for thylakoid membranes were detected. Transverse and cross sections of short cells demonstrated a peripheral but undulating alignment of thylakoids relative to the internal side of the cytoplasm membranes of the cells, with five to six thylakoids per cell observed on average. For elongated cells, the thylakoid membranes assembled into a more irregular pattern, described as a knit-ball structure. The sheaths of JSC-1 were colorless, thick, persistent, firm, and easily visible by both light microscopy and TEM (Fig. 2C, D, and F). In contrast to the persistent, nonlaminated sheaths typically observed for Leptolyngbya (14), the sheaths of JSC-1 cells were laminated. Detailed TEM analysis revealed very tiny bodies within the sheath not observed in other representatives of Leptolyngbya. The necridia were filled with symmetrical membrane patterns with no chlorophyll autofluorescence.</description>
</treatment>
