<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Metallosphaera_yellowstonensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>MK1</strain>
  <reference>Isolation and Distribution of a Novel Iron-Oxidizing Crenarchaeon from Acidic Geothermal Springs in Yellowstone National Park AEM 74:942-949</reference>
  <file>Metallosphaera.yellowstonensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Obtained from a well-characterized acid-sulfate-chloride geothermal spring in Norris Geyser Basin, YNP. Facultative chemolithoautotroph with an optimum pH range of 2.0 to 3.0 and an optimum temperature range of 65 to 75°C.  Strain MK1 grows optimally on pyrite or Fe(II) sorbed onto ferrihydrite, exhibiting doubling times between 10 and 11 h under aerobic conditions (65°C).  Abundant in Fe(III) oxide mats at temperatures ranging from 55 to 80°C. No measurable growth in the presence of 20 mM ferrous sulfate, suggesting that sorbed Fe(II) or the presence of a mineral substrate is an important prerequisite for the growth of this organism.  This organism is also capable of growth on elemental S˚, albeit at a reduced rate compared to treatments containing Fe(II).  The amount of sulfate produced during growth in the presence of pyrite (3 mM) or elemental sulfur ( 1.3 mM) was consistent with the differential growth rates on these substrates and confirmed that strain MK1 is capable of oxidizing reduced forms of sulfur.  This organism exhibited optimal growth at pH 2 to 3 and at 65 to 75°C; however, it could survive over a reasonably broad temperature range (45 to 85°C).  Autotrophic growth was also significant in the presence of pyrite-enriched mine tailings, pyrrhotite (FeS), and chalcopyrite (CuFeS2).  Growth was modest on S˚ plus 0.005% yeast extract.  Growth on S˚ was enhanced considerably after the addition of 10 mM Fe(II)SO4, despite the fact that strain MK1 did not grow in media containing 20 mM aqueous Fe(II)SO4.  Poor or modest growth was observed on other sulfide minerals, including sphalerite (ZnS) and covellite (CuS); however, no growth was observed on aqueous sulfide, thiosulfate, or tetrathionate or on the reduced Fe minerals magnetite (Fe3O4) and siderite (FeCO3).  Anaerobic growth was not detected using S˚ as an electron donor and ferric iron (as ferrihydrite) as an electron acceptor.  No growth was observed on pyrite, Fe(II) ferrihydrite, or S˚ under anaerobic conditions when NO3 was present as a potential electron acceptor.  Coccus morphology (diameter, 0.9 to 1.2 µm), as well as a plasma membrane and an S layer approximately 50 nm thick, both of which are typical of other members of the Sulfolobales.  Cells of strain MK1 is closely associated with pyrite and/or Fe(III) oxide particles formed as a result of Fe(II) oxidation.</description>
</treatment>
