<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Methanosaeta_thermophila</taxon_name>
  <strain>PT (= DSM 6194)</strain>
  <reference>Characterization of Three Thermophilic Strains of Methanothrix (‘ ‘Methanosaeta ”) thermophila sp.  nov. and Rejection of Methanothrix (“Methanosaeta ”) thermoacetophila IJSB 42:463-468</reference>
  <file>Methanosaeta.thermophila.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are nonmotile, strictly anaerobic rods with flat ends and are gram negative.  The mean dimensions of single cells are 0.8 to 1.3 µm by 2 to 6 µm.  Cells are enclosed inside an annular, striated sheathed structure and are separated by partitions that have a concentric structure.  Cells grow in the form of loose sediment, and culture broth exhibits opalescent turbidity after gentle shaking.  Most of the sheathed filaments are less than 100 µm long, and they do not form bundles or the cottonlike flocs which are common in Methanothrix soehngenii.  Colonies are sometimes observed in acetate agar medium when high cell concentrations are present.  Gas vesicles are often observed inside the cells.  Cells are not susceptible to lysis by SDS or hypotonic conditions at room temperature, but cells are lysed by SDS at 60°C.  The optimum temperature for growth and methanogenesis is 55 to 60˚C, depending on the strain.  The optimum pH is around 7.  Acetate is the only substrate used for growth and methanogenesis.  Neither methanogenesis nor growth is observed when H2-CO2, formate, methylamines, or methanol is used for the substrate.  Formate is not split into H2 and CO2.  NaCl is not required for growth.  Coenzyme M (mercaptoethane sulfonate), vitamins, manure extract, or sludge fluid stimulates growth.  Chloramphenicol (5 µg/ml), bacitracin (10 µg/ml), neomycin (10 µg/ml), tetracycline (100 µg/ml), and kanamycin (100 µg/ml) inhibit growth and methanogenesis.  The DNA base composition ranges from 52.7 to 54.3 mol% guanine plus cytosine as determined by HPLC.  The type strain of Methanothrix themophila is strain PT (= DSM 6194).</description>
</treatment>
