<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Methanosarcina_vacuolata</taxon_name>
  <strain>Z-761 (DSM 1232)</strain>
  <reference>Methanosarcina vacuolata sp. nov. a Vacuolated Methanosarcina IJSB 37:281-283</reference>
  <file>Methanosarcina.vacuolata.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells spherical or compressed, 1 to 2 µm in rounded aggregates arranged into sarcinalike packets.  Nonmotile.  Gram positive.  Not lysed by 0.07% sodium dodecyl sulfate at 23°C.  Differentiating cytological characteristic: the presence of large vacuoles containing gas vesicles.  Multiplication by uneven fission in different planes; septation may not be visible by phase-contrast microscopy.  Rounded pseudococci observed in a light microscope are aggregates of polygonal cells with a common microcapsule.  Forms 0.5- to 1.0-mm-deep colonies in agar; light yellow, angular, fine granulation.  Grows in liquid medium as a yellow sediment, easily dispersed.  Strictly anaerobic.  Methanogenic catabolism: methanol, monomethylamines, dimethylamines, and trimethylamines, H2-CO2 are utilized with formation of methane.  Formate is not utilized.  Autotrophic anabolism.  Organic compounds with growth factors enhance growth of some strains but are not obligately needed.  Ammonium is the source of nitrogen and sulfide is the source of sulfur.  Optimal temperature, 37 to 40°C; temperature range, 18 to 42°C.  Optimal pH, 7.5; range, 6 to 8.  Squalenes are major compohent of lipids.  Cytochromes and factor III are present in the cells, while B12 is absent.  Guanosine plus cytosine content of DNA is 36.3 mol%.  Habitat: soils of wetlands, swamps, freshwater sediments, anaerobic digestors.  Type strain is Z-761 (DSM 1232) isolated from an anaerobic digestor in Moscow, USSR.  Deposited in the Institute of Microbiology of the Academy of Sciences of the USSR and in Deutsche Sammlung von Mikroorganismen, Gottingen, Federal Republic of Germany.</description>
</treatment>
