<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Methanosarcina_siciliae</taxon_name>
  <strain>C2J</strain>
  <reference>Isolation of an Aceticlastic Strain of Methanosarcina siciliae from Marine Canyon Sediments and Emendation of the Species Description for Methanosarcina siciliae IJSB 47:1258-1261</reference>
  <file>Methanosarcina.siciliae.pdf</file>
  <description>Enriched from a sediment core retrieved from the Sumner Branch of Scripps Canyon near La Jolla, CA, at a depth of 19.8 m below the surface of the water.  During exponential growth in liquid culture cells were irregularly shaped cocci, 3.4 h 0.5 µm in diameter, and occurred singly or in pairs.  Motility was not observed.  Single cells and aggregates were lysed with 0.005% sodium dodecyl sulfate.  Single-cell forms of C2J grown in medium containing trimethylamine are larger (diameter 3.4e0.5 µm) than strain T4/M cells (diameter 2.5/0.2 µm) grown in the same medium and larger than the strain HI350 cells (diameter 1.5 to 3.0 µm) described previously.  Under similar growth conditions, strain C2J forms aggregates after achieving stationary growth.  In addition, strain C2J forms large multicellular aggregates up to 1 mm in diameter.  Strain C2J is mesophilic, and the maximum rate of growth occurs at 35°C.  Growth of strain C2J was observed at 20˚C.  No growth was observed at 45°C.  Strain C2J exhibited the maximum rate of growth at pH 6.0 to 7.0.  Strain C2J has a maximum rate of growth at 0.2 to 0.6 M NaCl.  Grows poorly at 0.3 osmol/kg (no addition of NaCl).  Therefore, this newly described strain, like previously described strains of M. siciliae, is slightly halophilic.  Growth on methanol, trimethylamine, and dimethylsulfide and acetate as catabolic substrates.  Did not use formate or H2/CO2 as catabolic substrates.  Trypticase, yeast extract, Casamino Acids, and vitamins were not required for growth in minimal medium and did not significantly stimulate growth.</description>
</treatment>
