<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Methanotorris_formicicus</taxon_name>
  <strain>Mc-S-70T (=JCM 11930T=ATCC BAA-687T)</strain>
  <reference>Methanotorris formicicus sp. nov., a novel extremely thermophilic, methane-producing archaeon isolated from a black smoker chimney in the Central Indian Ridge IJSEM 54:1095-1100</reference>
  <file>Methanotorris.formicicus.pdf</file>
  <description>Irregular coccus, mean diameter of 0.8–1.5 µm.  Cells occur singly or in pairs.  Non-motile, but with a few thin, long flagella, which are easily removed from the cell.  Strictly anaerobic and obligately methanogenic.  The temperature range for growth is 55–83 ˚C (optimum of 75 ˚C).  The pH range for growth is pH 6.0–8.5 (optimum of pH 6.7).  NaCl is required for growth, which occurs in 4–60 g NaCl per liter (optimum growth at 24 g per liter).  Grows using molecular hydrogen or formate as an electron donor and carbon dioxide as an electron acceptor and a carbon source.  Acetate, methanol, ethanol, dimethyl sulfide, trimethylamine, yeast extract, peptone, tryptone, casamine acids, and an amino acid mixture of 20 amino acids did not replace the growth requirement for H2 or stimulate growth in the presence of H2 and CO2.  Ammonium, molecular nitrogen and nitrate serve as nitrogen sources.  Vitamins, selenium, tungsten, magnetite (Fe3O4) and thiosulfate do not stimulate growth.  Resistant to ampicillin (200 µg per mL), kanamycin (200 µg per mL), rifampicin (50 µg per mL) and streptomycin (200 µg per mL), but sensitive to chloramphenicol (50 µg per mL) and rifampicin (100 µg per mL).  Susceptible to lysis by 0.1% (w/v) SDS solution and hypotonic solutions.  Major hydrocarbon chains of core lipids are C20 (76.9%) and C40 (23.1 %).  The type strain is Mc-S-70T (=JCM 11930T=ATCC BAA-687T), isolated from a black smoker chimney in the Kairei field, Central Indian Ridge, Indian Ocean.  Its genomic DNA G+C content is 33.3% (HPLC method).</description>
</treatment>
