<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Methanosaeta_concilii</taxon_name>
  <strain>GP6T = DSM 3671 = NRC 2989 = OGC 69 = ATCC 35969</strain>
  <reference>Methanosaeta concilii gen. nov. sp. nov. (“Methanothrix concilii”) and Methanosaeta thermoacetophila nom. rev., comb. nov.? IJSB 40:79-82</reference>
  <file>Methanosaeta.concilii.pdf</file>
  <description>The cells are gram-negative, nonmotile, nonsporeforming, strictly anaerobic rods with flat ends.  The cells are 0.8 µm wide by 2.5 to 6.0 µm long and are enclosed in a proteinaceous sheath.  Chains of cells grow as long filaments which aggregate into bundles.  Filaments do not easily break into smaller fragments when they are subjected to vigorous shaking.  Cultures incubated without shaking grow as a mat or as a sediment.  The sheath consists of annular hoops stacked to form the sheath tube.  In-growth of spacer plugs and filament splitting at the site of a nonreplicating unit of the protoplasm are part of the cell division process.  The sheath consists of a matrix with an outer paracrystalline surface array composed of small subunits exhibiting p2 symmetry, and it resists dissociation by various chemical treatments.   The optimum growth temperature is 35 to 40°C in acetate medium at pH 7.2.  Growth does not occur at 10 or 45°C.  The optimum growth pH at 35°C is between 7.1 and 7.5, with growth occurring at least between pH 6.6 and 7.8.  The mass doubling time is 65 to 70 h based on either CH4 production or turbidity of the culture between 3 and 9 days of incubation.  If a small inoculum is used, then a requirement is demonstrable for sodium carbonate or CO2 for initiation of growth in acetate medium.  Inorganic nitrogen serves as a sole nitrogen source for growth, but organic nitrogen, including cysteine, alanine, phenylalanine, glutamic acid, aspartic acid, and methylamine, does not.  Cysteine hydrochloride, sodium sulfide, or glutathione serves as a sole sulfur source, and biotin, thiamine hydrochloride, and p-aminobenzoic acid stimulate growth.  Iron, nickel, manganese, zinc, and cobalt enhance growth, whereas both calcium and magnesium are essential.  Sludge fluid is stimulatory.  Organic growth factors are not required for culture maintenance in mineral-salts-vitamin medium Aa. Growth is almost completely inhibited by either methyl or benzyl viologen (5 µM), by chloroform (50 µM), and by potassium cyanide (100 µM).  Inhibition by 2-bromoethanesulfonic acid is reversed by a five-fold excess of 2- mercaptoethanesulfonic acid .  Severe inhibition of CH4 production that is caused by 40 mM NH4Cl during shortterm (6-h) incubation of cells in anaerobic, 0.1 M HEPES (N-2-hydroxyethylpiperazine-N’-2-ethanesulfoniacc id) buffer is completely reversed in the presence of 20 to 40 mM CaCl2.  In longer-term (21-d) incubations in growth medium, 120 mM NH4Cl is required to cause about 80% inhibition of growth and methanogenesis.  Yeast extract (0.05%, wt/vol) results in a 50% inhibition of CH4 production and growth.  An equivalent amount of ashed yeast extract (550˚C, 4 h) does not affect growth or methanogenesis.  Vancomycin (1 mg/ml), kanamycin (1 mg/ml), and D-cycloserine (0.1 mg/ml) cause 90 to 100% inhibition of growth and methanogenesis.   Growth and CH4 production do not occur with methanol, trimethylamine, formic acid, propionic acid, butyric acid, or pyruvic acid as the sole source of carbon and energy.  In the presence of acetate, formic acid is split into H2 and CO2.  H2-CO2 does not support growth, and 80% H2 in the headspace gas does not inhibit growth on acetate.  Acetic acid serves as the sole energy source, and both acetic acid and CO2 serve as carbon sources for growth.  The metabolism of 1 mol of acetic acid results in the production of 1.0 mol of CH4, 0.95 mol of CO2, and 1.13 to 1.16 g (dry weight) of cells, and the apparent Ks for acetate is 1.2 mM.  The CH4 carbon is nearly all derived from the methyl carbon of acetate, the carboxyl carbon of acetate is predominantly converted to CO2, and both carbons of acetate, as well as carbon from NaHCO2, are incorporated into cell biomass.  Acetate is carboxylated to form pyruvate, which is then converted to amino acids.   The DNA base composition is 49.0 mol% G+C, as determined by the thermal denaturation procedure (melting temperature, 88.8 to 90.0˚C) in this work.  The type strain of Methanosaeta concilii is strain GP6; it has been deposited with the DSM as strain DSM 3671, with the National Research Council of Canada as strain NRC 2989, with the Oregon Graduate Center Collection of Methanogenic Archaeobacteria as strain OGC 69, and with the American Type Culture Collection as strain ATCC 35969.  Strain GP6T was isolated from a laboratory acetic acid enrichment culture which received inoculum from a pear waste fermentor inoculated with anaerobic sludge from the Regional Municipality of Ottawa-Carleton sewage treatment facility.  This isolate represents a key methanogenic organism in mesophilic anaerobic digestion processes where acetic acid is a major intermediary metabolite of organic waste fermentation.</description>
</treatment>
