<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Methanohalophilus_halophilus</taxon_name>
  <strain>Z-7982 (= DSM 3094 = OCM 160)</strain>
  <reference>DNA-DNA Hybridization of Methylotrophic Halophilic Methanogenic Bacteria and Transfer of Methanococcus halophilus to the Genus Methanohalophilus as Methanohalophilus halophilus comb. nov. IJSB 41:558-562</reference>
  <file>Methanohalophilus.halophilus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are irregular polygonal cocci that range in diameter from 0.2 to 2 µm (0.5 to 2 µm for the type strain).  The cells occur singly or in pairs and often form irregular aggregates.  Multiplication occurs by binary fission, not multiple fission.  The cell wall consists of protein subunits.  Cells are surrounded by a slime polysaccharide capsule.  Cell walls are lysed by 0.05% sodium dodecyl sulfate and 0.07% Sarcosyl NL30.  Osmotically unstable; lysis occurs in hypotonic solutions.  Nonmotile.  Flagella are not present.  Fimbriae are absent, Gram negative.  Growth in liquid medium is dispersed.  The temperature range for growth is &lt;18 to 40°C; the optimum temperature is 26 to 36°C.  The pH optimum is between 6.5 and 7.4.  No growth occurs at pH 8.0 and 6.3.  Obligate moderate halophile.  Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 0.6 to 2.5 M NaCl (1.2 to 1.5 M for the type strain).  The range of salinities tolerated is 0.3 to 3.5 M NaCl (0.3 to 2.6 M for the type strain).  Strictly anaerobic.  Obligately methylotrophic.  Growth occurs in chemically defined medium with trimethylamine, monomethylamine, and dimethylamine (trimethylamine is the preferred substrate).  Some strains utilize methanol.  Formate, acetate, H2-CO2, and secondary alcohols are not utilized.  Yeast extract or other organic growth factors are not required.  Yeast extract and Trypticase at a concentration of 0.05% inhibit growth of the type strain.  The G+C contents range from 43 to 48 mol% (44 mol% for the type strain).  Habitat: widely distributed all over the world in hypersaline lagoons with evaporating seawater.  The type strain was isolated from cyanobacterial mat and bottom deposits at Hamelin Pool, Shark Bay, northwestern Australia.  The type strain of Methanohalophilus halophilus is strain Z-7982 (= DSM 3094 = OCM 160).</description>
</treatment>
