<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Gail Gasparich">
  <taxon_name>Mycoplasma_mycoides_subsp._capri</taxon_name>
  <file>Myleachii Mymycoidesmycoides Mymycoidescapri Manso-Silvan et al 2009</file>
  <description>Initially designated Asterococcus mycoides ‘variety’ capri (Edward, 1953), this taxon acquired the genus name Mycoplasma in 1956 (Edward &amp; Freundt, 1956), as listed on the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names that became effective in January 1980 (Skerman et al., 1980). This subspecies now also includes strains previously referred to as M. mycoides subsp. mycoides Large Colony, which are represented by strain Y-goatR. Non-helical, pleomorphic, facultative anaerobe. It grows optimally at 37C, less vigorously at 22C and its viability is maintained after 2 days incubation at 45C (Thigpen et al., 1983). It grows rapidly in liquid medium such as that of Hayflick (1965), producing heavily turbid cultures. On suitable solid medium, colonies with characteristic fried-egg morphology about 2.5 mm in diameter appear after 2 days (Thigpen et al., 1983). Does not produce filamentous growth, films or spots.  Digests casein, liquefies inspissated serum, produces haemolysis on horse blood agar and the supernatants from 6 day cultures discolour horse erythrocytes. Ferments glucose, but does not metabolize arginine or urea. Serological crossreactions have been reported with M. mycoides subsp. mycoides (Cottew &amp; Yeats, 1978; Thigpen et al., 1983). According to Bergey’s Manual of Determinative Bacteriology (Holt, 1994), the DNA G+C content is 24.0–26.0 mol%; the partial genome sequence of strain GM12 shows a G+C content of 23.0 mol% (Lartigue et al., 2007). Associated with various symptoms in small ruminants, including mastitis, arthritis, keratoconjunctivitis, pneumonia and septicaemia. The type strain, PG3 (5NCTC 10137 5CIP 71.25), was isolated in 1950 or possibly earlier from a case of pleuropneumonia in a Turkish goat (Tully et al., 1974), but is no longer virulent for its primary host (El Nasri, 1967). Strain Y-goatR represents a serovar showing serological cross-reactions with M. mycoides subsp. mycoides.</description>
</treatment>
