<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Gail Gasparich">
  <taxon_name>Mycoplasma_mycoides_subsp._mycoides</taxon_name>
  <file>Myleachii Mymycoidesmycoides Mymycoidescapri Manso-Silvan et al 2009</file>
  <description>Initially designated Asterococcus mycoides (Borrel et al., 1910), referring to its pleomorphic, mucous nature and to the production of mycelium-like filaments, the nomenclature of this taxon was modified to Mycoplasma mycoides when it acquired the legitimate genus name Mycoplasma (Edward &amp; Freundt, 1956), as listed on the Approved Lists of Bacterial Names that became effective in January 1980 (Skerman et al., 1980). This Text, based on the original Texts and on additional data, emphasizes the particularities related to the fact that this taxon no longer includes the Large Colony strains represented by strain Y-goatR. A non-helical, pleomorphic organism measuring 125–175 nm in length (Edward, 1954). Facultative anaerobe that displays a tendency to produce filamentous growth, but does not produce films or spots. Optimal growth occurs at 37C; no growth is evident at 22C. Its viability is extremely reduced after 12 h incubation at 45C (Cottew &amp; Yeats, 1978). Grows relatively slowly and, after 2 days incubation, produces small colonies about 0.5 mm in diameter (Thigpen et al., 1983), which show the characteristic fried-egg appearance on suitable solid medium such as that of Hayflick (1965). When broth cultures are shaken, the sediment rises in characteristic ‘silky swirls’. Digests casein and liquefies in spissated serum, albeit less vigorously than the other members of the M. mycoides cluster. Produces haemolysis on horse blood agar and filtrates of 6 day cultures discolour horse erythrocytes. Ferments glucose, does not metabolize arginine or urea and can be distinguished from other members of the M. mycoides cluster by its total inability to oxidize maltose and trehalose, coupled to its inability to oxidize mannose and glucosamine at concentrations of 50 mM (Abu-Groun et al., 1994). Shows serological cross-reactions with M. mycoides subsp. capri (Cottew &amp; Yeats, 1978; Thigpen et al., 1983) and shares antigens with the newly designated taxon M. leachii (formerly MBG7).  According to Bergey’s Manual of Determinative Bacteriology (Holt, 1994), the DNA G+C content is 26.1–27.1 mol%; the genome sequence from type strain PG1 showed a G+C content of 24.0 mol% (Westberg et al., 2004). Mycoplasma mycoides subsp. mycoides is the aetiological agent of contagious bovine pleuropneumonia (CBPP). The type strain, PG1 (5NCTC 10114 5CCUG 32753), was deposited in 1931 by P. Laidlaw as a representative of the CBPP agent. The exact origin of the strain is not known and the cultures are no longer pathogenic.</description>
</treatment>
