<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Gail Gasparich">
  <taxon_name>Mycoplasma_leachii</taxon_name>
  <file>Myleachii Mymycoidesmycoides Mymycoidescapri Manso-Silvan et al 2009</file>
  <description>Mycoplasma leachii (leachi.i. N.L. masc. gen. n. leachii of Leach, named in honour of Dr R. H. Leach, who first characterized this taxon). This Text is based on data obtained from previous reports (Abu-Groun et al., 1994; Cottew et al., 1987; Leach, 1967). Non-spiral, non-motile, pleomorphic cells that lack a cell wall, are bounded by a single plasma membrane and pass through 0.45 mm pore-size membranes. As a facultative anaerobe, it grows rapidly, producing heavily turbid cultures and relatively large colonies with characteristic fried-egg morphology, which measure about 2 mm in diameter on suitable solid media such as Hayflick medium (Hayflick, 1965). It does not produce films or spots, nor does it form filaments. Optimal growth occurs at 37C; it may grow at 28C, but not at 22 uC. Susceptible to digitonin, requires sterols for growth, digests casein, liquefies inspissated serum and produces haemolysis on horse blood agar. Ferments glucose, but does not metabolize arginine or urea.  Can be distinguished from other members of the M. mycoides cluster by a high rate of trehalose metabolism, coupled to an inability to oxidize mannose and glucosamine at concentrations, 50 mM. Members of this species produce strong serological crossreactivity with M. capricolum subsp. capripneumoniae and limited reactivity with strains of M. capricolum subsp. capricolum, and share antigens with M. mycoides. The DNA G+C content was estimated to be 25.4 mol% (Askaa et al., 1978; Christiansen &amp; Erno, 1982). Associated mainly with mastitis, polyarthritis and abortion in dairy cattle, although it may also be found in healthy cattle, as well as in small ruminant hosts. The type strain PG50, previously known as N29 (5NCTC 10133 5DSM 21131), was isolated in Australia in 1963 from an arthritic joint of a calf.</description>
</treatment>
