<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Gail Gasparich">
  <taxon_name>Mycoplasma_agassizii</taxon_name>
  <file>Myagassizii Brown et al 2001</file>
  <description>Mycoplasma agassizii [aga«ssi.z.ii. M.L. gen. n. agassizii of Agassiz, named after J. Louis R. Agassiz, a notable Swiss born American naturalist who first described the North American Testudinata (Agassiz, 1857) and after whom the desert tortoise was named (Cooper, 1863)]. Cells are coccoid to pleomorphic with no cell wall but with a clearly defined three-layer membrane. Nonhelical and non-motile. Some strains appear to possess a rudimentary tip structure. Colonies on agar are variable, with both mulberry and fried-egg characteristics. Mulberry colonies are common on primary isolation plates. Primary isolation requires 3±6 weeks of incubation. It does not grow well above 30 °C. Best growth is achieved with SP-4 medium. Cells pass through 0.45 um filters and some, but not all strains also pass through 0.22 um filters. No reversion to bacterial forms is seen. It is inhibited by digitonin and requires serum or sterol for growth. Glucose is fermented, but arginine and urea are not hydrolysed.  Phosphatase is not produced. It haemagglutinates guinea pig and tortoise erythrocytes. Most, but not all strains haemadsorb guinea pig and tortoise erythrocytes. It  contains conserved mycoplasmal genus species sequences in the 16S rRNA gene and is serologically distinct from other Mycoplasma species. The 16S rRNA gene sequence is unique. The habitat is the respiratory tract of the desert tortoise and gopher tortoise, with the most common sites of isolation being the nares and choana. It is virulent and has been demonstrated in experimental infections to cause upper respiratory tract disease in both the desert tortoise and gopher tortoise. Type strain is PS6 (ATCC 700616T) and is also available from the Mollicutes Culture Collection (Curators Dr J. K. Davis and M. K. Davidson, University of Florida).</description>
</treatment>
