<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Natronobacterium_vacuolata</taxon_name>
  <strain>M24 = NCIMB 13189</strain>
  <reference>Natronobacterium vacuolata sp. nov., a Haloalkaliphilic Archaeon Isolated from Lake Magadi, Kenya IJSB 43:401-404</reference>
  <file>Natronobacterium.vacuolata.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are short rods, (0.5 to 0.7 by 1.5 to 3.0 µm) in the exponential phase of growth in liquid medium and spherical in the stationary phase and on solid medium (1 to 1.5 µm in diameter).  Cells produce large gas vacuoles in the stationary phase and on solid medium.  Cells lyse when shifted from 3.5 to &lt;1.2 M NaCl.  Nonmotile and gram variable.  Colonies bright pink, 1 to 2 mm in diameter, convex, entire, and circular after incubation for 5 days at 37°C.  Strict aerobe.  Requires 15 to 30% NaCl for growth; optimum, 20% (3.5 M NaCl).  Obligately alkaliphilic, requiring sodium carbonate, with a pH range for growth of 8.5 to 10.5; optimum pH 9.5.  Temperature range for growth, 20 to 50°C; optimum temperature, 35 to 40°C.  Possesses menaquinone MK8 and both C20C20, and C20C25 diether derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol phosphate.  Does not possess glycolipids.  Chemoorganotroph.  Utilizes a range of amino acids and sugars.  Oxidase and catalase positive.  Gelatin and starch not hydrolyzed.  Nitrate reduced to nitrite.  Sensitive to nitrofurantoin (50 µg), sulfamethoxazole (50 µg), trimethoprim (2.5 µg), and novobiocin (5 µg); growth is weakened but not inhibited by erythromycin (5 µg).  Insensitive to ampicillin (25 µg), chloramphenicol (25 µg), streptomycin (10 µg), and tetracycline (25 µg).  G+C content of DNA is 62.7 mol% (Tm).  Habitat: highly saline soda lakes.  Type strain M24 isolated on site from beside the main causeway across Lake Magadi, Kenya, and deposited with the National Collection of Industrial and Marine Bacteria, Aberdeen, United Kingdom, as NCIMB 13189.  Growth not stimulated by fructose, mannitol, and pyruvate.</description>
</treatment>
