<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Natrinema_salaciae</taxon_name>
  <strain>MDB25T (=DSM 25055T =JCM 17869T)</strain>
  <reference>Natrinema salaciae sp. nov., a halophilic archaeon isolated from the deep, hypersaline anoxic Lake Medee in the Eastern Mediterranean Sea Syst Appl Microbiol 35:368-373</reference>
  <file>Natrinema.salaciae.pdf</file>
  <description>Gram-negative, pleomorphic cells ranging from rods to coccoid forms (1.0–3.0 µm in length and 0.8–1.5 µm in width).  Non-motile.  Colonies are red pigmented in Halobacteria medium.  The optimum growth temperature is about 45 ˚C; growth does not occur at 25 and 55 ˚C.  The optimum pH for growth is between 7.0 and 8.0; growth does not occur at pH 6.0 or pH 9.5.  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations between 1.7 and 5.1 M, with optimum growth at 2.6–3.4 M.  Growth occurs with MgSO4*7H2O at 0–2.2 M, with optimum growth at 0.08–0.4 M.  Yeast extract is required for growth.  Growth is very poor under anaerobic conditions in the presence of nitrate, but no growth occurs with DMSO, l-arginine, Na2S2O3 and Na2SO4.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite.  The major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol (PG1 and PG2), phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester (PGP-Me) and mannose-2,6-dissulfate (1-2)-glucose glycerol diether (S2-DGD).  Menaquinone MK-8 and MK-8(H2) are the major respiratory lipoquinones.  Oxidase and catalase positive.  Gelatine, starch, casein, arbutin, esculin, hippurate are degraded; DNA is not degraded.  Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and acid phosphatase positive in the API ZYM, other activities were negative.  Acetate, pyruvate, succinate, fumarate, glutamate, l-alanine, l-asparagine, l-lysine, proline, l-glutamine, l-arginine, l-serine, l-leucine, l-isoleucine, l-ornithine and threonine are assimilated.  d-Glucose, d-fructose, d-galactose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, l-fucose, l-sorbose, d-ribose, d-xylose, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, sucrose, maltose, lactose, d-cellobiose, d-trehalose, d-raffinose, d-melibiose, glycerol, ribitol, xylitol, sorbitol, d-mannitol, erythritol, myo-inositol, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, a-ketoglutarate, dl-lactate, malate, citrate, benzoate, formate, d-gluconate, d-glucoronate, aspartate, glycine, l-histidine, valine, l-phenylalanine and methionine are not assimilated.  Acid is produced from glycerol, d-ribose, d-xylose, l-xylose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-sorbose, methyl-ad-glucopyranoside, arbutin, esculin ferric citrate, salicin, d-cellobiose, d-maltose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose, d-turanose, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, potassium 2-ketogluconate and potassium 5-ketogluconate using the API 50 CH.  Susceptible to novobiocin, trimethoprim, anisomycin and aphidicolin; resistant to bacitracin, vancomicin, ampicillin, penicillin-G, erythromycin, rifamycin B, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, neomycin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, cyclohexamide, gramicidin, spectinomycin, phosphomycin and oxytetracycline.  The DNA of strain MDB25T has a G+C content of 63.0 mol% (HPLC method).  The type strain MDB25T (=DSM 25055T =JCM 17869T) was isolated from a sample of the anoxic brine of Lake Medee in the Mediterranean sea, in Italy.</description>
</treatment>
