<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Natrinema_ejinorense</taxon_name>
  <strain>EJ-57T (=CECT 7144T=JCM 13890T= CGMCC 1.6202T)</strain>
  <reference>Natrinema ejinorense sp. nov., isolated from a saline lake in Inner Mongolia, China IJSEM 56:2683-2687</reference>
  <file>Natrinema.ejinorense.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are non-motile and pleomorphic, with triangular, square, rod, disc and other polygonal shapes, and are 1.5–4.0 x 0.8–2.0 µm size.  Colonies are circular, smooth, entire, opaque, pale red pigmented and 0.5–1.5 mm in diameter after 5 days at 37˚C on plates containing 20% (w/v) total salts.  Extremely halophilic; cells lyse in water.  At least 1.8 M NaCl is required for growth (optimal growth at 3.4 M NaCl).  MgCl2 is not required for growth.  The pH and temperature ranges for growth are 6.0–8.5 (optimum at pH 7.0) and 25–50 ˚C (optimum at 37 ˚C), respectively.  Chemo-organotrophic.  Aerobic.  Oxidase- and catalase positive.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons’ citrate tests are negative.  Acid is not produced from lactose, glycerol, glucose, sucrose, fructose, arabinose, maltose, D-xylose, galactose, trehalose or mannose.  Does not grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate or L-arginine.  Starch, gelatin and Tween 80 are hydrolysed, but DNA and casein are not.  Does not produce arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase or ornithine decarboxylase.  Nitrate and nitrite are reduced and gas is produced from nitrite.  Utilizes glucose, fructose, glycerol, maltose, trehalose, starch, propionate, fumarate, acetate, threonine, asparagine and lysine as single carbon and energy sources for growth.  No growth is observed on mannitol, sorbitol, lactose, arabinose, galactose, mannose, raffinose, D-ribose, D-xylose, malate, succinate or glutamate.  The following compounds are not used as sole carbon, nitrogen or energy sources: isoleucine, L-serine and glycine.  Sensitive to bacitracin and novobiocin, but resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, penicillin G, rifampicin, streptomycin and tetracycline.  The major polar lipids are C20C20 and C20C25 derivates of phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester and the disulfated glycolipid, S2-DGA-1.  The G+C content of the DNA is 64.7 mol% (Tm).  The type strain, EJ-57T (=CECT 7144T=JCM 13890T= CGMCC 1.6202T), was isolated from saline Lake Ejinor, Inner Mongolia, China.  The urease test was negative.</description>
</treatment>
