<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Natronorubrum_sediminis</taxon_name>
  <strain>CG-6T (=CECT 7487T =CGMCC 1.8981T =JCM 15982T)</strain>
  <reference>Natronorubrum sediminis sp. nov., an archaeon isolated from a saline lake IJSEM 60:1802-1806</reference>
  <file>Natronorubrum.sediminis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, pleomorphic rods, 4.0–6.0 x 0.8–1.0 µm.  Colonies are circular, smooth, entire, of shining aspect, pink-pigmented and 1.0–4.0 mm in diameter after 10 days incubation at 37 ˚C on plates containing 20% (w/v) total salts.  Extremely halophilic; the cells lyse in water.  Growth occurs in 2.5–5.0 M NaCl and is optimal in 3.4 M NaCl.  MgCl2 is not required for growth.  The pH and temperature ranges for growth are pH 8.0– 11.0 (optimum at pH 9.0) and 25–50 ˚C (optimum at 37 ˚C).  Chemo-organotrophic, aerobic, and oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Indole is not produced from tryptophan.  Methyl red, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons’ citrate tests are negative.  Does not grow anaerobically in the presence of nitrate or L-arginine.  Starch, gelatin, DNA, aesculin and casein are not hydrolysed.  Urea and Tween 80 are hydrolysed.  Produces arginine dihydrolase and lysine decarboxylase, but not ornithine decarboxylase.  Nitrate is reduced to nitrite; gas is not produced from nitrite.  H2S is not produced from Na2S2O3.  Utilizes D-glucose, D-fructose, D-xylose, D-arabinose, D-mannose and L-asparagine.  No growth is observed on glycerol, maltose, trehalose, starch, propionate, fumarate, acetate, L-lysine, D-mannitol, D-sorbitol, lactose, D-galactose, raffinose, D-ribose, malate, succinate, glutamate, isoleucine, L-serine or glycine.  Sensitive to novobiocin (30 µg).  Resistant to ampicillin (10 µg), bacitracin (10 U), chloramphenicol (30 µg), erythromycin (15 µg), gentamicin (10 µg), nalidixic acid (30 µg), neomycin (10 µg), penicillin G (10 U), rifampicin (30 µg), streptomycin (10 µg) and tetracycline (30 µg).  The polar lipids are C20C20 and C20C25 derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol and phosphatidylglycerol phosphate methyl ester.  No glycolipids are detected.  The DNA G+C content is 61.9–62.5 mol% (Tm).  The type strain is CG-6T (=CECT 7487T =CGMCC 1.8981T =JCM 15982T), isolated from sediment of the saline Lake Chagannor in Inner Mongolia, China.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 62.5 mol%.</description>
</treatment>
