<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Natronolimnobius_baerhuensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>IHC-005T (=CGMCC 1.3597T =JCM 12253T)</strain>
  <reference>Natronolimnobius baerhuensis gen. nov., sp. nov. and Natronolimnobius innermongolicus sp. nov., novel haloalkaliphilic archaea isolated from soda lakes in Inner Mongolia, China Extremophiles 9;111-116</reference>
  <file>Natronolimnobius.baerhuensis.innermongolicus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, and motile.  Cells were ca. 0.5 x 3-5 µm wide.  Cells lyse in distilled water or in dilute medium containing less than 0.5 M NaCl.  Colonies are bright red, translucent, circular, 0.3-0.5 mm in diameter, raised or convex.  Grows between pH 7.0 and 10.0, with an optimum at pH 9, and between 30 and 46 ˚C, with an optimum at 37 ˚C.  Requires at least 15% NaCl for growth with an optimum 20%, is chemoorganotrophic and aerobic.  Forms sulfides from thiosulfate, but not sulfur.  Produces indole.  Hydrolyses Tween 80 but not starch, casein, or gelatin.  Utilizes arabinose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, raffinose, xylose, acetate, fumarate, and pyruvate.  Unknown phospholipid may be present.  Sensitive to anisomycin, aphidicolin, bacitracin, erthromycin, novobiocin, rifampicin, but not ampicillin, chloramphenicol, neomycin, or penicillin.  The DNA G+C content is 59–60%.  The type strain is IHC-005T (=CGMCC 1.3597T =JCM 12253T).  No gas vacuoles.  Strictly aerobic and never showed growth in an anaerobic medium containing nitrate, arginine, DMSO, or trimethylamine N-oxide.  Oxidase- and catalase-positive.  Did not utilize D-ribose, starch mannitol, glycine, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-asparagine, L-glutamic acid, sorbitol, citric acid, propionic acid, L-ornithine, or L-lysine.  Diphytanyl (C20:C20) and phytanyl-sesterterpanyl (C20:C25) moieties of phosphatidylglycerol, and phosphatidylglycerophosphate methyl ester as major polar lipid components.</description>
</treatment>
