<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Natrialba_aegyptiaca</taxon_name>
  <strain>40T = DSM 13077T = JCM 11194T</strain>
  <reference>Transfer of Natrialba asiatica B1T to Natrialba taiwanensis sp. nov. and description of Natrialba aegyptiaca sp. nov., a novel extremely halophilic, aerobic, non-pigmented member of the Archaea from Egypt that produces extracellular poly(glutamic acid) IJSEM 51:1133-1142</reference>
  <file>Natrialba.taiwanensis.aegyptica.pdf</file>
  <description>Generally non-pigmented, but slightly pigmented under certain conditions, especially when the agar basal medium plus 1% (w/v) sodium acetate is used as carbon and energy sources or after long periods on isolation and maintenance media.  Cells are either rods, 0.5-1.2 x 1.5-6 µm, or cocci and tetrads, individual cells measuring 0.5-2.0 µm in diameter; cells are pleomorphic, especially under suboptimal conditions.  Cocci and coccobacilli dominate when acetate or gluconate is added to the basal medium as carbon and energy source.  Gram-negative; rods are motile.  The optimal temperature for growth is 37-42 °C, with a maximum at 60 °C.  The pH range for growth is pH 6.9, with an optimum in the range pH 7.8.  The NaCl range for growth is 1.6 M to saturation, with an optimum in the range 2.5-3.0 M.  NaCl may be replaced to a large extent by KCl.  Aerobic, catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Acid is produced from xylose, arabinose, glucose, sucrose, maltose, lactose (weak) and starch.  Strongly amylolytic; casein and gelatin are also hydrolysed.  Tweens 20, 40 and 80 as well as egg yolk (lecithin) are hydrolysed.  Produces an exopolymer, which is composed of l-glutamic acid (85% w/w), carbohydrates (12.5% w/w) and unidentified compounds (2.5% w/w).  Isolated from a salt soil close to Aswan, Egypt.  The type strain is strain 40T, which has been deposited in the DSMZ as DSM 13077T and in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, Wako, Saitama, Japan, as JCM 11194T.  Presence of diether-linked isoprenoid lipids and no evidence for the presence of fatty acids was obtained.  In addition, it was possible to show that strain 40T produced phytanyl-phytanyl (C20:C20) and sesterpanyl-phytanyl (C25:C20) diethers.  Susceptible to fucidic acid, bactracin, nitrofurantoin, novobiocin, anisomycin, trimethoprim, and rifampicin.  Resistant to nystatin, tetracycline, nalidixic acid, erythromycin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin, and penicillin G.</description>
</treatment>
