<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Natrinema_versiforme</taxon_name>
  <strain>XF10T (=JCM 10478T=AS 1.2365T=ANMR 0149T)</strain>
  <reference>Natrinema versiforme sp. nov., an extremely halophilic archaeon from Aibi salt lake, Xinjiang, China IJSEM 50:1297-1303</reference>
  <file>Natrinema.versiforme.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells non-motile and pleomorphic.  Lyse in dilute medium containing less than 1.0 M NaCl or in distilled water.  Colonies light red, 0.5-1.0 mm in diameter, smooth, circular and elevated.  Requires at least 1.5 M NaCl for growth; optimum 3.4-4.3 M (in the presence of 0.15 M MgCl2).  Growth occurs at 0.005-0.5 M MgCl2; optimum around 0.15 M.  Temperature range for growth 20-53 °C, optimum 37-46 °C.  pH range for growth 6.0-8.0; optimum 6.5-7.0.  Chemo-organotrophic.  Anaerobic growth in the presence of nitrate.  Carbon sources: Casamino acids and several sugars, such as fructose, glucose, glycerol (with strong acid formation), galactose, maltose, mannose, d-ribose, sucrose and d-xylose, but not lactose.  Reduces nitrate and forms gas.  Forms sulfide from sulfur or thiosulfate.  Forms indole.  Does not hydrolyse gelatin or casein.  Starch hydrolysis doubtful and weak hydrolysis of Tween 80.  Possesses C20C20 and C20C25 diether core lipids and some unidentified glycolipids.  Possesses phospholipids: PG, PGP-Me and PGS.  Sensitive to anisomycin, bacitracin, novobiocin and rifampicin.  Insensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, neomycin and penicillin G.  Type strain: XF10T (=JCM 10478T=AS 1.2365T=ANMR 0149T). There were no gas vesicles formed inside cells.  Showed anaerobic growth in the presence of nitrate but not arginine, DMSO or TMAO. It exhibited positive catalase and oxidase reactions. Indole was formed. There was no hydrolysis of gelatin or casein, although weak hydrolysis of Tween 80 occurred.  Hydrolysis of starch was doubtful. The strain did not utilize arabinose, lactose, mannitol, raffinose, rhamnose or sorbitol.  Isolated from a neutral salt lake in the northwest part of China.  Possesses glycerol diether analogues of phosphatidylglercerol (PG), phosphatidylglycerophosphatemethyl ester (PGP-Me), phosphatidylglycerosulfate (PGS) and some glycolipids. The core lipids were C20C20 and C20C25 diethers.</description>
</treatment>
