<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Natronoarchaeum_mannanilyticum</taxon_name>
  <strain>YSM-123T (=JCM 16328T =CECT 7565T),</strain>
  <reference>Natronoarchaeum mannanilyticum gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic, extremely halophilic archaeon isolated from commercial salt IJSEM 60:2529-2534</reference>
  <file>Natronoarchaeum.mannanilyticum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile and extremely pleomorphic.  Colonies on agar are small and are pigmented clear red.  Chemo-organotrophic, aerobic, halophilic and slightly alkaliphilic, requiring at least 2 M NaCl for growth.  The major polar lipids are phosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylglycerophosphate methyl ester and disulfated diglycosyl diether (S2-DGD).  Cells are typically 1–5 µm in diameter in liquid medium.  Cells lyse in distilled water.  On agar medium, under optimal conditions, forms clear red microcolonies (0.5–1.0 mm in diameter after 10 days of growth at 37 ˚C).  Grows in 2.0–5.3 (saturated) M NaCl (optimum 4.0–4.5 M), at pH 5.8–9.5 (optimum pH 8.0– 9.0) and at 20–55 ˚C (optimum 37 ˚C).  Mg2+ is required for growth, with maximum growth at 5 mM.  Catalase- and oxidase-negative.  Does not reduce nitrate to nitrite.  Anaerobic growth does not occur with nitrate, arginine or DMSO.  Indole production from tryptophan is positive.  Susceptible to bacitracin, novobiocin and rifampicin and resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, penicillin, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.  Utilizes cellobiose, glucose, lactose, mannose, raffinose, locust-bean gum, yeast extract, Casamino acids, peptone, sodium glutamate and pyruvic acid as single or complex carbon sources for growth.  Hydrolyses starch.  Does not hydrolyse gelatin, Tween 80 or casein.  Contains an unknown glycolipid in addition to the polar lipids described for the genus.  The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 63 mol% as determined by HPLC.  The type strain, YSM-123T (=JCM 16328T =CECT 7565T), was isolated from a commercial salt sample made in Niigata prefecture, Japan.</description>
</treatment>
