<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Lisa Moore">
  <taxon_name>Nostoc.sp.PCC7107</taxon_name>
  <strain>PCC 1707</strain>
  <reference>Metabolites Produced by Nitrogen-Fixing Nostoc Species (Dembitsky, V., Rezanka, T., 2004)</reference>
  <DOI>NA</DOI>
  <file>Dembitsky, V. Nostoc.sp.PCC7107.pdf</file>
  <description>Members of the order Nostocales are broadly characterized by unbranched filaments and the production of up to three kinds of differentiated cells. Nostoc species are nitrogen-fixing cyanobacteria. Heterocysts differentiate in response to the lack of combined nitrogen in the environment and are the sites of nitrogen fixation. Nostoc species also produce relatively short, motile filaments called hormogonia and this characteristic, in part, distinguishes them from members of the closely related genus Anabaena. In addition, Nostoc species differentiate spore-like structures termed akinetes in response to nutrient limitation other than nitrogen. Nostoc species are widely distributed in illuminated portions of the biosphere, including fresh waters and tropical, temperate, and polar terrestrial systems; they are rarely found in marine habitats. Growth in both aquatic and terrestrial habitats is often as a colony of filaments within a gelatinous matrix. Many Nostoc  species occur in symbiotic associations with fungi to form lichens and with representatives of each of the major phylogenetic groups of plants. Nitrogen-fixing Nostoc  species, in both free-living and symbiotic growth states, are major contributors to the sequestration of CO2  in organic compounds, especially in nutrient poor and extreme environments. Nostoc species are terrestrial and benthic cosmopolitan microorganisms, which form extended mucilaginous layers on soil and in the aquatic environment on stones and mud. Many secondary metabolites with new structures have been isolated from these organisms. In nature, these components may be directed against phototrophic competitors (cyanobacteria and algae) and grazers. The pharmacological value of these substances is that they have been shown to exhibit antiviral and antitumor properties, and Nostoc , as cyanobacteria in general, have gained much interest as a natural source of such compounds.</description>
</treatment>
