<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Palaeococcus_ferrophilus</taxon_name>
  <strain>DMJT = JCM 10246T</strain>
  <reference>Palaeococcus ferrophilus gen. nov., sp. nov., a barophilic, hyperthermophilic archaeon from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent chimney IJSEM 50:489-500</reference>
  <file>Palaeococcus.ferrophilus.pdf</file>
  <description>Irregular cocci, 0.5-2.0 µm in diameter.  Cells occur singly or in pairs.  Exhibits high motility with multiple flagella.  Strictly anaerobic.  The temperature range for growth is 60-88 °C with the optimum being 83 °C.  The pH range for growth is from 4.0 to 8.0, with optimum growth occurring at pH 6.0.  Sea salts in the concentration range of 20-73 g per liter are required for growth, with optimum growth occurring at 43 g per liter.  The optimum hydrostatic pressure for growth is 30 MPa.  Growth using yeast extract, peptone, tryptone or casein occurs in the presence of elemental sulfur (S˚) or ferrous iron (Fe2+) as a required cofactor.  Major core lipids are C40 tetraether (&gt;80%) and C20 diether lipids (&lt;20%).  The G+C content of genomic DNA is about 53.5 mol% (HPLC).  Isolated from a black smoker sample obtained from the Myojin Knoll in the Ogasawara-Bonin Arc, Japan, at a depth of 1338 m.  The type strain of Palaeococcus ferrophilus is strain DMJT, which has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms, Institute of Physical and Chemical Research (RIKEN), Wako-shi, Saitama, Japan, under accession number JCM 10246T. Did not grow in a medium consisting only of synthetic sea water and organic substrates such as yeast extract and Trypticase peptone.  Able to use nitrate as an electron acceptor and to form ammonium in the presence of iron, whereas nitrate reduction was not absolutely required for growth.  In the absence or presence of NaNO3, H2 was produced during growth and no H2S was detected.  Nitrate reduction was not associated with iron oxidation.  Organic substrates that served to support heterotrophic growth were determined in the presence of ferrous iron or elemental sulfur as cofactors for growth.  In either case, the isolate grew only in media containing proteinaceous substrates such as yeast extract, Trypticase peptone, tryptone or casein.  No growth occurred with starch, Casamino acids, any of various sugars (maltotriose, cellobiose, maltose, lactose, trehalose, sucrose, glucose, galactose, fructose or xylose), organic acids (tartrate, succinate, propionate, 2-aminobutyric acid, malate, lactate, pyruvate or acetate) or amino acids.  Resistant to vancomycin, streptomycin, chloramphenicol, and rifampicin.</description>
</treatment>
