<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Picrophilus_oshimae</taxon_name>
  <strain>KAW2/2 = DSM 9789</strain>
  <reference>Picrophilus gen. nov., fam. nov.: a Novel Aerobic, Heterotrophic, Thermoacidophilic Genus and Family Comprising Archaea Capable of Growth around pH 0 J Bact 177:7050-7059</reference>
  <file>Picrophilus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells were irregular cocci of around 1 to 1.5 µm in diameter.  The cells showed an envelope in the form of an S-layer situated on top of the cytoplasmic membrane.  Pilli or flagella have not been observed.  The organism grew heterotrophically under aerobic conditions on 0.2% yeast extract, with a generation time of 8 h.  The addition of glucose, sucrose, or lactose to the medium resulted in slightly slower growth.  No growth occurred on starch, glucose, sucrose, or lactose alone, on Casamino Acids, or when these carbon sources were supplemented with vitamins.  On tryptone, poor growth occurred.  Tryptone compounds inhibited growth.  Growth was inhibited by the addition of 0.2 M sodium chloride to the medium.  No growth was observed under aerobic conditions with CO2 as the sole carbon source and sulfur as the energy source.  Under anaerobic conditions on yeast extract with and without sulfur and CO2 or under conditions for chemolithoautotrophic growth with sulfur and H2 as the energy source and CO2 as the carbon source, no growth was observed.  Grew between 45 and 65˚C, with an optimum at 60˚C.  The organisms grew only below pH 3.5, the optimal pH was 0.7.  Even at a pH around 0, significant growth was observed.  The inocula used for these experiments were from late-logarithmic-phase cultures grown under optimal conditions.  Significant growth was observed even upon addition of 1.2 M sulfuric acid, pH -0.06.  Resistant to rifampin, chloramphenicol, streptomycin, novobiocin, bacitracin, and vancomycin.  The major core lipid obtained after methanolysis of the polar lipids was caldarchaeol, containing 0+0, 0+1, 1+1, 1+2, 2+2, and 3+2 cyclopentane rings, with mainly 0+0 and 1+2 rings.  A trace of archaeol was also found.  The abundant polar lipids were a glycolipid (Rf, 0.93), identified as a b-glucosyl derivative of caldarchaeol, and a phosphoglycolipid (Rf, 0.35), with the latter containing the same sugar moiety, although the phospho- head has not yet been identified. Isolated from a dry, hot soil (obviously a dried small solfataric field) in the vicinity of Kawayu, Hokkaido, northern Japan.</description>
</treatment>
