<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Pyrobaculum_aerophilum</taxon_name>
  <strain>IM2 = DSM 7523</strain>
  <reference>Pyrobaculum aerophilum sp. nov., a Novel Nitrate-Reducing Hyperthermophilic Archaeum AEM 59:2918-2926</reference>
  <file>Pyrobaculum.aerophilum.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells usually between 3 and 8 µm long; cylinder-shaped rods with a width of 0.6 µm.  Motile by monopolar flagellation.  Cells with terminal spheres occur mainly in the stationary-growth phase, at high nitrite concentrations, or at pH values above 8.  Spheres can enlarge, producing coccoid cell forms.  Colonies greyish yellow, round with a rough surface.  Anaerobically grown, packed cell masses exhibit a deep green color; aerobically grown cells exhibit a brownish yellow color.  Growth between 75 and 104°C (optimum, 100°C), at pH 5.8 to 9 (optimum, 7.0), and at 0 to 3.6% NaCl (optimum, 1.5%).  Optimal doubling time, 180 min.  Heterotrophic growth on yeast extract, meat extract, tryptone, peptone, gelatin, casein, Casamino Acids, propionate, and acetate.  Autotrophic growth by oxidation of hydrogen or thiosulfate.  Oxygen, nitrate, and nitrite are possible electron acceptors.  Nitrite and dinitrogen are products of dissimilatory nitrate reduction (denitrification).  Growth inhibition by elemental sulfur.  Aerobically grown cells exhibit catalase-positive reaction.  Cell wall composed of a protein surface layer, exhibiting p6 symmetry and a center-to-center distance of approximately 30 nm between neighboring protein complexes.  Core lipids mainly glycerol diphytanyl glycerol tetraethers with varying degrees of cyclization.  DNA base composition, 52 mol% G+C. Type strain: Pyrobaculum aerophilum IM2, DSM 7523, Braunschweig, Germany (isolated at Maronti Beach, Ischia, Italy).  Does not utilize starch, sucrose, glucose, lactose, ribose, pyruvate, sulfite, or sulfur.  Does not grow on sulfur and yeast extract.  Cells are insensitive to penicillin G, streptomycin, phosphomycin, vancomycin, and chloramphenicol.  Sensitive to rifampin.</description>
</treatment>
