<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Pyrococcus_abyssi</taxon_name>
  <strain>GE5 = CNCM 1-1302</strain>
  <reference>Pyrococcus abyssi sp. nov., a new hyperthermophilic archaeon isolated from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent Arch Microbiol 160:338-349</reference>
  <file>Pyrococcus.abyssi.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are gram-negative, slightly irregular cocci, variable in size (usually 0.8 to 2 µm) and shape depends upon growth conditions, type strain (GE5) is highly motile by means of a polar tuft of flagella.  Cell envelope consists of a double- S-layer.  Cell division occurs by constriction.  Obligate anaerobe.  Grows optimally at 0.2-0.3% NaC1, and pH around 7.0.  At atmospheric pressure, growth occurs between 67˚C and 102˚C (Optimum 96˚C corresponding to 33 min doubling time).  Facultatively barophilic: elevated hydrostatic pressures significantly extend upper growth temperature and stimulates growth.  Habitat: anaerobic hot sites of deep-sea hydrothermal systems.  Barotolerant to facultatively barophilic.  Obligate chemoorganotroph, fermenting proteolysis products (e.g. tryptones and gelatin), and mixtures of amino acids and pyruvate in presence of vitamins in H2, CO2, and volatile fatty acids.  H2 produced inhibits growth, but this can be alleviated by addition of S˚, cystine, or polysulfides.  In this case, H2S and mercaptans are produced.  Membrane lipids are composed mainly of tetraether lipids with 0 to 4 cyclopentane rings in the isoprenoid chains.  G + C content is 45%.  Isolated from hot fluid from an active chimney in the North Fiji Basin (SW Pacific).  Type strain is P.  abyssi, GE5, CNCM 1-1302, Collection Nationale de Culture de Microorganismes, Institut Pasteur, Paris, France.  NH4Cl, nitrate, nitrogen, tryptone, gelatine, urea, glutamate, amino acids, yeast extract and peptone could serve as nitrogen sources.  Nitrite and ferric iron could not serve as electron acceptors.  The following could not be utilized: glucose, galactose, sorbose, fructose, sucrose, xylose, arabinose, mannose, raffinose, melibiose, maltose, lactose, starch, glycogen, pure agar, alginates, carraghenans, mannitol, sorbitol, ethanol, isopropanol, methanol, acetate, lactate, citrate, benzoate, formate, gluconate, malate, 2-methylbutyrate, 3-methylbutyrate, lsovalerate, propionate, succinate, methylamines and all the amino acids tested alone.  Resistant to chloramphenicol, vancomycin, penicillin, streptomycin, and rifampicin.</description>
</treatment>
