<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Salarchaeum_japonicum</taxon_name>
  <strain>YSM-79T (=JCM 16327T =CECT 7563T)</strain>
  <reference>Salarchaeum japonicum gen. nov., sp. nov., an aerobic, extremely halophilic member of the Archaea isolated from commercial salt IJSEM 61:2266-2270</reference>
  <file>Salarchaeum.japonicum.pdf</file>
  <description>The description of Salarchaeum japonicum is as that given above for the genus, with the following additions.  Cells are Gram-negative, motile, short rods, 0.5–1.0 x 0.5– 2.0 µm in liquid media.  On agar plates, under optimal conditions clear red microcolonies are formed (0.1 mm in diameter after 1 week growth at 37 ˚C).  Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1.5–5.3 M (saturated), optimum 2.5– 3.0 M; at pH 5.0–8.8, optimum pH 5.2–6.3; and at 20–55 ˚C, optimum 40 ˚C.  Mg2+ is required for growth, with maximum growth occurring at 200–300 mM.  Cells lyse in distilled water.  Catalase- and oxidase-positive.  Does not reduce nitrate or nitrite under aerobic conditions.  Anaerobic growth with nitrate, arginine and DMSO does not occur.  Indole production from tryptophan is negative.  H2S production from thiosulfate or cysteine is negative.  Susceptible to novobiocin; resistant to ampicillin, anisomycin, bacitracin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, penicillin, rifampicin, streptomycin, tetracycline and vancomycin.  Utilizes sodium fumarate, sodium malate, sodium succinate, sodium glutamate, yeast extract, Casamino acids, peptone, and neopeptone as single or complex carbon sources for growth.  Does not utilize arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, glycerol, inositol, lactose, maltose, mannitol, mannose, raffinose, ribitol, ribose, sodium acetate, sodium citrate, sodium pyruvate, sodium lactate, sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, xylose, glycine, L-alanine, L-arginine chloride, L-lysine chloride, sodium L-aspartate or Bacto peptone.  Hydrolyses Tween 80.  Does not hydrolyse starch, gelatin or casein.  The following enzymic activities are positive: esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14, weak), alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, trypsin and a-chymotrypsin.  Ornithine decarboxylase, lysine decarboxylase, valine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, a-galactosidase, b-galactosidase, b-glucuronidase, a-glucosidase, b-glucosidase, N-acetyl-b-glucosaminidase, a-mannosidase and a-fucosidase activities are negative.  The type strain is YSM-79T (=JCM 16327T =CECT 7563T), isolated from commercial salt made from seawater in Yonaguni island, Okinawa, Japan.  Its DNA G+C content is 64 mol% as determined by HPLC.  Contained the diether derivatives of phosphatidylglycerol (PG) and phosphatidylglycerophosphate methyl ester (PGP-Me), sulfated diglycosyl diether-1 (S-DGD-1) and five unidentified glycolipids.</description>
</treatment>
