<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Lisa Moore">
  <taxon_name>Spirulina_subsalsa</taxon_name>
  <strain>CCC Baja-95 Cl. 2T</strain>
  <reference>The halotolerance and phylogeny of cyanobacteria with tightly coiled trichomes (Spirulina Turpin) and the description of Halospirulina tapeticola gen. nov., sp. nov. (Nubel, U., et al., 2000)</reference>
  <DOI>NA</DOI>
  <file>Nubel, U. et al. Spirulina subsalsa.pdf</file>
  <description>tightly coiled trichomes, halotolerant, Cyanobacteria with tightly coiled trichomes are frequently found in thermal freshwater environments as well as in brackish, marine and hypersaline waters, Under favourable conditions they can form dense benthic populations and make major contributions to primary productivity., they are traditionally considered cosmopolitan micro-organisms with remarkable capabilities to acclimatize to broad ranges of environmental conditions, euryhaline cyanobacteria, from hypersaline waters, In contrast, three strains from hypersaline environments at 25 °C grew at salinities from 3±2 % (CCC Baja-95 Cl. 2T, CCC Baja-95 Cl. 3)., In strain CCC Baja-95 Cl. 2T, elevated temperature (38 °C) resulted in increased growth rates at high salinities and an increased upper salinity limit of growth (20%)., extremely euryhaline and were among the most halotolerant cyanobacteria that have been described, tolerated 40 or 38 °C, respectively, and did not grow at 15 °C and below. Thus they displayed a slightly elevated temperature requirement compared to the normal salinity marine strains, most of which tolerated 10± 35 °C. Similarly, this characteristic was found in unicellular cyanobacteria from hypersaline environments and might be an adaptation to life in brines with low heat capacity which may easily reach high temperatures when sunlit., contained phycocyanin, CCC Baja-95 Cl. 2T produced aphanyzophyll and an unidentified carotenoid with an absorption maximum at 480 nm instead of myxoxanthophyll (l-chinovosemyxol)and canthaxanthin,</description>
</treatment>
