<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Stygiolobus_azoricus</taxon_name>
  <strain>FC6 (= DSM 6296)</strain>
  <reference>Stygiolobus azoricus gen. nov., sp. nov. Represents a Novel Genus of Anaerobic, Extremely Thermoacidophilic Archaebacteria of the Order Sulfolobales IJSB 41:495-501</reference>
  <file>Stygiolobus.azoricus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are about 0.5 to 1.8 µm wide and occur almost exclusively singly under optimal culture conditions.  Under suboptimal conditions, especially at an elevated pH of &gt;4, aggregates of 2 to 50 cells occur commonly.  Cells are frequently surrounded by pilus- or fimbria-like appendages.  No flagellation has been detected.  No motility is evident in a microscopic chamber either at room temperature or at 75°C.  The envelope surrounding the cells is about 22 nm wide.  Packed cells are black.  Growth is strictly chemolithotrophic by means of H2-S˚ lithoautotrophy.  Trace amounts of yeast extract (0.005 to 0.02%) stimulate growth.  Cells grow at temperatures ranging from about 57 to 89˚C, with optimal growth occurring around 80°C.  No growth is detected at 50°C (incubation time 3 weeks) and 89°C.  The pH suitable for growth ranges from 1.0 to 5.5, with optimum growth around pH 2.5 to 3.  Cultures of isolate FC6T can be used for at least 1 year as inocula when they are stored anaerobically at 4°C after the pH is increased to 5.5 by adding sterile CaCO3.  Cells lyse at pH values above 7.5 to 8.  Isolated were obtained from hot water, mud, and soil at acidic geothermal springs on S5o Miguel Island, Azores.  The type strain is isolate FC6 (= DSM 6296).  Sulfur could not be replaced by sulfite, tetrathionate, L-cystine, or sulfate.  Amino acids, D-ribose, D-fructose, D-glucose, D-xylose, L-sorbose, maltose, sucrose, starch, acetate, meat extract, Casamino Acids, yeast extract, peptone, and tryptone could not be used as electron donors.  Trace amounts of yeast extract, meat extract, tryptone, peptone or Casamino Acids raised the growth yield significantly.  Could not grow aerobically or microaerobically.  Incapable of oxidizing S˚ to H2SO4.  Cannot use nitrate, Fe(III) or KH2PO4 as electron acceptors.  Incapable of growing by anaerobic S˚C oxidation.  The purified DNA has a G+C content of about 38 mol %.  Occurrence of isopranyl ether lipids in their cells.  Cells are strongly lobed or have sharp edges and bends.  Cells are strictly anaerobic, chemolithotrophic thermoacidophiles that thrive by means of S˚ reduction with H2.  Neither muramic acid nor rneso-diaminopimelic acid is present, indicating the absence of murein.  Elongation factor EF-G is sensitive to adenosine diphosphate ribosylation by diphtheria toxin.  Cells contain glycerol-dibisphytanyl-nonitol tetraether lipids and sulfolobusquinone.  No caldariellaquinone has been detected.  The organisms are resistant to vancomycin, ampicillin, and kanamycin.</description>
</treatment>
