<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Sulfolobus_tokodaii</taxon_name>
  <strain>7T = JCM 10545</strain>
  <reference>Sulfolobus tokodaii sp. nov. (f. Sulfolobus sp. strain 7), a new member of the genus Sulfolobus isolated from Beppu Hot Springs, Japan Extremophiles 6:39-44</reference>
  <file>Sulfolobus.tokodaii.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are irregular cocci and variable in size (usually 0.5– 0.8 µm in diameter) and have some flattened and uneven surfaces.  The cell envelope consists of a hexagonal S-layer lattice (spacing approximately 20 nm).  Colonies are pale tan, translucent, smooth, and convex, with entire margins.  Cells grow chemoheterotrophically on a modified Brock’s basal salts mixture supplied with tryptone, yeast extract, casamino acid, or amino acids under obligatory aerobic conditions.  Best growth occurs on a modified Brock’s basal salts mixture supplied with yeast extract, casamino acid, and glucose.  Supplements of elemental sulfur are not required for the chemoheterotrophic growth.  Poor growth occurs under facultatively chemolithotrophic conditions in the presence of elemental sulfur when supplied with alanine or polypeptone.  No growth occurs in minimal medium amended with a H2/CO2 (90:10) headspace.  Growth occurs at 70° to 85°C; optimal growth is at 80°C under aerobic and chemoheterotrophic growth conditions.  Growth occurs at pH 2 to 5; optimal growth is at pH 2.5–3.  No growth was detected at pH 1 or pH 6.  It is an obligately aerobic and facultatively chemoheterotrophic thermoacidophile that grows by aerobic respiration rather than by simple fermentation.  The G + C content of the genomic DNA is 32.8 mol%, as calculated from its whole genomic DNA sequence.  The type strain is Sulfolobus tokodaii sp. strain 7T, which was isolated from the Beppu Hot Springs in the continental acidic geothermal area of Kyushu Island, Japan, and it has been deposited in the Japan Collection of Microorganisms as strain JCM 10545.  No autotrophic growth in minimal media supplemented with elemental sulfur.</description>
</treatment>
