<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermogymnomonas_acidicola</taxon_name>
  <strain>IC-189T (=JCM 13583T=DSM 18835T)</strain>
  <reference>Thermogymnomonas acidicola gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel thermoacidophilic, cell wall-less archaeon in the order Thermoplasmatales, isolated from a solfataric soil in Hakone, Japan IJSEM 57:2557-2561</reference>
  <file>Thermogymnomonas.acidicola.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are pleomorphic, predominantly comprising irregular cocci that range from 1.0 to 3.0 µm in diameter.  Cells lack a cell wall and are surrounded by a thin membrane (approx.  10 nm thick).  Buds (daughter cells) are sometimes associated with cells.  Pili are present.  Non-motile.  On solid medium, small colourless colonies with a ‘fried-egg’ appearance are formed.  Strictly aerobic.  Acidophilic and moderately thermophilic.  Heterotrophic, requiring yeast extract for growth.  Growth is inhibited by erythromycin, novobiocin and rifampicin.  Lipids predominantly comprise tetraethers; MK-7 is the major respiratory quinone.  The DNA G+C content is 56 mol%.  Growth occurs at temperatures in the range 38– 68 ˚C (optimum, 60 ˚C) and at pH 1.8–4.0 (optimum, pH 3.0).  Yeast extract, as well as glucose and mannose (in the presence of yeast extract), serve as carbon and energy sources.  NaCl is tolerated at concentrations up to 2.5 %.  The DNA G+C content DNA is 56.1 mol%.  The type strain, IC-189T (=JCM 13583T=DSM 18835T), was isolated from a sample of solfataric soil collected from Ohwaku-dani, Hakone, Japan.  Did not grow anaerobically, even in the presence of sulfur, nitrate, or ferric iron. Unable to utilize arabinose, fructose, galactose, lactose, maltose, D-ribose, sucrose, xylose, starch, glycogen, acetate, butyrate, citrate, formate, fumarate, L-lactate, malate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, methanol, ethanol, formamide, methylamine, trimethylamine, gelatin, beef extract, peptone, malt extract, tryptone, or a mixture of amino acids.  Glutamate supported weak growth.  Addition of FeSO4 was inhibitory to growth.  Insensitive to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, oleandomycin, penicillin, streptomycin, and vancomycin.</description>
</treatment>
