<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermosphaera_aggregans</taxon_name>
  <strain>M11TLT = DSM 11486</strain>
  <reference>Sulfur-inhibited Thermosphaera aggregans sp. nov., a new genus of hyperthermophilic archaea isolated after its prediction from environmentally derived 16s rRNA sequences IJSB 48:31-38</reference>
  <file>Thermosphaera.aggregans.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are cocci from 0.2 to 0.8 µm in diameter, occurring singly, in pairs, in short chains and in grapelike aggregates.  During growth, aggregates up to 10 pm with several hundred individuals visible.  Cell aggregates exhibit a bluish-green fluorescence at 420 nm.  Spores are not formed.  Flagella present.  Cell envelope composed of a cytoplasmic membrane (width: 4 nm), covered by an amorphous layer, 10-15 nm thick.  No evidence for a regular arrayed surface-layer protein.  Core lipids consist mainly of acyclic and cyclic glycerol diphytanyl glycerol tetraethers with one to four pentacyclic rings.  Growth between 67 and 90 ˚C (optimum: 85 ˚C), pH 5.0-7.0 (optimum: 6.5) and 0-0.7 % NaCl (optimum: 0 %).  Optimal doubling time 110 min.  Anaerobic.  Heterotrophic growth with yeast extract.  Peptone stimulates growth.  CO2, H2, acetate and isovalerate formed as metabolic products.  Growth inhibition by sulfur or hydrogen.  G+C content 46 mol%.  The type strain is isolate M11TLT, DSM 11486, Braunschweig, Germany (isolated from ' Obsidian Pool' in the Mud Volcano area of Yellowstone National Park, WY, USA).  No autotrophic growth.  No growth on native xylan or xylose.  Growth took place on heat-treated xylan.  Growth was observed on gelatin, on a mixture of amino acids, and on glucose.  No growth on meat extract, bovine heart infusion peptone, amylose, glycogen, cellulose, cellobiose, maltose, raffinose, pyruvate, and acetate.  When sulfur was present, H2S was formed in large amounts, resulting in growth inhibition.  Core lipids mainly acyclic and cyclic glycerol diphytanyl tetraethers with one to four pentacyclic rings.  Traces of glycerol diphytanyl diethers were also detected.</description>
</treatment>
