<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermococcus_barophilus</taxon_name>
  <strain>MPT = CNCM I- 1946</strain>
  <reference>Thermococcus barophilus sp. nov., a new barophilic and hyperthermophilic archaeon isolated under high hydrostatic pressure from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent IJSB 49:351-359</reference>
  <file>Thermococcus.barophilus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are regular to irregular cocci and variable in size (usually 0.8-2-0 µm).  The cell envelope consists of a hexagonal S-layer lattice (spacing 28-4 nm).  Cell division occurs by constriction.  Obligate anaerobe.  Growth was observed at pH 4.5-9.5 and salt concentrations of 1-4% NaCl.  Grows optimally at 2-3% (w/v) NaCl and pH 7.0.  At atmospheric pressure, growth occurs at 48-95 ˚C, with optimum growth temperature at 85 ˚C under 0.3 MPa hydrostatic pressure.  High hydrostatic pressure (40 MPa) stimulates growth at 75, 80, 85, 90 and 95 ˚C with an optimum growth temperature of 85 ˚C.  Obligately barophilic between 95 and 100 ˚C and requires 15.0-175 MPa to grow at these temperatures.  Obligately chemo-organotrophic.  Grows on complex organic compounds such as tryptone, beef extract, casein, Casamino acids, yeast extract or peptone.  Sulfur is not necessary for growth, but greatly enhances growth and can be replaced by cystine.  Membrane lipids are composed of one major phospholipid and an archaeol component.  The G + C content is 37.1 mol%.   Isolated from a chimney wall, under 40 MPa hydrostatic pressure at 95 ˚C, from the Mid- Atlantic Ridge, Snakepit at depth of 3550 m.  The type strain is Thermococcus barophilus MPT [CNCM I- 1946 (Collection Nationale de Cultures de Microorganismes, Institut Pasteur, Paris, France)].  Strain MPT appeared to be an obligate heterotroph.  No growth was detected in minimal medium amended with vitamins and with a H2/CO2 headspace.  Optimal growth requirements were determined in the presence of S˚, although S˚ was not required for growth and could be replaced by cystine.  Pyruvate and propionate supported poor growth.  Other substrates tested, such as starch, maltose, glycogen, sucrose, glucose and acetate, did not give any growth.  The strain grew best with NH4Cl as a nitrogen source, but some growth occurred with thiourea, glutamate, KNO3 and KNO2.  The new isolate was insensitive to penicillin and streptomycin, but sensitive to chloramphenicol and rifampicin.</description>
</treatment>
