<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermococcus_atlanticus</taxon_name>
  <strain>MA898 = CIP-107420T = DSM15226</strain>
  <reference>Thermococcus atlanticus sp. nov., a hyperthermophilic Archaeon isolated from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent in the Mid-Atlantic Ridge Extremophiles 7:101-109</reference>
  <file>Thermococcus.atlanticus.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are spherical cocci (from 0.7 to 1.2 µm in diameter), and division occurs by constriction.  Not motile.  Obligate anaerobes Grows optimally on rich proteinaceous medium, BHI-S, at 23–30.6 g/l NaCl and at pH around 7.  Salinity range for growth ranges from 15.3 to 46 g per liter.  pH range for growth is 5-8.  The temperature range for growth is 70–95 ˚C, and the temperature optimum is around 85 ˚C.  Obligate chemoorganotroph, grows only on proteic products.  Poor growth is observed on starch.  Sulfur is not necessary for, but greatly enhances, growth.  The G+C content is 50%.  Source of isolate: active chimney wall fragment recovered from a hydrothermal site in the Mid-Atlantic Ridge.  Type strain is T. atlanticus, MA898, and has been deposited at the CIP under the number CIP-107420T and at the DSMZ (DSM15226).  Resistant to vancomycin, penicillin, kanamycin, and streptomycin.  Sensitive to rifampicin and chloramphenicol.  Capable of growth on brain heart infusion, peptone, tryptone, yeast extract and meat extract.  Unable to grow on maltose, glucose, cellobiose, xylose, lactose, fructose, saccharose, malt, casein, casamino acids, xylan, dextrane, cellulose, chitin, formate, acetate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, and lactate, ethanol, glycerol, methanol, and a mixture of amino acids.  Cystine, cysteine, and polysulfide supported rapid growth.  Nitrate, nitrite, sulfite, thiosulfate, sulfate, and Fe(III) were unable to be used as electron acceptors.  When elemental sulfur was present in the culture medium, growth was accompanied by the production of H2S.  Incapable of growth under autotrophic conditions with hydrogen present.  On brain heart infusion, formate, acetate, phenyl acetate, propionate, and isovalerate were formed as major fermentation products.</description>
</treatment>
