<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Therrnocladium_modestius</taxon_name>
  <strain>IC-125T (= JCM 100MT)</strain>
  <reference>Therrnocladium modestius gen. nov., sp. nov., a new genus of rod-shaped, extremely thermophilic crenarchaeote IJSB 48:879-887</reference>
  <file>Therrnocladium.modesties.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are rod-shaped.  Grows anaerobically or microaerobically.  Heterotrophic.  Growth is stimulated by CO2 in the gas phase and by archaeal cell-extract or a vitamin mixture.  Growth occurs at 45-82°C and is optimal around 75 ˚C.  Growth occurs at pH 2.6-5.1 and is optimal at pH 4.0 when buffered with 10 mM trisodium citrate.  Growth pH is extended to pH 5.9 when buffered with 10 mM MES. Under optimal conditions [75 ˚C, pH 4.2, under H2/CO2 gas mixture], strain IC-125T grows with a doubling time of 15-18 h.  Grows at low salinity (0-1.0 % NaC1).  Grows in medium containing 1.0% NaCl but not 1.5% NaCl.  Utilizes glycogen, starch, beef extract, casamino acids, peptone, malt extract, tryptone, gelatin, and yeast extract as carbon sources.  Grows best with 0.1-0-2% yeast extract, but does not grow with 1.0% yeast extract.  Requires sulfur, thiosulfate, L-cystine or sulfate as electron acceptors.  With H2/CO2 as gas phase, may utilize nitrate or FeCl3 as electron acceptors.  Produces sulfide during growth.  The G + C content of genomic DNA is 52 mol %.  The type strain, IC-125T (= JCM 100MT), was isolated from solfataric mud at Noji-onsen, Fukushima, Japan.   No or negligible growth was obtained on D-arabinose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, D-ribose, sucrose, D-xylose, acetate, butyrate, citrate, formate, fumarate, lactate, L-malate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, L-alanine, L-arginine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-cysteine, L-glutamic acid, L-glutamine, glycine, L-histidine, L-isoleucine, L-leucine, L-lysine, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, L-tryptophan, L-tyrosine, L-valine, methanol, ethanol, formamide, monomethylamine, and trimethylamine.  The three stains showed no or negligible growth on the basal medium without an electron acceptor.  The isolates were resistant to chloramphenicol, oleandomycin kanamycin, rifampicin, vancomycin, ampicillin and erythromycin.  The three isolates contained large amounts of tetraether core lipids and small amounts of diether core lipids.  No fatty acid was found.  Major lipids are glycerol-bisdiphytanyl-glycerol tetraethers.  All of these lipids are considered to be different cyclized variations in the isopranoid chains.</description>
</treatment>
