<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermococcus_aggregans</taxon_name>
  <strain>TYT = DSM 10597T = JCM 10137T</strain>
  <reference>Thermococcus guaymasensis sp. nov. and Thermococcus aggregans sp. nov., two novel thermophilic archaea isolated from the Guaymas Basin hydrothermal vent site IJSB 48:1181-1185</reference>
  <file>Thermococcus.guaymasensis.aggregans.pdf</file>
  <description>Coccoid archaeon with cell diameters of 1.0-1-5 µm.  Cells are Gram-positive, non-motile and occur as single cells, diploid forms or (particularly when cultivated on yeast extract/tryptone plus sulphur) aggregates of many cells (up to 50).  Colonies are circular, convex and pale-grey in colour, and colony diameters range from 0.5 to 1.0 mm after 48-72 h incubation at 70 ˚C under strictly anoxic conditions.  Chemo-organotrophic and strictly anaerobic.  Utilizes preferably proteinaceous substrates such as yeast extract and trypticase in the presence of 0.5-1.0 % (w/v) elemental sulphur.  Casein, dextrose, maltose and starch are also utilized.  The end products of metabolism on medium containing yeast extract plus tryptone and sulphur are acetate, propionate, isobutyrate, isovalerate, CO2 and H2S, whereas, after growth on dextrose or maltose plus sulphur, only acetate, CO2 and H2S are formed.  The pH range for growth is 5-6-7-9; the optimum pH is 7.0.  Grows between 60 and 94 ˚C, with no growth occurring at 95 ˚C.  The optimum temperature is 88 ˚C.  The NaCl range for growth is 1-0-3.0 % (w/v) with the optimum at 2.5 %.  The G+C content of the DNA is 42.0 mol %.  Lipids are mainly represented by one phospholipid and some minor components; core lipids are characteristically archaeol and caldarchaeol compounds in equal amounts.  Isolated from marine sediments at the Guaymas Basin hydrothermal vent site (2000 m depth) in the Gulf of California.  Type strain TYT has been deposited in the DSMZ-German Collection of Microorganisms and Cell Cultures, Braunschweig, Germany, as strain DSM 10597T and in the Japanese Collection of Microorganisms as JCM 10137T.  No growth on chitin, formate, acetate, propionate, butryrate, methanol, ethanol, propanol, or casamino acids.</description>
</treatment>
