<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermogladius_shockii</taxon_name>
  <strain>WB1 = JCM-16579 = BAA-1607</strain>
  <reference>Thermogladius shockii gen. nov., sp. nov., a hyperthermophilic crenarchaeote from Yellowstone National Park, USA Arch Microbiol 193:45-52</reference>
  <file>Thermogladius.shockii.pdf</file>
  <description>Regular to slightly irregular cocci growing singularly or in pairs with vacuoles and tetragonal patterned S-layer.  Heterotrophic metabolism using fermentation of a variety of complex organic substrates to produce organic acids.  Cells are not capable of autotrophic growth and are strictly anaerobic.  Cells can thrive in high temperatures and in a broad pH range but require low NaCl concentrations.  The presence of elemental sulfur has no effect on growth rate or final density except for detoxification of elevated H2.   Cells are 0.6–1.2 µm in diameter with rigid, stalk-like protrusions on a subset (&lt;2%) of the population.  Species is capable of fermenting yeast, peptone, tryptone, beef extract, and casein.  Grows optimally at 84 ˚C (range 64–93 ˚C), pH 5–6 (range 3.5–8.5), with little or no added NaCl (range 0–4.6 g/l).  Grows best at 0 g per liter NaCl.  At optimal conditions, cells grow with a doubling time of 4.9 h.  Species does not show sensitivity to the antibiotics ampicillin, kanamycin, rifampicin, chloramphenicol, or streptomycin.  The G+C content of genomic DNA is 51.3 mol%.  Organism was isolated from the Washburn hot spring group in Yellowstone National Park, USA.  The type strain is Thermogladius shockii WB1, which has been deposited at RIKEN (JCM-16579) and ATCC (BAA-1607).  No growth was observed on glucose, sucrose, lactose, maltose, fructose, ribose, formic acid, acetic acid, propanoic acid, citric acid, pectin, cellulose, or starch.  Did not grow autotrophically under a H2/CO2 headspace.  Growth was unaffected by the presence of sulfur or sulfate.  Hydrogen inhibits growth.  Sulfur stimulates growth.  Does not reduce sulfate.</description>
</treatment>
