<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermococcus_hydrothermalis</taxon_name>
  <strain>AL662 = CNCMI1319</strain>
  <reference>Thermococcus hydrothermalis sp. nov., a New Hyperthermophilic Archaeon Isolated from a Deep-sea Hydrothermal Vent IJSB 47:622-626</reference>
  <file>Thermococcus.hydrothermalis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are cocci (diameter, 0.8 to 2 µm) that are motile by means of polar flagella.  Cell division occurs by constriction.  Obligately anaerobic.  Growth was observed at pH 3.5 to 9.5, and at salt concentrations ranging from 20 to 80 g per liter.  Grows optimally in the presence of 30 to 40 g of Sea Salt per liter and at a pH around 6.  Growth occurs at 55 to 100˚C, and the optimum temperature is around 85°C.  Obligately chemoorganotrophic.  Grows preferentially on yeast extract, peptone, meat extract, brain heart infusion, a mixture of amino acids, maltose, cellobiose, and pyruvate.  Sulfur is not necessary for growth but greatly enhances growth.  Type strain AL662 (= CNCMI1319 [Collection Nationale de Cultures de Microorganismes, Institut Pasteur, Paris, France]) was isolated from an active chimney wall fragment recovered from a hydrothermal site on the East Pacific Rise at a latitude of 21˚N.  Resistant to vancomycin, penicillin, kanamycin, streptomycin, rifampin, and chloramphenicol.  The polar lipid fraction contained primarily glycerol ether lipids, and diphytanyl glycerol diether (C20) was the predominant lipid and accounted for 80% of the total lipid fraction.  In contrast, the tetraethers predominated (accounting for 75% of the total lipids) in the lipids extracted by the Bligh-Dyer method.  No cyclopropane rings were observed either in the organic fraction or in the residual phase.  Slow growth on casamino acids and casein.  None of the other sugars, alcohols, carboxylic acids, individual amino acids, or polysaccharides tested supported growth.  H2-CO2 gas did not support autotrophic growth.  Slow growth occurred in the absence of elemental sulfur, and growth was rapidly inhibited by 80% H.  Cystine and polysulfide supported rapid growth.  When elemental sulfur was present in the culture medium, growth of AL662T was accompanied by the production of large amounts of hydrogen sulfide.  On brain heart infusion, acetate, phenyl acetate, lactate, and 2-methylpropionate were major fermentation products.</description>
</treatment>
