<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermococcus_fumicolans</taxon_name>
  <strain>ST557 = CIP 104690</strain>
  <reference>Thermococcus fumicolans sp. nov., a New Hyperthermophilic Archaeon Isolated from a Deep-sea Hydrothermal Vent in the North Fiji Basin</reference>
  <file>Thermococcus.fumicolans.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are spherical cocci (diameter, 0.8 to 2 µm) that are motile by means of polar tufts of flagella.  Cell division occurs by constriction.  Obligately anaerobic.  Growth occurs between pH 4.5 and 9.5 and 10-80 g per liter NaCl.  Grows optimally in the presence of 20 to 40 g of Sea Salt per liter and at a pH around 8.  The temperature range for growth is 73 to 103˚C, and the optimum temperature is around 85°C.  Obligately chemoorganotrophic.  Grows on proteolysis products and a mixture of amino acids.  Sulfur is not necessary for growth but greatly enhances growth.  Type strain ST557 (= CIP 104690 [Collection de 1’Institut Pasteur, Paris, France]) was isolated from an active chimney wall fragment obtained at a hydrothermal site in the North Fiji Basin in the southwest Pacific Ocean.  Resistant to vancomycin, penicillin, kanamycin, streptomycin, and chloramphenicol but was susceptible to rifampin.  Lipids consistent of glycerol ether lipids, with diphytanyl glycerol diether (C20) accounting for 70% of the total lipids.  In the residual phase of the extraction preparation the glycerol tetraethers having various proportions of cyclopentane rings predominated along with small amount of diethers.  The proportions of the acyclic, monocyclic, and bicyclic tetraethers were estimated to be 60, 20, and 20% of the total ethers, respectively. Able to grow on yeast extract, peptone, meat extract, malt extract, peptone, tryptone, brain heart infusion, casein, maltose, amino acids, and pyruvate.  Unable to grow on casamino acids, glucose, sucrose, fructose, lactose, galactose, cellulose, starch, chitin, ethanol, sorbitol, mannitol, formate, acetate, glutamate, lysine, and glycine.  Unable to grow under H2/CO2 under autotrophic conditions.  Able to use sulfur, cystine, or polysulfide as electron acceptors.  Unable to use thiosulfate, thioglycolate, dithionite, sulfite, formate, and malate as electron acceptors.  Acetate, phenylacetate, lactate, and 2-methylpropionate are major fermentation products.  G+C content of the DNA was 55 mol% (Tm) and 54 mol% (HPLC).  In the presence of sulfur, large amounts of H2S is produced.</description>
</treatment>
