<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermococcus_zilligii</taxon_name>
  <strain>DSM 2770</strain>
  <reference>The phylogenetic position of the Thermococcus isolate AN1 based on 16S rRNA gene sequence analysis: a proposal that AN1 represents a new species, Thermococcus zilligii sp. nov. Arch Microbiol 168:245-248</reference>
  <file>Thermococcus.zilligii.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells are coccoid-shaped, gram-negative, motile, 0.5– 2.0 µm in diameter dependent on the phase of growth, being larger in later stages.  The optimal temperature for growth is 75–80°C with growth occurring between 55 and 85°C.  The optimal NaCl concentration for growth is 50 mM (0.29%), with no growth being observed above 200 mM in the presence of 0.8% peptone.  Isolate AN1 has an absolute requirement for either Na+ or Li+ for growth.  Sulfur [either as elemental sulfur (S˚) or as cystine or oxidized glutathione with the sulfur being reduced to H2S] is also an absolute requirement.  Sulfur could not be replaced by sulfate, sulfite or thiosulfate when the cultures were continuously gassed with N2.  The pH optimum for growth is 7.4 (minimum, pH 5.4; maximum, pH 9.2).  The organism is strictly anaerobic, obligately heterotrophic growing on peptone (0.8%), casein or yeast extract.  The following amino acids stimulate growth when the peptone concentration is 0.1%: glutamic acid, aspartic acid, tryptophan, alanine, leucine, valine, isoleucine, threonine and arginine.  No growth is observed on carbohydrates, amino acids or organic acids when peptone is absent from the media.  Cells divide by constriction and, when grown in the presence of S˚, often have an inclusion body.  The G+C content (mol%) of the genomic DNA is 46.2.  Metabolic end products when grown on trypticase peptone included H2, sulfide (H2S), CO2, NH4+, acetate, propionate, isobutyrate, mercapto-based compounds and isovalerate/2-methylbutyrate.  Growth is not inhibited by rifampicin, but is inhibited by mevinolin and monensin.  Isolated from a terrestrial, fresh-water geothermal pool (Rt1) in Kuirau Park, Rotorua, New Zealand.  The type strain is DSM 2770.  Unusual membrane lipid composition, of which 45% is the unique 2,3-di-O-phytanyl-sn-glycero-1-(a-D-glucopyranosyl-3-phosphate).  Resistant to rifampin.  Sensitive to mevinolin and monensin.</description>
</treatment>
