<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermoproteus_uzoniensis</taxon_name>
  <strain>Z-605 = DSM 5263</strain>
  <reference>Thermoproteus uzoniensis sp. nov., a new extremely thermophilic archaebacterium from Kamchatka continental hot springs Arch Microbiol 154:556-559</reference>
  <file>Thermoproteus.uzoniensis.pdf</file>
  <description>Cells 0.3-0.4 by 3-20 µm rods, some of them branching or forming spherical protrusions on the ends, or at the branching points.  The cell envelope consists of hexagonally packed subunits covered on the outer side by a layer with less clearly defined structure.  Cells are non-motile and have no flagella.  Anaerobic.  Optimal growth at 90˚C and pH 5.7.  Utilizes peptides, simultaneously reducing elemental sulfur, but does not depend on it obligatory.  Production of fermentation products such as acetate, isobutyrate, and isovalerate.  G+ C content of Z-605 isolate is 56.5 mol%.  The habitat is hot springs, soil and geothermal waters of the Uzon caldera (Kamchatka).  Type strain is Thermoproteus uzoniensis Z-605, DSM 5263, Braunschweig-Stockheim, FRG.  Capable of growth between 74˚C and 102˚C.  Growth was observed in the pH range 4.6 to 6.8.  Good growth on peptone, reducing sulfur to hydrogen sulfide.  Able to grow on casein hydrolysate and trypticase.  No growth on albumin, casamino acids, amino acids, yeast extract, starch, pectin, glucose, sucrose, maltose, cellobiose, galactose, xylose, fructose, ramnose, arabinose, lactose, malate, formate, acetate, propionate, butyrate, methanol, ethanol, formaldehyde, or acetone.  Unable to grow autotrophically on H2/CO2.  Capable of growth without sulfur, however growth is stimulated by the presence of sulfur.  Unable to use sulfate, thiosulfate, sulfite, nitrate, fumarate, and cystine as electron acceptors.  Resistant to benzylpenicillin and chloramphenicol.  Vancomycin, streptomycin, and rifampicin slightly inhibited growth.</description>
</treatment>
