<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Thermococcus_chitonophagus</taxon_name>
  <strain>GC74; DSM 10152</strain>
  <reference>Thermococcus chitonophagus sp. nov., a novel, chitin-degrading, hyperthermophilic archaeum from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent environment Arch Microbiol 164:255-264</reference>
  <file>Thermococcus.chitonophagus.pdf</file>
  <description>Round to irregular cocci, 1.2-2.5 µm in diameter, monopolar polytrichous flagellated and motile.  During growth, cells stick to chitin particles.  Cell wall composed of a protein surface layer, exhibiting p6 symmetry and a center-to-center distance of 15 nm between neighboring protein complexes.  Growth between 60 and 93˚C (optimum: 75˚C pH 3.5 and 9 (optimum: pH 6.7), and 0.8 to 8% NaCl (optimum: 2%).  Shortest doubling time: 75 min.  Strictly anaerobic.  Growth at low (300 kPa) and high pressure (23,000 kPa).  Growth on chitin, yeast extract, and meat extract.  With sulfur, growth on casein peptone and meat peptone.  Molecular hydrogen inhibits growth.  Inhibition is eliminated (to some extent) in the presence of sulfur by H2S formation.  Chitin is degraded to H2, CO2, NH3, acetate, and formate.  Cells consume N-acetylglucosamine, (GlcNAc)2, (GlcNAc)3, and pyruvate.  Acetate, CO2, and NH3 are formed from N-acetylglucosamine.   The chitinoclastic enzyme system is cell-associated, oxygenstable, and inducible.  Core lipids consist of glycerol diphytanyl diethers and acyclic and cyclic glycerol diphytanyl tetraethers with one pentacyclic ring.  46.5 mol% G+C.  Type strain: Thermococcus chitonophagus GC74; DSM 10152, Braunschweig, Germany [isolated from a deep-sea hydrothermal vent environment (depth: 2,600 m) at 20˚50’N, 109˚06’W]. Strict anaerobe.  Addition of elemental sulfur enhances growth rates slightly.  No growth was observed in the presence or absence of elemental sulfur: acetate, ribose, glucose, N-acetylglucosamine, maltose, mannitol, xylan, mannan, pectin, glycogen, agar, chitosan, cellulose, collagen, creatine, dextran sulfate, calf thymus DNA, and Chlorella extract.</description>
</treatment>
