<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Gail Gasparich">
  <taxon_name>Ureaplasma_urealyticum</taxon_name>
  <file>Uparvum Uurealyticum Robertson et al 2002</file>
  <description>Ureaplasma urealyticum (Shepard et al. 1974) Robertson et al. 2001 Phenotypic characteristics. Growth inhibition of cells by (or colony reaction with) polyclonal antisera to one or more of the specific antigenic determinants associated with the present T960 biovar of the human ureaplasmas (serovars 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12 or 13) but not to any antigenic determinants associated with the proposed U. parvum (parvo biovar of human ureaplasmas or its serovars 1, 3, 6 or 14). T960 biovarspecific polypeptide patterns obtained by PAGE: these may be enhanced through reaction with polyclonal antiserum or monoclonal antibodies to the antigenic specificities associated with the species. Growth is inhibited permanently in the presence of 1 mM Mn2+, with the exception of serovar 13, which shows severely delayed growth ± a response which is intermediate between that shown by strains of the T960 and parvo biovars of human ureaplasmas. Genotypic characteristics. Genomes ranging from 840 to 1140 kbp which demonstrate &gt;70% hybridization patterns with DNA of other strains of the present T960 biovar of ureaplasmas; RFLP patterns similar to those of other serovars of the T960 biovar but which differ from those characteristic of the proposed U. parvum; amplification with PCRs for T960 biovarspecific nucleotide sequences for the urease-associated genes, the 16S rRNA genes, the 16S-23S rRNA intergenic regions, and the 5'-end of the genes of the multiple-banded antigens, and T960-specific randomly amplified polymorphic DNA PCR. The type strain of U. urealyticum will continue to be serovar 8 standard (strain T960), represented by ATTC 27618 and NCTC 10177. The estimated G+C content of the DNA is 27-28 mol%; its genome size is 890 kbp. The most recent GenBank accession numbers for the sequences of its 16S rRNA and 16S-23S rRNA intergenic spacer region are AF073450 and AF059330, respectively.</description>
</treatment>
