<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Gail Gasparich">
  <taxon_name>Ureaplasma_parvum</taxon_name>
  <file>Uparvum Uurealyticum Robertson et al 2002</file>
  <description>Ureaplasma parvum (par«vum. L. neut. adj. parvum small, referring to the fact that its genome is significantly smaller than that of U. urealyticum). Phenotypic characteristics. Growth inhibition of cells by (or colony reaction with) polyclonal antisera to one or more of the specific antigenic determinants associated with the present parvo biovar of the human ureaplasmas (serovars 1, 3, 6 or 14) but not to any antigenic determinants associated with the emended U. urealyticum (T960 biovar of the human ureaplasmas or its serovars 2, 4, 5, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12 or 13). Parvo biovarspecific polypeptide patterns obtained by PAGE: these may be enhanced through reaction with polyclonal antiserum or monoclonal antibodies to the antigenic specificities associated with the species. Growth is inhibited temporarily in the presence of 1 mM Mn2+. Genotypic characteristics. Genomes of 760 kbp demonstrate &gt; 70% hybridization patterns with the DNA of other strains of the present parvo biovar of ureaplasmas.  RFLP patterns which are similar to those characteristics of other serovars of the parvo biovar but differ from those characteristics of the emended U. urealyticum; amplification by PCRs for parvo biovarspecific nucleotide sequences for the urease-associated genes, the 16S rRNA genes, the 16S-23S rRNA intergenic regions, and the 5' end of the genes of the multiple-banded antigens, and the parvo biovarspecific RAPD PCR. The type strain of U. parvum will be the serovar 3 standard (strain 27) represented by ATCC 27815 and NCTC 11736. The G+C content of the DNA is 26 mol%; its genome size is 751,719 kbp. The most recent GenBank accession numbers for the sequences of its 16S rRNA and 16S-23S rRNA intergenic spacer region are AF073456 and AF059323, respectively.</description>
</treatment>
