<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Vulcanisaeta_souniana</taxon_name>
  <strain>IC-059T (=JCM 11219T=DSM 14430T)</strain>
  <reference>Vulcanisaeta distributa gen. nov., sp. nov., and Vulcanisaeta souniana sp. nov., novel  hyperthermophilic, rod-shaped crenarchaeotes  isolated from hot springs in Japan IJSEM 52:1097-1104</reference>
  <file>Vulcanisaeta.distributa.souniana.pdf</file>
  <description>Grows anaerobically and tolerates low levels of oxygen (1%) when sodium thiosulfate is supplemented as an electron acceptor.  Heterotrophic.  Growth occurs from 65 to 89 °C and between pH 3.5 and 5.0 when buffered with 10 mM trisodium citrate.  Under optimal growth conditions, doubling time is 4.7 h.  Growth occurs at low salinity (&lt;1.25% NaCl).  Utilizes proteinaceous substances such as yeast extract, peptone, beef extract, Casamino acids and gelatin, as well as maltose, starch and malate as carbon sources.  Requires sulfur or thiosulfate as an electron acceptor.  Archaeal cell extract or a vitamin mixture has little effect on growth.  Produces sulfide during growth.  DNA G+C content is 44.9 mol%.  The type strain is IC-059T (=JCM 11219T=DSM 14430T), which was isolated from a hot spring in Sounzan, Kanagawa, Japan.  Strain IC-060 is also included in this species.  Unable to grow using galactose, glucose, mannose, or citrate.  Unable to grow on media containing sulfide using cystine, ferric iron, and oxidized glutathione.  Able to use sulfate as an electron acceptor.  When cultured in medium in which sulfur was replaced by thiosulfate, showed weak growth in a low oxygen atmosphere.  Unable to grow autotrophically using H2/CO2. Resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, oleandomycin, streptomycin, and vancomycin.  Had tetra ether core lipids.  Core lipid fractions contained acyclic or various cyclized glycerol-bisphytanyl-glycerol tetraethers.  Unable to use d-arabinose, d-fructose, lactose, sucrose, d-xylose, acetate, butyrate, formate, fumarate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, methanol, formamide, methylamine or trimethylamine as carbon sources.  Unable to use fumarate, malate or nitrate as electron acceptors.</description>
</treatment>
