<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<treatment dataprovider="Carrine Blank">
  <taxon_name>Vulcanisaeta_distributa</taxon_name>
  <strain>IC-017T (=JCM 11212T=DSM 14429T)</strain>
  <reference>Vulcanisaeta distributa gen. nov., sp. nov., and Vulcanisaeta souniana sp. nov., novel  hyperthermophilic, rod-shaped crenarchaeotes  isolated from hot springs in Japan IJSEM 52:1097-1104</reference>
  <file>Vulcanisaeta.distributa.souniana.pdf</file>
  <description>Grows anaerobically and tolerates low levels of oxygen (1%) when sodium thiosulfate is supplemented as an electron acceptor.  Heterotrophic.  Growth occurs, at least, from 70 to 99 °C and between pH 3.1 and 5.6 when buffered with 10 mM trisodium citrate.  Under optimal growth conditions, doubling time is 5.5-6.5 h.  Growth occurs at low salinity (&lt;1.0 % NaCl).  Utilizes proteinaceous substances such as yeast extract, peptone, beef extract, Casamino acids and gelatin, as well as maltose, starch and malate as carbon sources.  Requires sulfur or thiosulfate as an electron acceptor.  Archaeal cell extract or a vitamin mixture has little effect on growth.  Produces sulfide during growth.  DNA G+C content is 45.4 mol%.  The type strain is IC-017T (=JCM 11212T=DSM 14429T), which was isolated from a hot spring in Ohwakudani, Kanagawa, Japan.  Able to grow using galactose and mannose.  Unable to grow using glucose and citrate. In medium containing sulfide, unable to use ferric iron and sulfate as electron acceptors.  Able to use cystine and oxidized glutathione as an electron acceptor.  When cultured in medium in which sulfur was replaced by thiosulfate, showed weak growth in a low oxygen atmosphere.  Unable to grow autotrophically using H2/CO2. Resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, kanamycin, oleandomycin, streptomycin, and vancomycin. Core lipid fractions contained acyclic or various cyclized glycerol-bisphytanyl-glycerol tetraethers.  Unable to use d-arabinose, d-fructose, lactose, sucrose, d-xylose, acetate, butyrate, formate, fumarate, propionate, pyruvate, succinate, methanol, formamide, methylamine or trimethylamine as carbon sources.  Unable to use fumarate, malate or nitrate as electron acceptors.</description>
</treatment>
