<treatment><meta><source><author>Atsuko Ueki, Hiroshi Akasaka†, Daisuke Suzuki and Katsuji Ueki</author><date>2006</date><title>Paludibacter propionicigenes gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel strictly anaerobic, Gram-negative, propionate-producing bacterium isolated from plant residue in irrigated rice-field soil in Japan</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 13:45:59 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.63896-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM January 2006 vol. 56 no. 1 39-44</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Paludibacter</genus_name><species_name>propionicigenes</species_name><strain_name>WB4</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming, non-motile, short rods. Strictly anaerobic. Chemo-organotroph. Optimum growth temperature is 30 °C. Oxidase, catalase and nitrate-reducing activities are negative. Species utilize various sugars and produce acetate and propionate as major fermentation end-products with succinate as a minor product. Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C15 : 0, C15 : 0 and anteiso-C17 : 0 3-OH. The major respiratory quinone is MK-8(H4). The genomic DNA G+C content of the type species is 39·3 mol%. Cells are 0·5–0·6 μm in diameter and 1·3–1·7 μm in length. Ends of cells are usually round to slightly tapered and elongated cells are occasionally formed both singly and in chains of the short cells. Spherical cells sometimes develop after storage of slant cultures at 4 °C. Propionate and acetate are produced as major fermentation products from glucose at a ratio of 2 : 1. Grows at pH 5·0–7·6 (optimum pH 6·6) and at 15–35 °C. Even at 33 °C, growth is significantly slower than that at 30 °C. Does not grow at 37 °C. NaCl concentration range for growth is 0–0·5 % (w/v) in PYG medium. Utilizes arabinose, xylose, cellobiose, fructose, galactose, glucose, mannose, maltose, melibiose, glycogen and soluble starch as growth substrates and produces acids. Does not use ribose, sorbose, lactose, rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose, melezitose, raffinose, cellulose, xylan, salicin, dulcitol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, ethanol, glycerol, fumarate, lactate, malate, pyruvate or succinate. Aesculin is hydrolysed, but gelatin is not. Urease is negative. Hydrogen sulfide and indole are not produced. Does not grow in the presence of bile salts.</description></treatment>