<treatment><meta><source><author>Dong-Heon Lee,1 Sung-Ran Moon,1 Young-Hyun Park,1 Young Sun Lee,2  Jae Sung Jung,2 Jung Ho Kim,3 Hoon Kim3 and Hyung-Yeel Kahng1</author><date>2011</date><title>Gangjinia marincola gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine  bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:07:18 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.021592-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2011), 61, 325–329</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Gangjinia</genus_name><species_name>marincola</species_name><strain_name>GJ16</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are strictly aerobic, Gram-stain-negative, orange-pigmented, non-flagellated and rod-shaped (Supplementary Fig. S1, available in IJSEM Online). Gliding motility is absent. Oxidase and catalase activities are present. Non-diffusible carotenoid-type pigments are produced, but flexirubin pigments are absent. The major respiratory quinone is MK-6. The cellular fatty acid composition is dominated by iso-C15 : 0, iso-C15 : 1 G, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH and C15 : 0. Colonies on MA are orange in colour, circular, 1.0–3.0 mm in diameter and convex with smooth surfaces and entire margins. Non-diffusible carotenoid-type pigments with absorption peaks at 451 nm, 474 nm and 503 nm are produced. Growth occurs at 20–30 °C (optimum at 25–30 °C), at pH 6.0–9.0 (optimum at pH 7.0–8.0) and with 2–4 % NaCl (optimum in 3 % NaCl). However, no growth is observed at 15 °C or 30 °C, at pH 5.5 or 9.5, or in the presence of &lt;1 % or &gt;5 % NaCl. Anaerobic growth does not occur on marine agar. Acetoin, indole and H2S are not produced. Nitrate is not reduced. Hydrolyses casein, starch and DNA, but not agar, carboxymethyl-cellulose, chitin or Tween compounds. Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase and urease activities are absent. In the API ZYM kit, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-glucosidase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase activities are present, but esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent. In the API 50CH kit, acid is only produced aerobically from aesculin-ferric citrate and 5-ketogluconate. In the GN2 MicroPlate, the following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources: melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, methyl pyruvate, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, propionic acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, thymidine, putrescine, α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, acetic acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, glucuronamide, l-alanine, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-proline and phenylethylamine. None of the other carbon sources in the GN2 Microplate are utilized. Resistant to kanamycin (30 μg), gentamicin (10 μg), neomycin (30 μg) and polymyxin B (300 μg), but sensitive to ampicillin (10 μg), penicillin (10 IU), streptomycin (10 μg) and tetracycline (30 μg).The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.4 mol%.</description></treatment>