<treatment><meta><source><author>Elena P. Ivanova,1,2 Yulia V. Alexeeva,1 Se´bastien Flavier,3  Jonathan P. Wright,1 Natalia V. Zhukova,4 Natalia M. Gorshkova,2  Valery V. Mikhailov,2 Dan V. Nicolau1 and Richard Christen3</author><date>2004</date><title>Formosa algae gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel  member of the family Flavobacteriaceae</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 19:49:05 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.02763-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2004), 54, 705–711</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Formosa</genus_name><species_name>algae</species_name><strain_name>KMM 3553</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Rod-shaped cells with slightly irregular sides and pointed ends, approx. 0·8–1·8×0·4–0·9 μm. Gram-negative. Does not form endospores or resting stages. Does not accumulate poly-β-hydroxybutyrate as an intracellular reserve product and does not have an arginine dihydrolase system. Aerobic. Anaerobic growth occurs by fermentation of d-glucose by anaerobic respiration of nitrate. Chemo-organotroph. Cytochrome oxidase-negative, catalase-positive.Exhibits gliding motility. Colonies are circular, 1–3 mm in diameter, low-convex on solid media containing high nutrient concentrations. Colonies are light yellow in colour. Produces carotenoid pigments with absorbance peaks at 455 and 480 nm. Flexirubin pigments are absent. No growth detected at 4 or 37 °C; optimum growth at 23 °C. Grows at pH 5·0–10·0; optimum growth at pH 8·0–8·5. Alkalitolerant. Grows in 0–6 % NaCl. Does not decompose agar or chitin. Starch and gelatin are hydrolysed weakly. Utilizes Tween 40, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, mono-succinate, citric acid, d-glucuronic acid, succinamic acid, succinic acid, alaninamide, glycyl l-aspartic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-pyroglutamic acid, urocanic acid, thymidine, 2-aminoethanol and glycerol. Does not utilize α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, Tween 80, N-acetyl d-glucosamine, adonitol, d-cellobiose, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, d-fructose, l-fucose, m-inositol, α-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannitol, d-mannose, d-melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, d-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, acetic acid, cis-aconitic acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, itaconic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, d-alanine, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-proline, d-serine, l-serine, l-threonine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, inosine, uridine, phenylethylamine, 2,3-butanediol, dl-α-glycerol phosphate, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate or d-glucose 6-phosphate according to the Biolog system. Not susceptible to ampicillin, lincomycin, benzylpenicillin, kanamycin, oleandomycin, tetracycline, neomycin, streptomycin, gentamicin or polymyxin B. PE is the only phospholipid identified. Sphingophospholipids are absent. The predominant cellular fatty acids are odd-numbered: 15 : 0, i15 : 0, ai15 : 0, i15 : 1 and 15 : 1(n-6). DNA G+C content is 34·0–34·4 mol%.</description></treatment>