<treatment><meta><source><author>Fang Peng, Ming Liu, Lei Zhang, Jun Dai, Xueshong Luo, Hongli An and Chengxiang Fang</author><date>2009</date><title>Planobacterium taklimakanense gen. nov., sp. nov., a member of the family Flavobacteriaceae that exhibits swimming motility, isolated from desert soil</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 19:35:10 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.006619-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM July 2009 vol. 59 no. 7 1672-1678</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Planobacterium</genus_name><species_name>taklimakanense</species_name><strain_name>X-65</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, rod-shaped, non-sporulating and motile by swimming in broth cultures. Catalase- and oxidase-positive. The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-15 : 0, anteiso-15 : 0, 16 : 0 and 18 : 0. The predominant respiratory quinone is MK-6. The DNA G+C content of the type strain of the type species is 41.5 mol%.Cells are facultatively anaerobic, approximately 1.0–1.5 μm long and 0.4–0.6 μm in diameter and surrounded by long and relatively thick appendages. No growth occurs at 4 or 40 °C. Growth occurs at 18–37 °C (optimum 30 °C), with 0–3 % NaCl (optimum 0 % NaCl), at pH 6–12 (optimum pH 7–8) and on TSB/10, TGY, NA and TSA, but not MacConkey agar. Colonies are circular with regular edges, mucoid and pale yellow. Flexirubin-type pigments are not produced. No haemolysis occurs on 5 % sheep-blood agar. Starch, aesculin, L-tyrosine, gelatin and casein are decomposed, but agar, Tween 80, CM-cellulose and chitin are not. Methyl red negative. Nitrate is not reduced. The following results are obtained from API 20E and API 20NE strips after 48 h of incubation at 30 °C: indole and acetoin are produced, H2S is not produced, aesculin and gelatin are hydrolysed, urea is not hydrolysed, citrate is utilized and β-galactosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent. With API 50CH strips after 48 h of incubation at 30 °C, acid is produced from D-glucose, D-mannose, maltose, aesculin ferric citrate, melibiose, starch and glycogen. From API ZYM strips incubated for 4 h at 30 °C, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and α-glucosidase activities are present. The following compounds are utilized as sole carbon sources in GN2 MicroPlates: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, L-arabinose, cellobiose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, melibiose, D-sorbitol, trehalose, turanose, methyl pyruvate, monomethyl succinate, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid, bromosuccinic acid, L-alaninamide, L-alanine, L-alanyl glycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl L-aspartic acid, glycyl L-glutamic acid, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-proline, L-serine, L-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, 2,3-butanediol, α-D-glucose 1-phosphate and D-glucose 6-phosphate. Sensitive to (μg per disc) azithromycin (15), novobiocin (30), tetracycline (30), neomycin (30), cefoxitin (30), ceftriaxone (30), ceftizoxime (30), cefotaxime (30), lincomycin (2), cefazolin (30), rifampicin (5), spectinomycin (100), ofloxacin (5), amoxicillin (10), imipenem (10), cefixime (5), cefalexin (30), nitrofurantoin (300), vancomycin (30), gentamicin (10), streptomycin (10), furazolidone (300), cephradine (30), chloramphenicol (30), clindamycin (2), cefuroxime (30), cefoperazone (75), piperacillin (100), levofloxacin (5), teicoplanin (30) and norfloxacin (10). Resistant to (μg per disc unless otherwise indicated) penicillin (10 IU), erythromycin (15), sulfafurazole (300), oxacillin sodium (1), doxycycline (30), amikacin (30), ampicillin (10), kanamycin (30) and tobramycin (10). The dominant (i.e. &gt;9 %) cellular fatty acids are iso-15 : 0, anteiso-15 : 0, 16 : 0 and 18 : 0.</description></treatment>