<treatment><meta><source><author>Fumiko Nagai†, Masami Morotomi†, Yohei Watanabe, Hiroshi Sakon and Ryuichiro Tanaka</author><date>2010</date><title>Alistipes indistinctus sp. nov. and Odoribacter laneus sp. nov., common members of the human intestinal microbiota isolated from faeces</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 19:42:19 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.006619-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM June 2010 vol. 60 no. 6 1296-1302</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Odoribacter</genus_name><species_name>laneus</species_name><strain_name>YIT 12061</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells stain Gram-negative and are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, pleomorphic rods (0.4–1.9×1.4–19.1 μm) that hydrolyse gelatin and are positive for indole production. Catalase, urease and oxidase are not produced. Colonies after 4 days anaerobic incubation on GAM agar are 0.1–0.5 mm in diameter, circular, grey–beige and slightly opaque. After 7–10 days culture on sheep blood agar, colonies are surrounded by a clear haemolytic zone and demonstrate pigmentation after &gt;2 weeks. Analysis of metabolic end products by HPLC from PY and PYG broth reveals small amounts of succinic, acetic and iso-valeric acids. Asaccharolytic. The major cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0, C18 : 1ω9c and anteiso-C15 : 0. Using the commercially available API test systems (API ZYM and rapid ID 32A), positive for N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, acid phosphatase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, chymotrypsin, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4), α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase and tyrosine arylamidase, but negative for α-arabinosidase, arginine dihydrolase, cystine arylamidase, 6-phospho-β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, glycine arylamidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase, proline arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin and valine arylamidase. Weak activity is detected for naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and β-glucuronidase.</description></treatment>