<treatment><meta><source><author>Fumiko Nagai†, Masami Morotomi†, Yohei Watanabe, Hiroshi Sakon and Ryuichiro Tanaka</author><date>2009</date><title>Alistipes indistinctus sp. nov. and Odoribacter laneus sp. nov., common members of the human intestinal microbiota isolated from faeces</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 14:27:30 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.014571-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM June 2010 vol. 60 no. 6 1296-1302</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Alistipes</genus_name><species_name>indistinctus</species_name><strain_name>YIT 12060</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells stain Gram-negative and are non-spore-forming, coccoid to rod-shaped with round ends and are strictly anaerobic. Cells are approximately 0.5–0.7×1.0–3.8 μm. After growth for 4 days with anaerobic incubation on modified GAM agar, colonies are 0.1–0.5 mm in diameter, slightly opaque, circular and grey. The major end products of glucose fermentation in PYG broth are succinic and acetic acids. Not resistant to 20 % bile. Aesculin and gelatin are not hydrolysed and nitrate is not reduced. Indole is not produced. Catalase is positive. Oxidase and urease are not produced. Positive for acid production from cellobiose, glucose, lactose, maltose, D-mannose, melezitose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, trehalose and D-xylose. Acid production from L-arabinose, glycerol, D-mannitol and D-sorbitol is weakly positive. By using the commercially available API test systems (API Rapid ID 32A and API ZYM), positive for N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alanine arylamidase, alkaline phosphatase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase and β-glucosidase, and weakly positive for acid phosphatase, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4), naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and α-arabinosidase. Depending on the micro-test kit used, variable results are obtained for α-glucosidase (positive in the API Rapid ID 32A and negative in the API ZYM) and β-glucuronidase (positive in the API ZYM and negative in the API Rapid ID 32A). Negative for arginine arylamidase, arginine dihydrolase, chymotrypsin, cystine arylamidase, 6-phosphate-β-galactosidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, proline arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, serine arylamidase, trypsin, tyrosine arylamidase and valine arylamidase. The main respiratory quinones are MK-10 and MK-11. The fatty acid profile consists of iso-C15 : 0, C18 : 1ω9c, C15 : 0, C16 : 0, iso-C16 : 0, anteiso-C15 : 0 and an unknown fatty acid (ECL 17.879).</description></treatment>