<treatment><meta><source><author>Hana Yi1 and Jongsik Chun1,2</author><date>2011</date><title>Aquimarina addita sp. nov., isolated from seawater</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:28:22 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.027433-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2011), 61, 2445–2449</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Aquimarina</genus_name><species_name>addita</species_name><strain_name>JC2680</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Gram-reaction-negative, catalase- and oxidase-positive, and strictly aerobic. Cells are non-motile rods with rounded ends (approximately 0.3–0.5×1.4–2.2 µm). Colonies are orange, convex, translucent, glistening, circular with entire margins and become adherent to the agar surface after prolonged incubation on MA. No gliding motility on agar plates. Flexirubin-type pigments are absent (negative for the KOH test and no bathychromatic shift of the absorbance spectrum). Spores are not formed. Does not grow on cetrimide agar or MacConkey agar. Does not grow under microaerophilic or anaerobic conditions. Growth occurs at pH 6–8 (optimum, pH 6) and at 4–30 °C (optimum, 25 °C). Requires sea salts for growth (range 3–7 %; optimum, 3 %) and cannot grow on sea salts-free ZoBell’s medium supplemented with NaCl only. Does not require yeast extract for growth. Reduces nitrate to nitrite. Does not produce acetoin, indole or H2S. Does not utilize citrate. Acid is not produced from glucose. Decomposes aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80, but not agar, adenine, alginic acids, casein, crystalline cellulose, chitin, elastin, pectin, hypoxanthine, l-tyrosine or xanthine. Does not degrade egg yolk but a clear zone is formed around colonies. Positive for alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities, weakly positive for esterase lipase (C8) and trypsin activities, but negative for β-galactosidase, urease, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase. Cannot use any carbohydrate in the API 50CH system as sole carbon source. Produces acid weakly from glycerol, d-arabinose, l-arabinose, d-ribose, d-xylose, methyl β-d-xylopyranoside, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-fructose, d-mannose, l-rhamnose, d-mannitol, methyl α-d-mannopyranoside, methyl α-d-glucopyranoside, amygdalin, arbutin, aesculin ferric citrate, salicin, cellobiose, maltose, lactose (bovine origin), melibiose, sucrose, trehalose, inulin, melezitose, raffinose, starch, glycogen, gentiobiose and turanose, but not from erythritol, l-xylose, d-adonitol, l-sorbose, dulcitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, N-acetylglucosamine, xylitol, d-lyxose, d-tagatose, d-fucose, l-fucose, d-arabitol, l-arabitol, potassium gluconate, potassium 2-ketogluconate or potassium 5-ketogluconate. The major fatty acids are iso-C17 : 0 3-OH, iso-C15 : 0 and summed feature 9 (comprising 10-methyl C16 : 0 and/or iso-C17 : 1ω9c). The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 35 mol%.</description></treatment>