<treatment><meta><source><author>Hideyuki Tamaki,1,2 Satoshi Hanada,2 Yoichi Kamagata,2  Kazunori Nakamura,2 Nakao Nomura,3 Kazunori Nakano1  and Masatoshi Matsumura1</author><date>2003</date><title>Flavobacterium limicola sp. nov., a psychrophilic,  organic-polymer-degrading bacterium isolated  from freshwater sediments</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 10:52:34 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.02369-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2003), 53, 519–526</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Flavobacterium</genus_name><species_name>limicola</species_name><strain_name>ST-82</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, ovoid to short rods, 1·1–3·2 μm long and 0·3–0·6 μm wide, occasionally with elongated filament-like forms. Non-sporulating, non-flagellated and non-gliding. Colonies on trypticase soy agar are circular and convex with bright yellow colour: flexirubin pigments are not detected. Congo red is absorbed. The temperature range for growth is 0–25 °C; no growth occurs at 30 °C. The optimum temperature for growth is 15–20 °C. Sodium chloride inhibits growth: tolerates up to 1·5 % NaCl. Grows well on nutrient agar and trypticase soy agar, but not on sea-water agar. Catalase and cytochrome oxidase are produced. Indole production, Voges–Proskauer and Simmons' citrate test are negative. Neither reduction of nitrate nor production of hydrogen sulfide occurs under any conditions. Lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, tryptophan deaminase, β-glucuronidase, α-galactosidase and β-galactosidase activities are absent. Arginine dihydrolase, l-aspartic arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cysteine arylamidase, alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase, esterase-lipase, lipase, α-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-maltosidase, trypsin, chymotrypsin, urease and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase are produced. β-Glucosidase activity is detected by using aesculin as a substrate. Aerobic chemoheterotroph. No acid is produced from any carbohydrates. Amino acids such as l-alanine, l-alanylglycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl-l-aspartic acid, glycyl-l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-serine and l-threonine are better for growth than carbohydrates such as d-glucose, mannose, maltose, sucrose, starch, glycogen and dextrin. Yeast extract stimulates growth. Hydrolysis of some substrates is described in Table 1⇑; in addition, urea and uric acid are hydrolysed, but not DNA, Tween 80, xylan or xanthine. Brown diffusible pigments are formed on tyrosine agar. No precipitation occurs on egg yolk agar. Steamed cells of E. coli and P. putida are lysed. Major respiratory quinone is menaquinone-6. Membrane lipids consist of a wide variety of branched, saturated, monounsaturated and 3-OH fatty acids; composition is dependent on growth temperature. DNA G+C content is 34·0–34·8 mol%.</description></treatment>