<treatment><meta><source><author>Jiao-Yan Ying,1,2 Zhi-Pei Liu,1Bao-Jun Wang,1Xin Dai,1 Su-Sheng Yang2  and Shuang-Jiang Liu1</author><date>2007</date><title>Salegentibacter catena sp. nov., isolated from  sediment of the South China Sea, and emended  description of the genus Salegentibacter</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:11:09 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64658-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2007), 57, 219–222</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Salegentibacter</genus_name><species_name>catena</species_name><strain_name>HY1</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative rods, 0.5–0.8×2–6 μm, frequently occurring in chains and producing appendages in older cultures. Strictly aerobic. Devoid of flagellar and gliding motilities. Catalase-positive and oxidase-negative. Colonies on marine agar 2216 are saffron yellow, slimy, circular, convex and shiny, 3–5 mm in diameter after 5 days of incubation at 30 °C. Growth occurs at 15–42 °C (optimum, 33 °C), at pH 6.5–9.0 (optimum, 7.5–8.2) and in 0.1–10 % NaCl (optimum, 1–4 %). Arginine dihydrolase, urease and lecithinase are negative. H2S is produced, but indole is not. Nitrate is not reduced. Aesculin, casein, gelatin, starch and Tween 20 are hydrolysed, but agar, DNA and carboxymethylcellulose are not. Weak growth and acid formation occur with glucose, but not with sucrose, mannose, maltose, arabinose, lactose, rhamnose, melibiose, fucose, raffinose, xylose, adonitol, inositol, sorbitol, gluconate, malonate, galactose, malate, citrate, pyruvate, lactate, propionate, acetate, alanine or proline. In API ZYM kits, activities of alkaline and acid phosphatases, esterase lipase (C8), leucine and valine arylamidases, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and α-glucosidase are strong and activities of esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase and trypsin are weak. Negative for activities of α-chymotrypsin, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, α-mannosidase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase. Resistant to gentamicin (10 μg), neomycin (30 μg), polymyxin B (300 μg) and streptomycin (10 μg), but sensitive to ampicillin (10 μg), carbenicillin (100 μg), tetracycline (30 μg), vancomycin (30 μg), ciprofloxacin (5 μg), rifampicin (5 μg), norfloxacin (10 μg), chloramphenicol (30 μg), benzylpenicillin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg) and erythromycin (15 μg). Cellular fatty acids (&gt;1 % of the total fatty acids) are iso-14 : 0 (2.0 %), iso-15 : 1 (5.0 %), anteiso-15 : 1 (1.3 %), iso-15 : 0 (6.8 %), anteiso-15 : 0 (6.4 %), 15 : 1ω6c (2.6 %), 15 : 0 (10.4 %), iso-16 : 1 (2.8 %), iso-16 : 0 (13.5 %), summed feature 3 (comprising iso-15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1ω7c; 6.3 %), 16 : 0 (4.3 %), iso-15 : 0 3-OH (1.2 %), 15 : 0 2-OH (1.8 %), iso-17 : 1ω9c (2.3 %), anteiso-17 : 1ω9c (2.3 %), 17 : 1ω8c (1.5 %), 17 : 1ω6c (2.4 %), iso-16 : 0 3-OH (3.6 %), 18 : 1ω7c (1.3 %), 18 : 0 (2.6 %), iso-17 : 0 3-OH (5.2 %) and 17 : 0 2-OH (5.0 %).The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 44.4 mol%.</description></treatment>