<treatment><meta><source><author>Ju-Hyoung Kim,1 Ki-Youn Kim,1 Young-Tae Hahm,1 Bong-Soo Kim,2  Jongsik Chun2 and Chang-Jun Cha1</author><date>2008</date><title>Actibacter sediminis gen. nov., sp. nov., a marine  bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated  from tidal flat sediment</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 14:09:11 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.65346-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2008), 58, 139–143</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Actibacter</genus_name><species_name>sediminis</species_name><strain_name>KMM 6034</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are rod-shaped with rounded ends, non-flagellated and non-gliding. Gram-negative. Aerobic, chemoheterotrophic and mesophilic. Oxidase- and catalase-positive. Spores are not formed. Flexirubin-type pigments are absent. The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-6. The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0, iso-C15 : 1 G, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH and iso-C1. Cells are 0.7–0.9 μm wide and 2.4–3.2 μm long. Colonies on MA are circular, smooth, convex, entire and yellow-pigmented. Growth occurs at 5–45 °C (optimum, 37 °C), at pH 5–8 (optimum, pH 6) and in the presence of 1–10 % NaCl (optimum, 1–3 %) or 1–15 % sea salts (optimum, 1 %). Growth also occurs on R2A medium in the absence of NaCl and sea salt. Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite. Indole and H2S are not produced. Aesculin, gelatin, starch and Tween 80 are degraded, but DNA, agar, casein, crystalline cellulose (filter paper) and chitin are not. Alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and α-glucosidase activities are present, but lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-fucosidase and α-mannosidase activities are absent. Acid is not produced from glucose, arabinose, mannose, mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, maltose, gluconate, caprate, adipate, malate, citrate or phenylacetate. Growth occurs on peptone, tryptone and yeast extract. Acetate, citrate, pyruvate, sucrose and l-glutamate are utilized. Glycerol, l-leucine, l-proline, succinate, benzoate, l-proline and p-toluic acid are not utilized. The predominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0 (19.8 %), iso-C15 : 1 G (14.0 %), iso-C17 : 0 3-OH (13.7 %) and iso-C13 : 0 (6.4 %). The DNA G+C content is 43–45 mol%.</description></treatment>