<treatment><meta><source><author>Julia Downes,1 Iain C. Sutcliffe,2 Tor Hofstad3 and William G. Wade1</author><date>2006</date><title>Prevotella bergensis sp. nov., isolated from human infections</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Friday, 2014 March 28 14:34:51 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.63888-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2006), 56, 609–612</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Prevotella</genus_name><species_name>bergensis</species_name><strain_name>94067913T</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">The description is based on eight strains isolated from human skin and soft-tissue abscesses. Biochemical results were identical for all strains studied. Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-motile, Gram-negative bacilli (0·7–0·8 μm×0·8–6 μm). After 4 days incubation on FAA plates, colonies are 0·6–0·8 mm in diameter, circular, entire, convex, opaque and grey to off-white in colour. Growth in broth media produces a moderate turbidity which is enhanced by the addition of fermentable carbohydrates. Cells are saccharolytic and ferment arabinose, cellobiose, fructose, glucose, lactose, maltose, mannose, rhamnose, salicin and xylose; mannitol and trehalose are fermented variably; melezitose, melibiose, raffinose, ribose, sorbitol and sucrose are not fermented. Major amounts of acetic and succinic acids and a trace of isovaleric acid are produced as end products of metabolism in PYG broth. The non-hydroxylated fatty acid profile is predominately iso-C14 : 0, iso-C15 : 0 and anteiso-C15 : 0. Aesculin is hydrolysed; arginine, gelatin and urea are not hydrolysed. Indole and catalase are not produced and nitrate is not reduced. There is no growth in 20 % bile. The G+C content of the DNA of the type strain is 48 mol%.</description></treatment>