<treatment><meta><source><author>Jung-Hoon Yoon, So-Jung Kang, Choong-Hwan Lee and Tae-Kwang Oh</author><date>2005</date><title>Dokdonia donghaensis gen. nov., sp. nov., isolated  from sea water</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 10:30:02 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.63817-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2005), 55, 2323–2328</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Dokdonia</genus_name><species_name>donghaensis</species_name><strain_name>KMM 6177</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are 0·3–0·6×1·5–25·0 μm. Colonies on marine agar 2216 (MA) are circular, slightly convex, glistening, smooth, yellow in colour and 1·0–2·0 mm in diameter after incubation for 3 days at 30 °C. Growth occurs at 4 and 35 °C with an optimum temperature of 30 °C; growth does not occur at 36 °C. Optimal pH for growth is 7·0–8·0; growth is observed at pH 5·5, but not at pH 5·0. Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 2 % (w/v) NaCl; growth does not occur in the absence of NaCl and in the presence of greater than 7 % (w/v) NaCl. Anaerobic growth does not occur on MA and on MA supplemented with nitrate. Aesculin and Tween 60 are hydrolysed, but hypoxanthine and xanthine are not. Indole and H2S are not produced. Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase are absent. In assays with the API ZYM system, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase are present, but lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase are absent. Susceptible to penicillin G, chloramphenicol, cephalothin, lincomycin and oleandomycin, but not to polymyxin B, gentamicin, novobiocin, kanamycin or neomycin. Growth occurs on peptone and tryptone as the sole carbon and nitrogen sources, but not on d-glucose, sucrose, d-ribose, d-galactose, d-fructose, d-cellobiose, d-trehalose, Casamino acids, dl-aspartate, l-glutamate, l-leucine or l-proline. Acid is not produced from d-ribose, d-trehalose, d-sorbitol or myo-inositol. The major fatty acids (&gt;10 % of total fatty acids) are iso-C15 : 0, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH and iso-C15 : 1. The major polar lipids are phosphatidylethanolamine, unidentified phospholipids, an unidentified glycolipid and an amino-group-containing lipid that is ninhydrin-positive. The DNA G+C content is 38 mol%.</description></treatment>