<treatment><meta><source><author>Kae Kyoung Kwon1, Yoo Kyung Lee2 and Hong Kum Lee2</author><date>2006</date><title>Costertonia aggregata gen. nov., sp. nov., a mesophilic marine bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from a mature biofilm</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 14:13:41 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.65346-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM June 2006 vol. 56 no. 6 1349-1353</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Costertonia</genus_name><species_name>aggregata</species_name><strain_name>KOPRI 13342</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are aerobic, motile, Gram-negative rods. Gliding motility is absent. Orange-coloured colonies form on MA. Produce non-diffusible carotenoid pigments, but flexirubin-type pigments are absent. The major respiratory quinone is MK-6. The major cellular fatty acids are i-C15 : 0, i-C15 : 1 and 15 : 0. Oxidase- and catalase-positive.Cells are 0.50–0.57 μm in length and 0.35–0.41 μm in diameter. However, rods can sometimes be longer than 4 μm. Properties are as described for the genus in addition to the following. Growth occurs at 10–35 °C, pH 6.5–9.0 and with 1.5–12.0 % sea salts. Cells form irregular aggregates during growth in liquid medium. Obligately requires NaCl, Ca2+ and K+ for growth. Optimal growth is observed at pH 7.5–8.0 and 26–32 °C and requires the presence of 3 % (w/v) sea salts. Reduces nitrate to nitrogen gas in API 20 E test strip. Positive for β-glucosidase, β-galactosidase, urease, arginine dihydrolase and protease. Degrades dextrin, glycogen, Tweens 40 and 80, N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, adonitol, L-arabinose, D-arabitol, cellobiose, L-erythritol, D-fructose, L-fucose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, myo-inositol, α-D-lactose, lactulose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, D-melibiose, methyl β-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose, D-trehalose, turanose, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, acetic acid, cis-aconitic acid, citric acid, D-galactonic acid lactone, D-galacturonic acid, D-gluconic acid, D-glucuronic acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, quinic acid, D-saccharic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, glucuronamide, alaninamide, D-alanine, L-alanine, L-alanyl–glycine, L-asparagine, L-aspartic acid, L-glutamic acid, glycyl L-aspartic acid, glycyl L-glutamic acid, L-histidine, hydroxy-L-proline, L-leucine, L-ornithine, L-proline, L-pyroglutamic acid, D-serine, L-serine, L-threonine, γ-aminobutyric acid, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, glycerol, DL-α-glycerol phosphate, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate as sole carbon sources. The dominant fatty acids are i-15 : 0 (39.7 %), i-15 : 1ω10 (22.4 %), 15 : 0 (7.8 %) and 16 : 1ω9 (4.6 %).</description></treatment>