<treatment><meta><source><author>Lili Niu1,2, Lei Song1,2 and Xiuzhu Dong1</author><date>2008</date><title>Proteiniborus ethanoligenes gen. nov., sp. nov., an anaerobic protein-utilizing bacterium</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 12:10:29 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.65108-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM January 2008 vol. 58 no. 1 12-16</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Proteiniborus</genus_name><species_name>ethanoligenes</species_name><strain_name>GW</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are 0.5–0.6 μm wide and 1.4–3.8 μm long. Colonies on PY agar are white, smooth, circular and entire and slightly convex and reach 0.5 mm after cultivation at 37 °C for 72 h. Growth occurs between 20 and 48 °C (optimum 37 °C) and at pH 6.4–10.0 (optimum 8.5–8.8). Besides yeast extract and peptone, weak growth is also observed on tryptone and Casamino acids. Ethanol, acetic acid and hydrogen are the main products from yeast extract and peptone, and a trace amount of propionic acid is also produced. The following substrates are not used: L-serine, L-threonine, L-alanine, L-histidine, L-leucine, L-lysine, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, L-valine, L-glutamine, L-arginine, L-tyrosine, tryptophan, L-isoleucine, L-proline, aspartate, L-cysteine, L-arabinose, cellobiose, aesculin, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycogen, inulin, D-lactose, maltose, mannose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, ribose, sucrose, salicin, sorbose, starch, trehalose, D-xylose, adonitol, amygdalin, dulcitol, erythritol, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, ribitol, methanol, ethanol, l-propanol, citrate, fumarate, malate, succinate, malonate, hippurate, sodium gluconate, butane diacid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, phenylacetic acid, cellulose and xylan. Milk is not curdled. Indole is produced. No NH3 is produced from yeast extract or peptone. Methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative. Casein is degraded and nitrate is reduced. Gelatin and DNA are not hydrolysed.</description></treatment>