<treatment><meta><source><author>Masayuki Miyazaki, Yuriko Nagano, Yoshihiro Fujiwara, Yuji Hatada and Yuichi Nogi</author><date>2010</date><title>Aquimarina macrocephali sp. nov., isolated from sediment adjacent to sperm whale carcasses</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:18:35 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.018747-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM October 2010 vol. 60 no. 10 2298-2302</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Aquimarina</genus_name><species_name>macrocephali</species_name><strain_name>JAMB N27</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are rod-shaped, 0.4–0.6 μm in width and 3.0–25.5 μm in length. Cells are Gram-negative and motile by gliding. Colonies on MA are orange, circular, shiny with entire edges, smooth and convex, 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter after 2–3 days at 20 °C. Grows at 8 and 30 °C (optimum 24 °C), but not at 32 °C. Grows with 1–4 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum 2–3 % NaCl), but not without NaCl or with 5 % NaCl. Strictly aerobic. Catalase- and cytochrome oxidase-positive. H2S and indole are not produced. Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced. Casein, chitin, gelatin and starch are degraded. Aesculin, agar, cellulose, urea, xylose and Tweens 20, 40 and 80 are not hydrolysed. Lipase (tri-n-butyrin) and β-galactosidase are produced. Acid is produced from maltose, D-mannose and trehalose, but not from L-arabinose, cellobiose, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-glucose, glycerol, myo-inositol, lactose, D-mannitol, raffinose, L-rhamnose, D-sorbitol, sucrose or xylose. Susceptible to erythromycin, vancomycin and rifampicin and resistant to ampicillin, chloramphenicol, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, penicillin, streptomycin and tetracycline. Produces pigment with maximum absorption at 451.2 nm. The major isoprenoid quinone is MK-6. The dominant cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0, iso-C15 : 1, C16 : 1, iso-C17 : 1, C13 : 0 and iso-C17 : 0 3-OH.The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 33.1 mol% (HPLC).</description></treatment>