<treatment><meta><source><author>Mitsuo Sakamoto, Maki Kitahara and Yoshimi Benno</author><date>2007</date><title>Parabacteroides johnsonii sp. nov., isolated from  human faeces</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 11:57:11 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64588-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2010), 60, 1296–1302</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Parabacteroides</genus_name><species_name>johnsonii</species_name><strain_name>M-165</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-negative rods (0.8×1.7–2.5 μm). On EG agar plates, colonies are 1–2 mm in diameter, grey to off-white in colour, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth. Indole and urease are not produced. Catalase is produced. Aesculin is hydrolysed. Gelatin is not digested. Grows on medium containing 20 % bile. Acid is produced from l-arabinose, glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, d-trehalose and d-xylose but not from d-cellobiose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-melezitose, salicin or d-sorbitol. Positive Rapid ID 32A reactions are obtained for α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, α-arabinosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase. Mannose and raffinose are fermented. All of the other tests (for urease, arginine dihydrolase, 6-phospho-β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, α-fucosidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, proline arylamidase and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase) are negative. The major end products from PYG broth cultures (1 % peptone, 1 % yeast extract, 1 % glucose) are succinic and acetic acids; small amounts of isovaleric acid and propionic acid are also produced. The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-15 : 0 and iso-17 : 0 3-OH. The predominant respiratory quinones are menaquinones MK-9 and MK-10. The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 47.6 mol%.</description></treatment>