<treatment><meta><source><author>Mitsuo Sakamoto and Yoshimi Benno</author><date>2006</date><title>Reclassiﬁcation of Bacteroides distasonis,  Bacteroides goldsteinii and Bacteroides merdae  as Parabacteroides distasonis gen. nov.,  comb. nov., Parabacteroides goldsteinii comb. nov.  and Parabacteroides merdae comb. nov.</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 11:08:23 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64192-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2006), 56, 1599–1605</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Parabacteroides</genus_name><species_name>merdae</species_name><strain_name>JCM 9497</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Urease and catalase are not produced. Gelatin is not liquefied. Acid is produced from glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, d-raffinose, sucrose, d-trehalose and d-xylose, but not from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, glycerol, d-mannitol, d-melezitose, l-rhamnose, salicin or d-sorbitol. Positive reactions are obtained using Rapid ID 32A for α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase. Variable for α-glucosidase, α-arabinosidase and serine arylamidase. Mannose and raffinose are fermented. All the other tests are negative. Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C15 : 0 and iso 3-OH-C17 : 0. A significant amount of C18 : 1ω9c is also present. The G+C content of the type strain is 44 mol%.</description></treatment>