<treatment><meta><source><author>Mitsuo Sakamoto,1 Natsuko Suzuki,1 Naohisa Matsunaga,2  Kimihito Koshihara,2 Masayasu Seki,3 Hideaki Komiya3  and Yoshimi Benno1</author><date>2009</date><title>Parabacteroides gordonii sp. nov., isolated from  human blood cultures</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 12:00:09 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.010611-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2009), 59, 2843–2847</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Parabacteroides</genus_name><species_name>gordonii</species_name><strain_name>MS-1</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-negative rods (0.8×1.7–2.5 μm). Colonies on EG agar after 48 h of incubation at 37 °C under anaerobic conditions are 1–2 mm in diameter, grey to off-white–grey, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth. Indole and urease are not produced. Catalase is variable (activity is not detected in the API 20A test but is detected on EG agar). Aesculin is not hydrolysed. Gelatin is not digested. Growth occurs on medium containing 20 % bile. Acid is produced from l-arabinose, glucose, lactose, maltose, d-mannose, raffinose, sucrose and d-xylose, but not from cellobiose, glycerol, d-mannitol, melezitose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol or trehalose. Positive reactions are obtained using Rapid ID 32A for α- and β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, α-arabinosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and alanine arylamidase. Mannose and raffinose are fermented. All of the other tests that were performed in this study (urease, arginine dihydrolase, 6-phospho-β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, α-fucosidase, nitrate reduction, indole production, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase) gave negative results. The major end product in peptone-yeast extract-glucose broth (1 %, w/v, of each) is acetic acid; a small amount of succinic acid is also produced. The major cellular fatty acid is anteiso-15 : 0. The predominant respiratory quinone is menaquinone MK-10. The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 44.6 mol%.</description></treatment>