<treatment><meta><source><author>Mitsuo Sakamoto,1 Akiko Takagaki,2 Kohei Matsumoto,3 Yuko Kato,3  Keiichi Goto3 and Yoshimi Benno1</author><date>2009</date><title>Butyricimonas synergistica gen. nov., sp. nov.  and Butyricimonas virosa sp. nov., butyric  acid-producing bacteria in the family  ‘Porphyromonadaceae’ isolated from rat faeces</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 13:40:39 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.007674-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM July 2009 vol. 59 no. 7 1748-1753</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Butyricimonas</genus_name><species_name>virosa</species_name><strain_name>MT01</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Urease is not produced. Catalase is produced. Gelatin is not digested. Acid is produced from glucose and glycerol, but not from L-arabinose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melezitose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or D-xylose. Positive reactions are obtained using Rapid ID 32A for β-galactosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, indole, alkaline phosphatase and leucyl glycine, alanine and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidases. All the other tests in Rapid ID 32A are negative. The major end products of the type strain are butyric and isobutyric acids; smaller amounts of acetic, propionic and succinic acids are produced. The major cellular fatty acid of the type strain is iso-C15 : 0 (74 %). The predominant respiratory quinone of the type strain is MK-10 (50 %); minor amounts of MK-8 (28 %), MK-9 (4 %) and MK-11 (18 %) are present. The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46.5 mol%.Cells are Gram-negative, obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile, rod-shaped and 1.0×1.5 μm. Colonies on EG agar plates after 72 h incubation at 37 °C under anaerobic conditions are 0.5–1.0 mm in diameter, opalescent to yellowish, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth. Saccharolytic. The major end products are butyric and isobutyric acids; smaller amounts of acetic, propionic and succinic acids are produced. Growth is inhibited on medium containing 20 % bile. Aesculin is not hydrolysed. Indole and hydrogen are produced. The principal respiratory quinone is MK-10. Both non-hydroxylated and 3-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are present. The non-hydroxylated acids are predominantly of the isomethyl branched type (iso-C15 : 0), with smaller amounts of straight-chain saturated acids.</description></treatment>