<treatment><meta><source><author>Mitsuo Sakamoto and Yoshimi Benno</author><date>2006</date><title>Reclassiﬁcation of Bacteroides distasonis,  Bacteroides goldsteinii and Bacteroides merdae  as Parabacteroides distasonis gen. nov.,  comb. nov., Parabacteroides goldsteinii comb. nov.  and Parabacteroides merdae comb. nov.</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 10:00:59 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64192-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2006), 56, 1599–1605</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Parabacteroides</genus_name><species_name>goldsteinii</species_name><strain_name>JCM 13446</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Urease is not produced. Nitrate is not reduced. Acid is produced from cellobiose, glucose, rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose and xylose, but not from arabinose or xylan. In peptone yeast broth and peptone yeast glucose broth, major amounts of acetic and succinic acids and minor amounts of isovaleric acid, propionic acid and formic acid are produced. Using API ZYM, Rapid ID 32A and RapID ANA II systems, strains have the same profile. Positive reactions are obtained for α-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, leucine arylamidase, p-nitrophenylphosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase, leucyl glycine aminopeptidase, glycine aminopeptidase, phenylalanine aminopeptidase, arginine aminopeptidase and serine aminopeptidase. All the other tests are negative. Mannose and raffinose are fermented (Rapid ID 32A). Using Rosco diagnostic tablets (Rosco), β-xylosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase (o-nitrophenol-β-d-galactopyranoside), N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase and α-arabinosidase are present; α-arabinosidase is tested as positive only by Rosco tablets. Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C15 : 0 and iso 3-OH-C17 : 0 (25–28 and 18–23 %, respectively). Significant amounts of C18 : 1ω9c and anteiso 3-OH-C17 : 0 (11–16 and 9–15 %, respectively) are also present. Susceptible to metronidazole (MIC⩽2 μg ml−1) and ertapenem (MIC⩽1 μg ml−1). Some resistance is seen with clindamycin (MIC⩽8 μg ml−1). Resistant to penicillin G (MIC⩾32 μg ml−1), cefotetan (MIC⩽256 μg ml−1) and vancomycin (MIC⩽32 μg ml−1). β-Lactamase-positive. The G+C content of the type strain is 43 mol%.</description></treatment>