<treatment><meta><source><author>Mitsuo Sakamoto,1 Natsuko Suzuki1 and Masaaki Okamoto2</author><date>2010</date><title>Prevotella aurantiaca sp. nov., isolated from the  human oral cavity</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 10:56:57 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.012831-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2010), 60, 500–503</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Prevotella</genus_name><species_name>aurantiaca</species_name><strain_name>OMA31</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, ovoid to short rods, 1·1–3·2 μm long and 0·3–0·6 μm wide, occasionally with elongated filament-like forms. Non-sporulating, non-flagellated and non-gliding. Colonies on trypticase soy agar are circular and convex with bright yellow colour: flexirubin pigments are not detected. Congo red is absorbed. The temperature range for growth is 0–25 °C; no growth occurs at 30 °C. The optimum temperature for growth is 15–20 °C. Sodium chloride inhibits growth: tolerates up to 1·5 % NaCl. Grows Cells are obligately anaerobic, pigmented, non-spore-forming, non-motile, Gram-stain-negative rods or coccobacilli (0.5–0.8×1.6 μm or 0.8×0.9–1.0 μm). Colonies on EG agar plates after 48 h incubation at 37 °C under anaerobic conditions are 1–2 mm in diameter, light to dark brown, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth. Colonies exhibit orange fluorescence under long-wave UV light (365 nm). Their growth is inhibited in the presence of 20 % (w/v) bile. Acid is produced from glucose, maltose, d-mannose, raffinose and sucrose, but not from l-arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, lactose, d-mannitol, melezitose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, trehalose or d-xylose. Aesculin is not hydrolysed. Indole is produced. Gelatin is digested. Catalase and urease are not produced. Positive reactions are obtained using the Rapid ID 32A system for α-glucosidase, α-fucosidase, indole production, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase. Mannose and raffinose are fermented. All other tests performed (urease, arginine dihydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, 6-phospho-β-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, α-arabinosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-N-acetylglucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, nitrate reduction, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, pyroglutamic acid arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase and serine arylamidase) are negative. Both non-hydroxylated and 3-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are present. The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C15 : 0, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH and C18 : 1ω9c.The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.7 mol%</description></treatment>