<treatment><meta><source><author>Mitsuo Sakamoto,1 Akiko Takagaki,2 Kohei Matsumoto,3 Yuko Kato,3  Keiichi Goto3 and Yoshimi Benno1</author><date>2009</date><title>Butyricimonas synergistica gen. nov., sp. nov.  and Butyricimonas virosa sp. nov., butyric  acid-producing bacteria in the family  ‘Porphyromonadaceae’ isolated from rat faeces</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 11:34:42 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.007674-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2009), 59, 1748–1753</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Butyricimonas</genus_name><species_name>synergistica</species_name><strain_name>MT01</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Urease and catalase are not produced. Gelatin is digested. Acid is produced from glucose and d-mannose, but not from l-arabinose, cellobiose, glycerol, lactose, maltose, d-mannitol, melezitose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, salicin, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose or d-xylose. Positive reactions are obtained using Rapid ID 32A for α-galactosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, α-fucosidase, indole, alkaline phosphatase and leucyl glycine, pyroglutamic acid, alanine and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidases. Mannose is fermented. All other tests in Rapid ID 32A are negative. The major end product of the type strain is butyric acid; smaller amounts of acetic, propionic, succinic and isobutyric acids are produced. The major cellular fatty acid of the type strain is iso-C15 : 0 (66 %). The predominant respiratory quinone of the type strain is MK-10 (42 %); minor amounts of MK-8 (22 %), MK-9 (9 %) and MK-11 (27 %) are present. The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 46.4 mol%.</description></treatment>