<treatment><meta><source><author>Mitsuo Sakamoto and Yoshimi Benno</author><date>2006</date><title>Reclassification of Bacteroides distasonis, Bacteroides goldsteinii and Bacteroides merdae as Parabacteroides distasonis gen. nov., comb. nov., Parabacteroides goldsteinii comb. nov. and Parabacteroides merdae comb. nov.</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 21:12:22 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64192-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM July 2006 vol. 56 no. 7 1599-1605</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Parabacteroides</genus_name><species_name>distasonis</species_name><strain_name>JCM 5825</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, obligately anaerobic, non-spore-forming, non-motile and rod-shaped, and 0.8–1.6×1.2–12 μm in size. Colonies on EG agar plates are 1–2 mm in diameter, grey to off-white–grey, circular, entire, slightly convex and smooth. Saccharolytic. Major end-products are acetic and succinic acids; lower levels of other acids may be produced. Grow on medium containing 20 % bile. Aesculin is hydrolysed. Indole is not produced. Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PDH), 6-phosphogluconate dehydrogenase (6PGDH), malate dehydrogenase and glutamate dehydrogenase are present. α-Fucosidase is negative. The principal respiratory quinones are menaquinones MK-9 and MK-10. Both non-hydroxylated and 3-hydroxylated long-chain fatty acids are present. The non-hydroxylated acids are predominantly of the saturated straight-chain and anteiso-methyl branched-chain types.Urease is not produced. Catalase is produced. Gelatin is not liquefied. Acid is produced from D-cellobiose, glucose, lactose, D-mannose, D-melezitose, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, sucrose, D-trehalose and D-xylose, but not from L-arabinose, glycerol, D-mannitol or D-sorbitol. Positive reactions are obtained using Rapid ID 32A for α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, glutamic acid decarboxylase, alkaline phosphatase, arginine arylamidase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase and glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase. Variable for α-arabinosidase and serine arylamidase. Mannose and raffinose are fermented. All the other tests are negative. Major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C15 : 0 and iso 3-OH-C17 : 0. A significant amount of C18 : 1ω9c is also present. The G+C content of the type strain is 44 mol%.</description></treatment>