<treatment><meta><source><author>Mouhamad Al Masalma, Didier Raoult and Véronique Roux</author><date>2009</date><title>Phocaeicola abscessus gen. nov., sp. nov., an anaerobic bacterium isolated from a human brain abscess sample</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 12:13:10 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.007823-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM September 2009 vol. 59 no. 9 2232-2237</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Phocaeicola</genus_name><species_name>abscessus</species_name><strain_name>7401987</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">After 7 days growth in Schaedler broth, 7 % cells are rods (1.7–0.4 μm wide and 1.2–6.5 μm long) and 93 % cells are coccoid (0.3–0.6 μm wide and 0.4–0.9 μm long). The optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C. After 7 days growth on chocolate agar, colonies are white, entire, circular, regular, smooth, shiny, convex and 1 mm in diameter. Using API ZYM, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and α-fucosidase activities are detected. Leucine arylamidase and α-glucosidase activities are weakly positive. Esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase and α-mannosidase activities are not detected. Using API Rapid ID 32A, positive reactions are obtained for α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-galactosidase 6-phosphate, α-glucosidase (weakly positive with API ZYM), N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucyl glycine arylamidase and alanine arylamidase. Weakly positive reactions are obtained for β-glucosidase, α-arabinosidase, arginine arylamidase and leucine arylamidase. Negative reactions are obtained for urease, arginine dihydrolase, β-glucuronidase, mannose and raffinose fermentation, glutamic acid decarboxylase, reduction of nitrate, indole production, proline arylamidase, phenylalanine arylamidase, pyroglutamic arylamidase, tyrosine arylamidase, glycine arylamidase, histidine arylamidase, glutamyl glutamic acid arylamidase and serine arylamidase. Using API 50CH, all reactions are negative. Using the Biolog AN system, positive for utilization of dextrin, D-glucose 6-phosphate, D-malic acid, pyruvic acid, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinamic acid, succinic acid, succinic acid monomethyl ester, L-alanyl-L-glutamine, L-glutamic acid, L-glutamine and glycyl L-glutamine, weakly positive for utilization of L-fucose, α-D-glucose 1-phosphate and trehalose and negative for utilization of N-acetyl-D-galactosamine, N-acetyl-D-glucosamine, N-acetyl-β-D-mannosamine, adonitol, amygdalin, D-arabitol, arbutin, cellobiose, α-cyclodextrin, β-cyclodextrin, dulcitol, i-erythritol, D-fructose, D-galactose, D-galacturonic acid, gentiobiose, D-gluconic acid, D-glucosaminic acid, α-D-glucose, glycerol, DL-α-glycerol phosphate, myo-inositol, α-lactose, lactulose, maltose, maltotriose, D-mannitol, D-mannose, melezitose, melibiose, 3-methyl-D-glucose, methyl α-D-galactoside, methyl β-D-galactoside, methyl α-D-glucoside, methyl β-D-glucoside, palatinose, raffinose, L-rhamnose, salicin, D-sorbitol, stachyose, sucrose, turanose, acetic acid, formic acid, fumaric acid, glyoxylic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, DL-lactic acid, L-lactic acid, D-lactic acid methyl ester, L-malic acid, propionic acid, D-saccharic acid, m-tartaric acid, urocanic acid, alaninamide, L-alanine, L-alanyl L-histidine, L-alanyl L-threonine, L-asparagine, glycyl L-aspartic acid, glycyl L-methionine, glycyl L-proline, L-methionine, L-phenylalanine, L-serine, L-threonine, L-valine, L-valine plus L-aspartic acid, 2′-deoxyadenosine, inosine, thymidine, uridine, TMP and UMP. The major cellular fatty acids are anteiso-C15 : 0, C16 : 0, iso-C15 : 0 and iso-C17 : 0 3-OH.</description></treatment>