<treatment><meta><source><author>Olga I. Nedashkovskaya,1 Seung Bum Kim,2 Anatoly M. Lysenko,3  Galina M. Frolova,1 Valery V. Mikhailov,1 Kyung Sook Bae,2  Dong Hyuck Lee4 and In Seop Kim4</author><date>2005</date><title>Gramella echinicola gen. nov., sp. nov.,  a novel halophilic bacterium of the family  Flavobacteriaceae isolated from the sea  urchin Strongylocentrotus intermedius</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 19:53:15 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.63314-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2005), 55, 391–394</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Gramella</genus_name><species_name>echinicola</species_name><strain_name>KMM 6050</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Rod-shaped cells, motile by gliding. Gram-negative. Do not form endospores. Strictly aerobic. Produce non-diffusible carotenoid pigments. Chemo-organotrophic. Cytochrome oxidase-, catalase- and alkaline phosphatase-positive. The major respiratory quinone is MK-6. The main cellular fatty acids are straight-chain unsaturated and branched-chain unsaturated fatty acids i15 : 0, a15 : 0, 15 : 0, i16 : 1, i16 : 0, i16 : 0 3-OH and i17 : 0 3-OH and summed feature 3, comprising fatty acids 15 : 0 iso 2-OH and/or 16 : 1ω7 or both.In addition, cells are 0·5–0·7 μm in width and 2·1–2·7 μm in length. On marine agar, colonies are 2–4 mm in diameter, circular, shiny with entire edges and yellow–orange in colour. Growth is observed at 4–37 °C. Optimal temperature for growth is 23–25 °C. Growth occurs in 1–15 % (w/v) NaCl. β-Galactosidase-positive. Casein, gelatin, starch, DNA, Tween 40 and Tween 80 are decomposed. Agar, urea, Tween 20, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper) and chitin are not degraded. Acid is formed from d-galactose, d-glucose, d-maltose, d-sucrose and l-raffinose, but not from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, d-lactose, d-melibiose, l-rhamnose, dl-xylose, citrate, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol or mannitol. l-Arabinose, d-glucose and d-sucrose are utilized, but d-lactose, d-mannose, mannitol, inositol, sorbitol, malonate and citrate are not utilized. Nitrate is not reduced. H2S, indole and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) are not produced. The G+C content of the DNA is 39·6 mol%.</description></treatment>