<treatment><meta><source><author>Olga I. Nedashkovskaya1, Seung Bum Kim2 and Kyung Sook Bae3</author><date>2010</date><title>Gramella marina sp. nov., isolated from the sea urchin Strongylocentrotus intermedius</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:24:50 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.013870-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM December 2010 vol. 60 no. 12 2799-2802</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Gramella</genus_name><species_name>marina</species_name><strain_name>KMM 6048</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">heterotrophic, strictly aerobic, yellow–orange-pigmented and motile by gliding. It was oxidase-, catalase- and alkaline phosphatase-positive, required NaCl or seawater for growth, hydrolysed aesculin, gelatin and starch, and utilized carbohydrates.cells are 0.4–0.6 μm in width and 1.7–2.5 μm in length. On marine agar, colonies are 2–3 mm in diameter, circular, shiny with entire edges and yellow–orange-pigmented. Growth is observed at 4–37 °C (optimum, 28–30 °C) and with 1–15 % (w/v) NaCl (optimum, 2–5 % NaCl). Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent. Acid is produced from amygdalin, but not from cellobiose. D-Mannose, adipate, gluconate, malate and phenylacetate are utilized, but caprate is not. The substrates utilized in the GN2 MicroPlate are listed in Table 1⇑. Susceptible to ampicillin, benzylpenicillin, carbenicillin, cefalexin, cefazolin, chloramphenicol, doxycycline, erythromycin, lincomycin, nalidixic acid, ofloxacin, oleandomycin, streptomycin, tetracycline, rifampicin and vancomycin, but resistant to gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin, oxacillin and polymyxin. Other biochemical and physiological properties are shown in Table 2⇑. The predominant fatty acids (i.e. &gt;5 % of the total fatty acids) are iso-C15 : 0, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH, anteiso-C15 : 0, iso-C16 : 0, iso-C17 : 1ω9c and summed feature 3 (comprising C16 : 1ω7c and/or iso-C15 : 0 2-OH and C17 : 0 2-OH).The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 40.0 mol%.</description></treatment>