<treatment><meta><source><author>Olga I. Nedashkovskaya,1 Seung Bum Kim,2  Galina M. Frolova,1 Valery V. Mikhailov,1 Kang Hyun Lee2  and Kyung Sook Bae2  3 Anatoly M. Lysenko,3</author><date>2005</date><title>Description of Aquimarina muelleri gen. nov.,  sp. nov., and proposal of the reclassiﬁcation of  [Cytophaga] latercula Lewin 1969 as Stanierella  latercula gen. nov., comb. nov.</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:47:29 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.63349-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2005), 55, 225–229</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Stanierella</genus_name><species_name>latercula</species_name><strain_name>CIP 104806</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Rod-shaped cells, non-motile. Gram-negative. Do not form endospores. Strictly aerobic. Produces non-diffusible pigments. No flexirubins are formed. Chemo-organotroph. Cytochrome oxidase- and alkaline phosphatase-positive; catalase-negative. The main lipoquinone is MK-6. β-galactosidase-positive. Degrades casein, DNA and Tweens 20, 40 and 80, but not urea or cellulose (CM-cellulose or filter paper). Does not form acid from l-arabinose, d-cellobiose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, d-maltose, d-melibiose, l-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sucrose, dl-xylose, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol or N-acetylglucosamine. Growth occurs at 4–34 °C and at 1–5 % NaCl. Susceptible to ampicillin, lincomycin, oleandomycin and streptomycin. Resistant to benzylpenicillin, carbenicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin and polymyxin B. The predominant cellular fatty acids are straight-chain saturated, branched-chain saturated and unsaturated fatty acids: i15 : 0 (18·2 %), i15 : 1w10c (6·7 %), 15 : 0 (5·4 %), i15 : 0 3-OH (7·1 %), i17 : 1ω7c (11·6 %) and i17 : 0 3-OH (34·7 %) (Bowman et al., 1998). G+C content of the DNA is 34 mol%.</description></treatment>