<treatment><meta><source><author>Olga I. Nedashkovskaya,1 Marc Vancanneyt2 and Seung Bum Kim3</author><date>2010</date><title>Bizionia echini sp. nov., isolated from a sea urchin</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 10:26:11 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.013193-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2010), 60, 928–931</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Bizionia</genus_name><species_name>echini</species_name><strain_name>KMM 6177</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">In addition, cells are 0.4–0.5 μm wide and 1.4–3.5 μm long. On marine agar, colonies are circular, mucoid, orange-pigmented, shiny, with entire edges and 2–4 mm in diameter. Growth occurs with 1–8 % NaCl and at 4–39 °C. Optimal growth is observed with 2–3 % NaCl. Oxidase, catalase and alkaline phosphatase activities are present. Arginine dihydrolase, lysine and ornithine decarboxylases and tryptophan deaminase activities are absent. Decomposes aesculin, gelatin, DNA and Tweens 20, 40 and 80. Does not hydrolyse agar, casein, starch, CM-cellulose, urea or chitin. Produces no acid from l-arabinose, cellobiose, d-fructose, l-fucose, d-galactose, d-glucose, d-lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, dl-xylose, N-acetylglucosamine, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol or mannitol. Utilizes mannose, but not lactose, sucrose, inositol or sorbitol. According to the API 20 NE gallery, glucose, arabinose, mannitol, N-acetylglucosamine, maltose, malate, gluconate, citrate and phenylacetate are also utilized. None of the API 32 GN tests indicate a positive reaction, and only two tests (citrate utilization and gelatin hydrolysis) from the API 20 E gallery are positive for the type strain. Testing by using the API ZYM gallery for the type strain indicates that esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, acid phosphatase and naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase activities are present, but lipase (C14), α-chymotrypsin, α- and β-galactosidases, α- and β-glucosidases, β-glucuronidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent. Nitrate is not reduced. H2S is produced but indole is not. Susceptible to ampicillin, benzylpenicillin, carbenicillin, cefalexin, chloramphenicol, erythromycin, doxycycline, lincomycin, ofloxacillin, oleandomycin, rifampicin, tetracycline and vancomycin; resistant to cefazolin, gentamicin, kanamycin, nalidixic acid, neomycin, oxacillin, polymixin and streptomycin. The predominant fatty acids of strain KMM 6177T are iso-C15 : 1 G, iso-C15 : 0, iso-C15 : 0 3-OH, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH and a summed feature comprising C16 : 1ω7c and/or iso-C15 : 0 2-OH. The DNA G+C content is 34.4 mol%.</description></treatment>