<treatment><meta><source><author>Olga I. Nedashkovskaya,1 Seung Bum Kim,2  Valery V. Mikhailov1 and Kyung Sook Bae2  3 Kang Hyun Lee,2</author><date>2005</date><title>Gillisia mitskevichiae sp. nov., a novel bacterium of  the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from sea  water</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 14:02:42 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.63256-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2005), 55, 321–323</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Gillisia</genus_name><species_name>mitskevichiae</species_name><strain_name>KMM 6034</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, strictly aerobic with respiratory metabolism, chemo-organotrophic, asporogenic rods, non-motile by gliding, 0·5–0·7 μm wide and 3–4 μm long. Oxidase-, catalase-, urease- and alkaline phosphatase-positive. Colonies are circular, convex, shiny with entire edges, 1–3 mm in diameter on marine agar 2216. Produces yellow non-diffusible pigments. No growth is observed without Na+; grows at 1–12 % NaCl. Flexirubin pigments are absent. Growth occurs at 4–31 °C. The pH range of growth is 5·5–10·0, with optimum growth occurring between pH 7·6 and 8·3. Casein, gelatin, DNA, urea and Tweens 40 and 80 are degraded; does not hydrolyse agar, starch, cellulose (CM-cellulose and filter paper), chitin or Tween 20. Forms acid from glucose, sucrose and N-acetylglucosamine, but not from arabinose, cellobiose, fucose, galactose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, xylose, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol or mannitol. Does not utilize arabinose, lactose, mannose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol or citrate as sole sources of carbon and energy. Nitrate reduction is negative. H2S, indole and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) are not produced. Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, oleandomycin, lincomycin, streptomycin and tetracycline; resistant to kanamycin, benzylpenicillin, neomycin, gentamicin and polymyxin B. The predominant cellular fatty acids are straight-chain unsaturated, branched-chain unsaturated and saturated, namely i-15 : 0 (7·5 %), a-15 : 0 (5·1 %), i-15 : 1 (11·8 %), i-16 : 1 (6 %), i-16 : 0 (9·3 %), i-16 : 0 3-OH (7·2 %), i-17 : 0 3-OH (6·7 %) and summed feature 3 (11·1 %), consisting of i-15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1ω7c (64·7 % of total). The G+C content of the DNA is 36·4 mol%.</description></treatment>