<treatment><meta><source><author>Olga I. Nedashkovskaya,1 Seung Bum Kim,2  Galina M. Frolova,1 Valery V. Mikhailov,1 Kang Hyun Lee2  and Kyung Sook Bae2  3 Anatoly M. Lysenko,3</author><date>2005</date><title>Description of Aquimarina muelleri gen. nov.,  sp. nov., and proposal of the reclassiﬁcation of  [Cytophaga] latercula Lewin 1969 as Stanierella  latercula gen. nov., comb. nov.</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 10:47:05 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.63349-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2005), 55, 225–229</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Aquimarina</genus_name><species_name>muelleri</species_name><strain_name>KMM 6020</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">In addition, cells are 0·3–0·5 μm in width and 5–7 μm in length. Colonies are irregularly shaped, flat, with non-entire edges and 3–5 mm in diameter on marine agar 2216. Produces dark yellow to brown non-diffusible pigments. No growth is observed without Na+. Growth occurs at 1–8 % NaCl. Flexirubin pigments are formed. Growth occurs at 4–34 °C. Casein, gelatin, starch, DNA and Tweens 20, 40, 60 and 80 are degraded. Does not hydrolyse agar, alginate, urea, chitin or cellulose (CM-cellulose or filter paper). Does not form acid from arabinose, cellobiose, fucose, galactose, glucose, lactose, maltose, melibiose, raffinose, rhamnose, sucrose, xylose, adonitol, dulcitol, glycerol, inositol, mannitol or N-acetylglucosamine. Does not utilize arabinose, glucose, lactose, mannose, sucrose, inositol, mannitol, sorbitol, citrate or malonate as sole sources of carbon and energy. Nitrate reduction is negative. H2S, indole and acetoin (Voges–Proskauer reaction) are not produced. Susceptible to ampicillin, carbenicillin, lincomycin and oleandomycin. Resistant to benzylpenicillin, gentamicin, kanamycin, neomycin and polymyxin B. The predominant cellular fatty acids are straight-chain unsaturated, branched-chain unsaturated and saturated: i15 : 0 (19·3–21·1 %), i15 : 1 (9·8–13 %), i15 : 0 3-OH (5·5–7·5 %), i17 : 1ω9c (9·3–10·6 %), i17 : 0 3-OH (21–29·5 %) and summed feature 3 (7–8·4 %; comprising i15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1ω7c fatty acids). G+C content of the DNA is 31·6–32·5 mol%.</description></treatment>