<treatment><meta><source><author>On On Lee1, Stanley C. K. Lau2, Mandy M. Y. Tsoi1, Xiancui Li1, Ioulia Plakhotnikova1, Sergey Dobretsov1, Madeline C. S. Wu1, Po-Keung Wong3 and Pei-Yuan Qian1</author><date>2006</date><title>Gillisia myxillae sp. nov., a novel member of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from the marine sponge Myxilla incrustans</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:21:00 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64345-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM August 2006 vol. 56 no. 8 1795-1799</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Gillisia</genus_name><species_name>myxillae</species_name><strain_name>UST050418-08</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, short rods (1.3–2.0 μm in length and 0.5 μm in width), strictly aerobic, devoid of gliding and flagellar motility. Upon cultivation on marine agar, colonies are yellow in colour, 2–4 mm in diameter, circular and convex with a smooth surface and an entire edge. Does not produce flexirubin-type or diffusible pigments. MK-6 is the only respiratory quinone. Growth occurs between pH 5.0 and 10.0 (pH 7.0–9.0 optimum) and between 4.0 and 28.0 °C (12.0–20.0 °C optimum), but not at 36.0 °C or higher. Requires NaCl (2.0–10.0 %; 4.0–6.0 % optimum) for growth. Predominant fatty acids are i15 : 0, a15 : 0, i15 : 1, i16 : 0, i17 : 0 3-OH, 17 : 0 2-OH and summed feature 3 (comprising i15 : 0 2-OH and/or 16 : 1ω7c), together representing 69.0 % of the total. Susceptible to benzylpenicillin (1.0 μg), chloramphenicol (1.0 μg), ampicillin (1.0 μg) and tetracycline (10.0 μg), but resistant to streptomycin and kanamycin (tested up to 100.0 μg). Acetoin, indole and H2S are not produced. Nitrate is not reduced. Citrate is not utilized. Casein, starch, and Tweens 20 and 40 are degraded, but agar, Tween 80, chitin and carboxymethylcellulose are not. Positive for oxidase, DNase, alkaline phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and tryptophan deaminase activities. Negative for gelatinase, urease, trypsin, α-chymotrypsin, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase activities. Utilization of glycerol, D-glucose, sucrose, D-mannitol, D-galactose, starch, D-sorbitol, D-arabinose and D-melibiose as sole carbon sources is observed on agar medium supplemented with 4 % (w/v) carbon source and utilization of D-galacturonic acid, L-proline and putrescine is observed in the MicroLog 3 system. However, none of the carbon sources included in the API 20NE and 50CH systems are utilized. Acid is produced from L-arabinose, D-fructose, D-mannose, D-maltose, starch and glycogen in the API 50CH system, but no acid production is observed from the carbon sources in the API 20E system.The DNA G+C content of strain UST050418-085T is 34.6 mol%.</description></treatment>