<treatment><meta><source><author>Paula H. Summanen,1 Paul A. Lawson2 and Sydney M. Finegold3,4,5</author><date>2009</date><title>Porphyromonas bennonis sp. nov., isolated from  human clinical specimens</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 12:03:21 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.001909-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2009), 59, 1727–1732</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Porphyromonas</genus_name><species_name>bennonis</species_name><strain_name>WAL 1926C</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, non-spore-forming rods, 0.7–1.0×1.0–6.0 μm in size. Obligately anaerobic. Optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C. Colonies incubated on blood agar for 2 days are small, circular, entire, convex and slightly β-haemolytic. Colonies are grey to cream; after 10 days incubation, colonies are weakly pigmented (beige to tan) and show no red fluorescence under long-wave UV light. Gelatin-positive and bile-sensitive. Indole-, nitrate- and lipase-negative. Urease- and aesculin-negative. Catalase-variable. Asaccharolytic. The major fermentation products from glucose metabolism are acetic acid and succinic acid. The major cellular fatty acids are C15 : 0 DMA and/or C14 : 0 3-OH, C12 : 0, C14 : 0 and C16 : 0. Positive for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (weakly positive), leucine arylamidase, chymotrypsin (weakly positive), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, but negative for cystine arylaminidase, trypsin, α-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase (API ZYM system). Esterase lipase, lipase and valine arylamidase activities are variable with the API ZYM system. With Rosco diagnostic tablets, the strains are positive for α-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase and ONPG, but negative for α-fucosidase, trypsin, urease and aesculin. Positive for β-galactosidase, β-galactosidase phosphate, α-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, alkaline phosphatase, leucyl glycine arylamidase and alanine arylamidase, and negative for urease, arginine dihydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-glucosidase, α-arabinosidase, β-glucuronidase, mannosidase, raffinose fermentation, α-fucosidase and pyroglutamic acid arylamidase (Rapid ID 32A). β-Lactamase is produced by 15 % of the strains. The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 58 mol%.</description></treatment>