<treatment><meta><source><author>Peter Ka¨mpfer,1 Holly Matthews,2 Stefanie P. Glaeser,3 Karin Martin,4  Nicole Lodders1 and Ingrid Faye2</author><date>2011</date><title>Elizabethkingia anophelis sp. nov., isolated from the  midgut of the mosquito Anopheles gambiae</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:52:43 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.026393-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2011), 61, 2670–2675</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Elizabethkingia</genus_name><species_name>anophelis</species_name><strain_name>R26</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are aerobic Gram-reaction-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods, approximately 1 µm in width and 2 µm in length. Oxidase- and catalase-positive. Good growth occurs after 48 h on NA, R2A agar and TSA (all Oxoid) at 11–36 °C. No growth occurs on MacConkey agar (Oxoid) at 28 °C. Unable to grow at temperatures below 10 °C or above 37 °C. Two growth optima are detected on LB medium: 30–31 °C with a doubling time of 50 min; and 37 °C with a doubling time of 42 min. Colonies on NA are smooth, yellowish, circular, translucent and shiny with entire edges. The non-diffusible and non-fluorescent yellow pigment is not of the flexirubin-type (KOH test-negative). Resistant to a number of antibiotics; MICs in LB medium are &gt;400 µg ml−1 for ampicillin, &gt;250 µg ml−1 for kanamycin, &gt;250 µg ml−1 for streptomycin, &gt;30 µg ml−1 for chloramphenicol and &gt;10 µg ml−1 for tetracycline. Tests for haemolytic activity on blood agar plates show no lytic zones around the colonies. Acid is produced from d-glucose, lactose (weak), d-mannitol, maltose, l-rhamnose, sucrose, trehalose and cellobiose (weak). No acid is produced from adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, dulcitol, erythritol, i-inositol, melibiose, methyl α-d-glucoside, raffinose, salicin, d-sorbitol or d-xylose. Aesculin hydrolysis, indole production from tryptophan and β-galactosidase activity (ONPG) are positive. Urease activity, hydrolysis of casein, gelatin, starch, DNA and tyrosine, hydrogen sulfide production, activity of arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase and ornithine decarboxylase, and utilization of malonate are negative. The following compounds are not utilized as sole sources of carbon: N-acetyl-d-galactosamine, N-acetyl-d-glucosamine, l-arabinose, l-arbutin, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-glucose, maltose, d-galactose, gluconate, glycerol, d-mannose, d-mannitol, maltitol, α-melibiose, l-rhamnose, d-ribose, sucrose, salicin, trehalose, d-xylose, adonitol, inositol, d-sorbitol, putrescine, acetate, propionate, cis-aconitate, trans-aconitate, 4-aminobutyrate, adipate, azelate, fumarate, glutarate, dl-3-hydroxybutyrate, itaconate, dl-lactate, 2-oxoglutarate, pyruvate, suberate, citrate, mesaconate, l-alanine, β-alanine, l-ornithine, l-phenylalanine, l-serine, l-aspartate, l-histidine, l-leucine, l-proline, l-tryptophan, 3-hydroxybenzoate, 4-hydroxybenzoate and phenylacetate. The chromogenic substrates p-nitrophenyl (pNP)-β-d-glucopyranoside, pNP-β-d-galactopyranoside, pNP-α-d-glucopyranoside, bis-pNP-phosphate, bis-pNP-phenyl-phosphonate, bis-pNP-phosphoryl-choline, 2-deoxythymidine-2′-pNP-phosphate, l-alanine-p-nitroanilide (pNA), γ-l-glutamate-pNA and l-proline-pNA are hydrolysed but not pNP-β-d-xylopyranoside or pNP-β-d-glucuronide. Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH and summed feature 4 (iso-C15 : 0 2-OH and/or C16 : 1ω7c/t). The only menaquinone is MK-6. The major polar lipids are diphosphatidylglycerol, phosphatidylinositol, a characteristic unknown phospholipid, and unknown polar lipids and glycolipids.</description></treatment>