<treatment><meta><source><author>Seong Chan Park,1 Keun Sik Baik,1 Mi Sun Kim,1 Seon Suk Kim,1  Seok Ryel Kim,2 Myung-Joo Oh,2 Duwoon Kim,2 Byung-Ho Bang3  and Chi Nam Seong1</author><date>2009</date><title>Aequorivita capsosiphonis sp. nov., isolated from  the green alga Capsosiphon fulvescens, and  emended description of the genus Aequorivita</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 10:13:33 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.004119-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2009), 59, 724–728</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Aequorivita</genus_name><species_name>capsosiphonis</species_name><strain_name>A71</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Gram-negative, strictly aerobic bacterium. Oxidase-negative, catalase-positive and non-motile. In MB, cells are rod-shaped and 0.3–0.4×2.0–3.0 μm in size. In MB, cells sometimes appear filamentous or helical and reach up to 15 μm in size. Produces non-diffusible yellow- to orange-coloured pigments that are not of the flexirubin type. On MA, colonies are opaque, convex, circular, smooth and approximately 2 mm in diameter after 5 days at 25 °C (pH 7). Growth occurs at pH 7–9 (optimum, pH 7) and at 4–40 °C (optimum, 25 °C). Requires sodium ions (at least 0.5 % NaCl). Tolerates 8 % NaCl and grows weakly in the presence of 10 % NaCl on R2A agar and trypticase soy agar. Does not produce indole (API 20E). A positive reaction is obtained for H2S production in the API 20E gallery, but no H2S is detected on Kligler's iron agar. Acid is not produced from d-glucose or maltose (each at 0.5 %, w/v). Nitrate is not reduced. Produces acetoin (API 20E). Gelatin is hydrolysed, but aesculin, agar, CM-cellulose, casein, dextran, DNA, egg yolk, starch, Tween 80, tyrosine, xanthine and xylan are not hydrolysed. In the API ZYM gallery, alkaline phosphatase, acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), leucine arylamidase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and valine arylamidase activities are present, weak cystine arylamidase activity is detected and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-chymotrypsin, α-fucosidase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, β-glucuronidase, lipase (C14), α-mannosidase and trypsin activities are absent. In the API 20E system, amygdalin, arabinose, glucose, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, rhamnose, sorbitol and sucrose are not assimilated. The following substrates in the GN2 MicroPlate gallery are utilized: l-aspartic acid, l-fucose, gentiobiose, d-glucosaminic acid, glycogen, inosine, α-ketoglutaric acid and l-threonine. The following substrates in the GN2 MicroPlate gallery are utilized only weakly: adonitol, l-alanine, l-asparagine, citric acid, d-galactonic acid lactone, dl-lactic acid, malonic acid, propionic acid, raffinose, turanose and uridine. The remaining substrates in the GN2 MicroPlate gallery are not utilized. Sensitive to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): ampicillin (10), chloramphenicol (30), erythromycin (15), nalidixic acid (30), penicillin (10 IU), streptomycin (10) and vancomycin (30). Resistant to the following antibiotics (μg per disc, unless otherwise indicated): amikacin (30), gentamicin (10), kanamycin (30), polymyxin B (300 IU) and tetracycline (30). The predominant fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0, iso-C17 : 1ω9c, anteiso-C15 : 0, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH and summed feature 3 (comprising iso-C15 : 0 2-OH and/or C16 : 1ω7c). The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 36.9 mol%.</description></treatment>