<treatment><meta><source><author>Seung Seob Bae, Kae Kyoung Kwon, Sung Hyun Yang, Hee-Soon Lee, Sang-Jin Kim and Jung-Hyun Lee</author><date>2007</date><title>Flagellimonas eckloniae gen. nov., sp. nov., a mesophilic marine bacterium of the family Flavobacteriaceae, isolated from the rhizosphere of Ecklonia kurome</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 14:16:58 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64565-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM May 2007 vol. 57 no. 5 1050-1054</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Flagellimonas</genus_name><species_name>eckloniae</species_name><strain_name>DOKDO 007</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are strictly aerobic, motile, Gram-negative rods. Produce non-diffusible carotenoid pigments, but flexirubin-type pigments are absent. The major respiratory quinone is MK-6. The major cellular fatty acids are iso-15 : 0, iso-15 : 1ω10c and 10-methyl-16 : 0. Oxidase activity is absent, but catalase activity is present. The DNA G+C content of the type species is 56.3 mol%.Cells are 1.1–2.3 μm in length and 0.2–0.36 μm in diameter and motile by means of a single polar flagellum (see Supplementary Fig. S1 in IJSEM Online). Gliding motility is not observed. Cells form irregular aggregates during growth in MB. After 3 days of incubation on MA at 25 °C, colonies are orange-pigmented, opaque, convex and uniformly circular. Absorption maxima of the pigments extracted with solvent solution are observed at 450 and 473 nm. Growth occurs between 17 and 36 °C, at pH 7–9 and in the presence of 2.5–7 % sea salts. Requires Na+ and Ca2+ ions for growth. Optimal growth requires the presence of 3.5–4 % (w/v) sea salts (corresponding to 2.7–3.1 % NaCl), pH 8 and 26–29 °C. Cells hydrolyse casein, but not agar, gelatin or starch. In API 20NE test strips, β-glucosidase, β-galactosidase and protease (gelatin hydrolysis) activities are positive, but reduction of nitrate to nitrogen, glucose acidification, production of H2S and arginine dihydrolase and urease activity are negative; acetoin production is weakly positive. In Biolog GN2 MicroPlates, cells utilize dextrin, cellobiose, L-fucose, D-galactose, gentiobiose, α-D-glucose, maltose, D-mannose, sucrose, D-trehalose, turanose, D-glucuronic acid, DL-lactic acid and L-aspartic acid. Weakly positive results are recorded for the utilization of glycogen, D-fructose, D-melibiose, methyl β-D-glucoside, D-raffinose, L-rhamnose, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, succinic acid, alaninamide, L-alanine, L-alanyl glycine, L-asparagine, L-glutamic acid, glycyl L-glutamic acid, hydroxyl-L-proline, L-leucine, L-proline, L-threonine, urocanic acid, phenylethylamine and glucose 1-phosphate. The dominant fatty acids are iso-15 : 0 (41.8 %), iso-15 : 1ω10c (11.4 %), 10-methyl-16 : 0 (9.2 %), 15 : 0 (7.0 %), unidentified fatty acid ECL 18.056 (6.5 %,) and 16 : 1ω7c (6.0 %).</description></treatment>