<treatment><meta><source><author>Shams Tabrez Khan, Yasuyoshi Nakagawa and Shigeaki Harayama</author><date>2007</date><title>Sediminibacter furfurosus gen. nov., sp. nov. and  Gilvibacter sediminis gen. nov., sp. nov., novel  members of the family Flavobacteriaceae</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 09:36:49 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64628-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2007), 57, 265–269</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Sediminibacter</genus_name><species_name>furfurosus</species_name><strain_name>MAOS-86</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Exhibits the following properties in addition to those described for the genus. Cells are 0.5–0.7 μm wide and 1.0–2.5 μm long. Colonies on marine agar are colourless, but confluent colonies more than 5 days old turn a brownish colour. Growth occurs at temperatures in the range 10–37 °C, with an optimum at 25–30 °C. Growth occurs at NaCl concentrations of 1–6 % (w/v), with optimal growth at 3–4 %. Growth does not occur in the absence of NaCl or at NaCl concentrations above 6 % (w/v). Starch, gelatin and DNA are degraded. Chitin, agar, carrageenan, cellulose, CM-cellulose and urea are not degraded. Casein degradation, indole production and β-glucosidase and β-galactosidase activities are weakly positive. Acid is not produced from glucose. Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced. α-Cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, N-acetyl-d-glucosamine, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, α-d-lactose, lactulose, maltose, d-mannose, melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, raffinose, d-sorbitol, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, d-galacturonic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, dl-lactic acid, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, hydroxy-l-proline, l-ornithine, l-serine, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, thymidine, glucose 1-phosphate and glucose 6-phosphate are utilized. All other substrates tested are not utilized. The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39 mol%.</description></treatment>