<treatment><meta><source><author>Shu-Juan Cao, Chun-Ping Deng, Bao-Zhen Li, Xiu-Qin Dong  and Hong-Li Yuan</author><date>2010</date><title>Cloacibacterium rupense sp. nov., isolated from  freshwater lake sediment</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 19:30:11 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.017681-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2010), 60, 2023–2026</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Cloacibacterium</genus_name><species_name>rupense</species_name><strain_name>R2A-16</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">On R2A agar, cells are 0.2–0.3×1.0–2.0 μm, Gram-negative, non-sporulating, motile, straight rods, occurring singly, in pairs or in long chains. Colonies grown on agar medium are yellow, round, convex, entire, waxy and semi-transparent. Colony diameter is 1–2 mm after incubation for 48 h at 37 °C. Strictly aerobic. The optimum pH for growth is 7 (range pH 5.5–8.5). The optimum temperature for growth is 37 °C (range 18–37 °C). Catalase- and oxidase-positive. Negative for nitrate reduction. Starch, gelatin, urea and aesculin are hydrolysed, but casein, DNA and Tween 80 are not. Negative for indole production and methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests. Pigment is not of the flexirubin type. Yellow carotenoid-type pigment is produced. Resistant to streptomycin (10 μg), kanamycin (30 μg), tetracycline (30 μg) and carbenicillin (100 μg); sensitive to chloramphenicol (30 μg) and ampicillin (10 μg). The following carbohydrates can be used as sole carbon sources: d-ribose, d-mannose, l-arabinose, d-glucose, cellobiose, lactose, maltose, sucrose, d-salicin, l-rhamnose, d-galactose, starch, d-arabinose and d-xylose. d-Fructose, raffinose, inulin, d-sorbitol, inositol, melezitose, l-rhamnose, sodium gluconate, glycerol, trehalose and d-mannitol are not used. Major cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0, anteiso-C15 : 0 and iso-C17 : 0 3-OH. Predominant respiratory quinone is MK-6.</description></treatment>