<treatment><meta><source><author>Sung-Heun Cho,1 Song-Hee Chae,1 Myoungho Cho,1 Tae-Ui Kim,1  Seri Choi,1 Ji-Hye Han,1 Young Tae Kim,1 Yochan Joung,2 Kiseong Joh,2  Olga I. Nedashkovskaya3 and Seung Bum Kim1</author><date>2011</date><title>Gramella gaetbulicola sp. nov., a member of the  family Flavobacteriaceae isolated from foreshore  soil</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 19:56:29 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.027599-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2011), 61, 2654–2658</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Gramella</genus_name><species_name>gaetbulicola</species_name><strain_name>RA5-111</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-reaction-negative, strictly aerobic, non-spore-forming, motile by gliding and rod-shaped (1.2–2.7×0.6–0.7 µm). Colonies are yellow–orange, circular and convex with entire margins on marine agar. Growth occurs at 4–42 °C (optimum 30–37 °C), at pH 4–11 (optimum pH 7) and in 3–10 % (w/v) NaCl within 7 days (optimum 3–5 %). Catalase- and oxidase-positive. Acetoin is produced (positive Voges–Proskauer test). Citrate is not utilized. Nitrate and nitrite are not reduced and indole and hydrogen sulfide are not produced. Hydrolyses DNA, starch and Tweens 20, 40, 60, and 80, but not casein or cellulose. Acid is not produced from amygdalin, arabinose, glucose, inositol, mannitol, melibiose, rhamnose, sorbitol or sucrose. As determined by API ZYM and API 20 E strips, alkaline and acid phosphatase, esterase (C4), esterase lipase (C8), α- and β-galactosidase, α- and β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, tryptophan deaminase, α-chymotrypsin, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase and gelatinase activities are present, but lipase (C14), β-glucuronidase, α-mannosidase, α-fucosidase, arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase and urease activities are absent. Using Biolog GN2 MicroPlates, the following substrates are utilized: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, cellobiose, d-fructose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-glucose, maltose, d-psicose, raffinose, sucrose, trehalose, turanose, pyruvic acid methyl ester, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, d-gluconic acid, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, succinic acid, succinamic acid, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-proline, l-threonine, inosine, uridine, thymidine, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate. The predominant menaquinone is MK-6. The major fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0, iso-C17 : 0 3-OH and a summed feature (iso-C15 : 0 2-OH and/or C16 : 1ω7c). PE, unknown aminophospholipids and other unknown polar lipids are present.The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 39.1 mol%.</description></treatment>