<treatment><meta><source><author>Yu-Hua Xin,1 Zhi-Hong Liang,2 De-Chao Zhang,1 Hong-Can Liu,1  Jian-Li Zhang,3 Yong Yu,4 Ming-Shuang Xu,2 Pei-Jin Zhou1  and Yu-Guang Zhou1</author><date>2009</date><title>Flavobacterium tiangeerense sp. nov., a cold-living  bacterium isolated from a glacier</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 13:59:41 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.007906-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2009), 59, 2773–2777</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Flavobacterium</genus_name><species_name>tiangeerense</species_name><strain_name>0563</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-stain-negative rods, non-flagellated and 0.4–0.5 μm wide and 2.5–8.5 μm long. Gliding motility is not observed. Colonies are yellow, smooth, circular and convex with entire margins. Growth occurs at 4–26 °C (optimum, 22–23 °C) and at pH 6.5–9.0 (optimum, approximately pH 7.0–8.0). Growth occurs in the presence of 0–0.5 % (w/v) NaCl. Good growth occurs under aerobic conditions. Weak growth occurs under microaerobic conditions (approximately 10 % CO2, 11 % O2). No growth occurs under anaerobic conditions (O2&lt;1 %, 9–13 % CO2). Growth occurs on nutrient agar and trypticase soy agar, but not on seawater agar. No brown pigment is produced on tyrosine agar. No precipitate is formed on egg yolk agar. Casein and aesculin are hydrolysed. Gelatin, starch, tyrosine, chitin, pectin, alginate, DNA, carboxymethylcellulose and Tweens 20 and 80 are not hydrolysed. Congo red is not absorbed by colonies and flexirubin-type pigments are not produced. Hydrogen sulfide and indole are not produced. Nitrate is not reduced. The methyl red and Voges–Proskauer tests are negative. Oxidase, catalase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, acid phosphatase, alkaline phosphatase, β-glucosidase, α-chymotrypsin, trypsin, esterase lipase (C8), esterase (C4), lipase (C14), cystine arylamidase, leucine arylamidase and valine arylamidase activities are present. Arginine dihydrolase, lysine decarboxylase, ornithine decarboxylase, urease, tryptophan deaminase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, β-glucuronidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, α-mannosidase and α-fucosidase activities are absent. Citrate is not utilized. Acid is produced from cellobiose. Acid is weakly produced from starch and mannose. Acid is not produced from l-arabinose, adonitol, sorbitol, glycerol, melibiose, sorbose, galactose, rhamnose, mannitol, melezitose, sucrose, trehalose, glucose, lactose, glycogen, raffinose, methyl α-d-glucoside, meso-erythritol, amygdalin, xylose, inositol, dulcitol, salicin, ribose, fructose, maltose and inulin. The following substrates are utilized as sole carbon sources in the GN MicroPlate: α-cyclodextrin, dextrin, glycogen, α-d-glucose, maltose, l-alaninamide, l-alanine, l-glutamic acid, l-ornithine, l-proline, uridine, α-d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate. All other substrates in the GN MicroPlate are not utilized as sole carbon sources. Menaquinone-6 (MK-6) is the major respiratory quinone. The predominant cellular fatty acids (&gt;5 % of the total fatty acids) are iso-C15 : 0, iso-C15 : 0 3-OH, summed feature 3 (comprising C16 : 1ω7c and/or C16 : 1ω6c), C15 : 1ω6c, iso-C15 : 1 G and iso-C16 : 0 3-OH. The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 34.8 mol%.</description></treatment>