<treatment><meta><source><author>Yuli Song,1 Eija Ko¨ no¨ nen,2 Merja Rautio,2  Erkki Eerola3 and Sydney M. Finegold4,5,6  3 Chengxu Liu,1 Anne Bryk,2</author><date>2006</date><title>Alistipes onderdonkii sp. nov. and Alistipes shahii  sp. nov., of human origin</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Saturday, 2014 March 29 09:13:38 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64318-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2006), 56, 1985–1990</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Alistipes</genus_name><species_name>shahii sp. nov.</species_name><strain_name>WAL 8301T</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are slender rods, 0.1–0.2 μm by 0.6–4 μm. After incubation for 48 h anaerobically at 37 °C on supplemented Brucella blood agar, colonies are circular, entire, convex, grey, opaque, weakly β-haemolytic and 0.5–1 mm in diameter. After 4 days incubation on laked rabbit blood agar, colonies appear black. Under UV light (365 nm), colonies are brown but no fluorescence is observed. Strictly anaerobic. Resistant to 20 % bile. Indole-positive and catalase-negative. Nitrate is not reduced to nitrite. Aesculin is hydrolysed. When tested with the API Rapid ID 32A system, mannose and raffinose are fermented, and positive reactions are obtained for α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase, β-glucosidase, N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase, indole, alkaline phosphatase, leucyl glycine arylamidase, alanine arylamidase, α-fucosidase and glutamyl glutamate arylamidase. All other reactions are negative. With the API ZYM system, positive enzyme reactions are obtained for alkaline phosphatase, esterase (weak), esterase lipase (weak), acid phosphatase, naphthol-AS-BI-phosphohydrolase, α-galactosidase, β-galactosidase, α-glucosidase and N-acetyl-β-glucosaminidase. Two strains have very weak reactions to α-chymotrypsin. Negative for lipase (C14), leucine arylamidase, valine arylamidase, cystine arylamidase, trypsin, β-glucuronidase and α-mannosidase. The content of the principal long-chain fatty acid (iso-C15 : 0) of six tested strains varies from 36 to 43 % (of total CFAs).</description></treatment>