<treatment><meta><source><author>Zhi-Pei Liu,1 Bao-Jun Wang,1 Xin Dai,1 Xing-Yu Liu1,2  and Shuang-Jiang Liu1</author><date>2006</date><title>Zhouia amylolytica gen. nov., sp. nov., a novel  member of the family Flavobacteriaceae isolated  from sediment of the South China Sea</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 20:14:33 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64587-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology (2006), 56, 2825–2829</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Zhouia</genus_name><species_name>amylolytica</species_name><strain_name>HN-171</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Cells are Gram-negative, non-motile, non-spore-forming rods. Strictly aerobic. NaCl is required for growth. Positive for oxidase and catalase. The menaquinone is MK-6. The major fatty acids are iso-C15 : 1, iso-C15 : 0 and summed feature 4.Cells are 0.25–0.3×1.3–3.0 μm in size; devoid of flagellar and gliding motility. Colonies on MA are circular, slightly raised, smooth, yellow to pale-yellow in colour and 2.0–3.0 mm in diameter after incubation for 2 days at 30 °C. Growth occurs at 7–42 °C, with an optimum at 30 °C; growth does not occur at 4 or 45 °C. Growth is observed at pH 6.0–8.0, with an optimum at pH 7.2–7.4; growth does not occur at pH 5.8 or 8.2. Optimal growth occurs in the presence of 4.5–5 % (w/v) NaCl; growth does not occur in the absence of NaCl or in the presence of &gt;9 % (w/v) NaCl. Nitrate is not reduced. Starch and gelatin are hydrolysed, but agar, casein and Tweens are not hydrolysed. Dextrin, α-cyclodextrin, glycogen, N-acetyl-d-galactosamine, N-acetyl-d-glucosamine, d-cellobiose, d-fructose, L-fucose, d-galactose, gentiobiose, α-d-lactose, maltose, d-melibiose, methyl β-d-glucoside, d-psicose, d-raffinose, l-rhamnose, d-sorbitol, d-trehalose, turanose, succinic acid monomethyl ester, acetic acid, d-galactonolactone, α-ketobutyric acid, α-ketoglutaric acid, α-ketovaleric acid, dl-lactic acid, propionic acid, l-alanine, l-alanyl glycine, l-asparagine, l-aspartic acid, l-glutamic acid, glycyl l-aspartic acid, glycyl l-glutamic acid, l-leucine, l-ornithine, l-proline, l-threonine, urocanic acid, inosine, uridine, d-glucose 1-phosphate and d-glucose 6-phosphate are utilized. Tweens 40 and 80, adonitol, l-arabinose, d-arabitol, i-erythritol, myo-inositol, d-mannitol, xylitol, methyl pyruvate, cis-aconitic acid, citric acid, formic acid, d-galactonic acid, d-gluconic acid, d-glucosaminic acid, d-glucuronic acid, α-hydroxybutyric acid, β-hydroxybutyric acid, γ-hydroxybutyric acid, itaconic acid, malonic acid, quinic acid, d-saccharic acid, sebacic acid, succinic acid, bromosuccinic acid, succinamic acid, glucuronamide, l-alaninamide, d-alanine, l-histidine, l-phenylalanine, l-pyroglutamic acid, d-serine, l-serine, dl-carnitine, γ-aminobutyric acid, thymidine, phenylethylamine, putrescine, 2-aminoethanol, 2,3-butanediol, glycerol and dl-α-glycerol phosphate are not utilized. The major fatty acids are iso-C15 : 1 G (24.2 %), iso-C15 : 0 (14.9 %), summed feature 4 (10.7 %) and C15 : 0 (9.4 %). The DNA G+C content of the type strain is 34.5 mol%.</description></treatment>