<treatment><meta><source><author>Zhong-Wen Wang, Ying-Hao Liu, Xin Dai, Bao-Jun Wang, Cheng-Ying Jiang and Shuang-Jiang Liu</author><date>2006</date><title>Flavobacterium saliperosum sp. nov., isolated from freshwater lake sediment</title></source><processed_by><processor><date>Sunday, 2014 March 30 21:04:25 UTC-4</date><software type="Semantic Markup Input Generator" version="1.0"/><operator>elvis</operator></processor></processed_by><other_info_on_meta>doi: 10.1099/ijs.0.64065-0</other_info_on_meta><other_info_on_meta>full citation: IJSEM February 2006 vol. 56 no. 2 439-442</other_info_on_meta></meta><taxon_identification status="ACCEPTED"><genus_name>Flavobacterium</genus_name><species_name>Flavobacterium</species_name><strain_name>S13</strain_name></taxon_identification><description type="morphology">Gram-negative, aerobic and heterotrophic, with cell size of 0·35–0·55×1·5–2·5 μm. Non-flagellated and non-gliding. Colonies are yellow, smooth and circular with entire margins. Grows at temperatures of 20–34 °C (optimum growth at 28 °C). Grows over pH range 6·5–8·5 (optimum growth at pH 7·5). A concentration of NaCl above 1 % severely inhibits growth (optimum growth is at 0·1 % NaCl in medium). Grows on nutrient agar and trypticase soy agar but not on seawater agar. Voges–Proskauer reaction and oxidase are negative but catalase and lipase are positive. Cells contain flexirubin pigments. Does not reduce nitrate or sulfate. Forms a precipitate on egg-yolk agar and produces brown pigment on tyrosine agar. Hydrolyses L-tyrosine, gelatin and casein, but not agar, alginate, aesculin, starch, CM-cellulose, chitin or pectin. Does not produce acid from the following sugars: lactose, arabinose, rhamnose, raffinose, ribose, galactose, melibiose, D-melezitose, sucrose, xylose, mannose, fucose, fructose, glucose, cellobiose, maltose, salicin, laetrile, mannitol or sorbitol. Filter-paper disc tests indicate resistance to ceftazidime, ceftriaxone, tobramycin and trimethoprim/sulfamethoxazole, but susceptibility to penicillin, erythromycin, tetracycline, gentamicin, chloramphenicol, azithromycin, kanamycin, streptomycin and rifampicin. Cells contain menaquinone-6 (MK-6). Cellular fatty acids are iso-C15 : 0 (28·2 %), iso-C17 : 1ω9c (19·0 %), iso-C17 : 0 3-OH (8·6 %), iso-C16 : 0 (6·9 %), iso-C15 : 1G (6·7 %), iso-C15 : 0 3-OH (5·0 %), C15 : 0 (4·6 %), anteiso-C15 : 0 (3·9 %), C16 : 1ω7c (2·6 %), iso-C16 : 1H (2·3 %), iso-C16 : 0 3-OH (2·0 %), iso-C14 : 0 (1·3 %), C17 : 0 2-OH (1·0 %), iso-C15 : 0 2-OH (0·9 %), iso-C13 : 0 (0·5 %), C15 : 1ω6c (0·42 %) and C17 : 1ω6c (0·3 %). DNA G+C content is 41 mol%.</description></treatment>